<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-standard-oil-monopoly</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85035524/1908-02-07/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1904&amp;index=14&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Fraud+Oil+Standard&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+fraud&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ROOSEVELT IN SCORCIII1 WORDS
ATTACKS THE LAW-DEPYING RICH
The President in a Special Message Compares Crimes
of Standard Oil to Murder, Fraud and
PUTS GAMBLERS IN STOCKS IN CLASS WITH CARO SHARKS
Asserts That Unscrupulous Men of Wealth Have Banded Together to*Attack
Ilis Administration and Bring About a Reaction.
Washington, D. C.—Never before, perhaps, in the history
of the country has a President of the United States defended his
policy in such impassioned language or made such a bitter attack
on his enemies and predatory wealth in general as President
Roosevelt does in a special message which he sent to both houses
of Congress.
His message was ostensibly for the purpose of recommend
ing legislation for the protection of the interests of the working
man, but he makes it the instrument by which he flays the
Standard Oil Corporation and the big railroad and financial in
terests of the country who are opposing him because of his poli
cies ; places the blame for the recent financial distress on a few
men of great wealth, and plainly intimates that there is a con
spiracy against him by the reactionaries of the country.
He does not recede one jot from his determination to curb
trust abuses and renews his recommendations for the enactment
of legislation that will give the Federal Government supervision
of the financial and physical operation of railroads and control
of law-defying wealth.
The President refers with very
strong feeling to the attacks that he
says are being made on him through
newspapers and public speakers con
trolled by the Standard Oil Trust and
other combinations and says the key
note of these attacks upon his efforts
to secure honesty in business and
politics is that they are unnatural
and unwarranted, and business panic
is the penalty.
Uke Plea of Gambler.
The morality of such a plea, he
says, is precisely as great as if made
on behalf of the men caught in a
gambling establishment raided by the
police and means that no effort should
be made to prevent a repetition of the
insurance, banking and railroad scan
dals in New York, the Chicago and
Alton deal, the successful effort by
the Standard Oil people to crush out
every competitor and to establish a
monopoly which treats the public
with a contempt it deserves so long
as it permits men of such principles
to avow and act on them with im
punity.
The “business” which is hurt by
the movement for honesty, the Pres
ident says, is the kind which in the
long run it pays the country to have
hurt; the kind which has tended to
make the name “high finance” a
term of scandal to which all honest
American men of business should join
in putting an end.
The opponents of the measures he
champions, Mr. Roosevelt says, single
out now one and now another for
special attack, as if the movement he
is engaged in was purely economic.
This is not so, he says, for it is funda
mentally an ethical movement and
one which must be persevered in until
the spirit which lies behind it sinks
deep into the heart and conscience of
the whole people. His purpose, he
declares, is to secure national honesty
in business and politics and equality
of opportunity for all, and he will not
hp swnvarl frnm it hv ftttank« on him.
Lairs Will Be Enforced.
The laws, the President insists,
must in future be administered as
they are at present, justice being
meted out with an even hand to great
and small, rich and poor, weak and
strong. And he adds that there
should be no delay in supplementing
the laws now on the statute books
with others he recommends.
Referring to the financial situation,
the President says there is a natural
tendency to feel gloomy and fright
ened at the outlook, but he declares
there is no justification for such a
feeling, as there is no nation so ab
solutely sure of success as ours, and
we must certainly succeed.
Not Responsible, He Says.
The President then disclaims any
responsibility for the business dis
tress, saying he does not believe for
a moment that any actions of the
Administration brought it on. It was
due, he says, to the speculative folly
and flagrant dishonesty of a few men
of great wealth, who seek to shield
themselves from the effect of then
own wrongdoing by ascribing its re
sults to the actions of those who have
tried to put a stop to the wrongdoing.
“But,” says the President, “if it
were true that to cut out rottenness
from the body politic meant a mo
mentary check to an unhealthy seem
ing prosperity, I should not for a mo
ment hesitate to put the knife to the
corruption.”
He advocates the immediate re-en
actment of the employers’ liability
law, limiting its scope to interstate
employment to conform to the ruling
of the Supreme Court; urges legisla
tion providing for compensation by
the Government and employers gen
erally to all employes for Injuries,
calls attention to the need of some
action in connection with the abuse of
injunctions in labor cases by the
courts and warns men of property
that they cannot afford to trust to
anything but the spirit of justice and
fair play.
Mr. Roosevelt assails stock gam
bling and the “cornering” of the mar
ket. He says there is no moral dif
ference between gambling at cards,
in lotteries, at the race tracks and
gambling in the stock market. It is
just as pernicious and in degree the
evil worked i3 far greater.
President’s New Platform.
Roosevelt’s platform, as he states
it in this second message, is as fol
lows: “We seek to control law-defy
ing wealth; in the first place to pre
vent its doing dire evil to the Repub
lic, and in the next place to avoid the
vindictive and dreadful radicalism
which, if left uncontrolled, it is cer
tain in the end to arouse.
“Sweeping attacks upon all prop
erty, upon all men of means, without
regard to whether they do well or ill,
would sound the death knell of the
Republic; and such attacks become
inevitable if decent citizens permit
those rich men whose lives are cor
rupt and evil to domineer in swollen
pride, unchecked and unhindered,
over the destinies of this country.
“We act in no vindictive spirit and
we are no respecter of persons. If
a labor union does wrong we oppose
it as firmly as we oppose a corpora
tion which does wrrong; and we stand
equally stoutly for the rights of the
man of wealth and for the rights of
the wage worker.
“We seek to protect the property
of every man who acts honestly, of
every corporation that represents.
wealth honestly accumulated and
honestly used. We seek to stop
wrongdoing , and we desire to punish
the wrongdoers only as far as it la
necessary to achieve this end.”
The Administration’s aim, the
President asserts, is to control law
defying wealth, and he asserts that
corporations and men of great wealth
have banded together to bring about
a reaction from this policy, hiring
writers to attempt to overthrow and
discredit all who honestly administer
the law.
Flays Standard Oil.
The Standard Oil Company and the
Santa Fe Railroad he specifically de
nounces. With regard to the former
he says:
“The methods by which the Stand
ard Oil people and those engaged in
the other combinations of which I
have spoken above have achieved
great fortunes can only be justified
by the advocacy of a system of moral
ity which would also justify every
form of criminality on the part of a
labor union, and every form of vio
lence, corruption and fraud, from
murder to bribery and ballot-box
stuffing in politics.”
In advocating laws better to secure
control over great business concerns,
especially great common carriers, Mr.
Roosevelt says the Interstate Com
merce Commission should be empow
ered to pass upon any rate or practice
on its own initiative, even to prohibit
an advance in rate pending examina
tion.
He says the Federal Government
should exercise supervision over the
financial operations of interstate rail
roads, and must also assume a cer
tain measure of control over their
physical operations. He favors traffic
associations.
After quoting from Lincoln, “with
malice toward none, with charity for
all; with firmness iu the right as God
gives us to see the right, let us strive
on to finish the work we are in,” the
President says: “In the work we of
this generation are in, there is,
thanks be to the Almighty, no danger
of bloodshed and no use for the
sword,” a3 “wo strive to bring nearer
the day when greed and trickery and
cunning shall be trampled under foot
by .those who fight for righteousness
that exalteth a nation.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90052331/1907-09-26/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1904&amp;index=7&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+Trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>When I was a boy, there used to be, in one
of the “Advanced Readers,” a story which
made an indelible impression on my youthful
memory.
Under the heading of “Alexander and the
Robber,” was given a spirited conversation
which was alleged to have taken place be
tween the Macedonian Conqueror and a rob
ber-chief, whom he had captured.
In this conversation, Alexander the Great
upbraids the robber-chief for his crimes, and
the robber-chief defends himself by comparing
his own methods to those of Alexander him
self. My recollection is that the Macedonian
King started out promisingly in the discussion,
but that he steadily lost ground. At the close
of the conversation, the robber-chief had every
thing his own way. To speak in up-to-date
phraseology, the King had got himself “balled
up.”
In brief, the argument of the robber-chief
was about this: “I do just as you do; but I
don’t do as much of it.”
It is a pity that our “Readers” no longer
carry this story of “Alexander and the Rob
ber.” It would apply mighty well to latter
day conditions.
The world acclaims Alexander the Great
because he burnt the whole city instead of one
house, murdered a thousand instead of one
man, and robbed provinces instead of individu
als.
But after all, he was a mere robber. Fan
ciful theorists may prattle about the Helleniz
ing of Asia, but that is mere academic talk.
The world gained nothing, and lost much, by
the raid which Alexander made into Asia.
Hardy, enterprising Greece did not Hellenize
Persia and Assyria; on the contrary, the
effeminacy of the East flowed back to Greece,
along the lines of Alexander’s march, and
Greece lost her hardiness and enterprise. Per
sia, in the end, conquered Greece; as effeminate
Greece, in turn, conquered her conqueror,
Rome.
“Alexander and the Robber,” —the story
in the old time Reader came back to me when
the papers announced that the Chiefs of the
Standard Oil Trust were to hold a conference
at Fairhaven, Mass. That’s where H. H. Rog
ers lives. And H. H. Rogers is the Standard
Oil Chief who is being sued for $50,000,000
by a man who alleges that Rogers cheated,
him out of that amount of pocket change, in a
transaction concerning an improved process for
refining oil. And the Plaintiff must have had
the Defendant in a tight place, for Rogers’ son,
and Doctor, and Preacher went into court and
swore loudly that Rogers was too sick to come
to court. And the Judge continued the case
indefinitely, stating that it would be “cruel and
inhuman” to force such a sick man as Rogers
was to come to court. And immediately after
the case had “gone over,” I saw, in the Wash
ington Post, that Rogers, the sick man, had
taken Mark Twain out for an automobile ride,
and that Rogers, the sick man, had acted as
chauffeur.
Whether the Judge who continued the lit
tle fifty million dollar case has gone out and
hung himself, I do not know; but I guess that
Young Rogers, and Old Rogers, and Rogers’
Doctor and Rogers’ Preacher, laugh a good
deal among themselves at the neat manner in
which they tricked the Judge.
What I meant to say was this: When those
chiefs of the Standard Oil Trust meet at Fair
haverf, there will be, bunched together, the
most ravenous and remorseless band of robbers
this world has ever seen.
Long before Ida Tarbell had published her
magazine articles, Henry Demorest Lloyd had
given, in his “Wealth and Commonwealth,” a
complete history of the criminal methods of
this robber band. From Courthouse records
and other official documents, Mr. Lloyd proved
that the Standard Oil Company, with John D.
Rockefeller in active control, had violated al
most every penal statute of the Code.
These banded criminals had made use of the
vilest men and the vilest methods to stifle
competition and to kill off rivalry. The com
mon thief, the brazen perjurer, the house
wrecker, the murderer were useful instru
ments, used by this gigantic‘monopoly. Above
and beyond this lower level of criminal meth
od, came the corrupt influencing of elections,
the bribery of men in office, the subsidizing of
the Press, the corrupt control of the State
Legislatures and of Congress. In municipal
politics, in state politics, in national politics,
these rascals, who were gaining $125,000,000
every year, from one Trust alone, have exerted
their baleful influence—corruptly and crimi
nally.
Touch dozens of the Pet National Banks,
in whose behalf nearly $200,000,000 of the
nation’s wealth is annually laid aside—to be
used by them, free of interest, and you touch
the Standard Oil band.
Touch the monster railroad corporations,
which are taxing commerce to compel divi
dends on about seven billion dollars of fraud
ulent stocks and bonds —and you again touch
the Standard Oil band.
Touch the Cotton Seed Oil Trust, the Lum
ber Trust, the Copper Trust, the Steel Trust,
the Harvester Trust—and again you touch the
Standard Oil band.
For, these Alexanders of modern commer
cialism have not yet had to weep for more
worlds to conquer; their tired troops have not
mutinied at the Hyphasis, refusing to march
farther! No; these omniverous, insatiable,
irresistible men of the Oil Trust have continu
ed to add province to province, until in scope
of territory and richness of loot, their empire
is greater than that which fell before the
onset of the Macedonian King.
Not only the New World, but the Old bows
to the Rockefeller band. Not only the general
Government of the United States, but every
state in the Union, and every city in every
state, knuckles to the Standard Oil band.
The direct revenues of the Oil Trust is theirs
—5490,000,000 net profits in seven years. Then,
the profits of their banks, their railroads, their
copper mines; their holdings in the Steel Trust,
Lumber Trust, Harvester Trust, and many oth
er commercial enterprises, are theirs.
Think of what the Grand Total must be!
Compared to it, the National Treasury
shrinks into comparative insignificance.
The average increase of wealth in this coun
try is not more than five per cent.
When Express Companies pocket net earn
ings of 200 per cent; and the Standard Oil
Trust 1,000 per cent; and we have a dozen
other Trusts increasing their wealth in the
same proportion, there is bound to be some
class, or some classes, which are increasing
their wealth at a smaller rate than the average
five per cent, OR NOT INCREASING AT
ALL. Where some exceed the average, some
must fall below it. When the Steel Trust
gets so much more than the average; when
Express Companies, Railroads, Banks, Oil
Trusts, Whiskey Trusts and Sugar Trusts
get so much more than the average—there
must be many a million of men in America at
whose expense these Trusts get more than
their share.
When a band of robbers meets in their cave,
and gloats over the loot which fills it, one nat
urally thinks of the folks who were robbed.
Somebody had to lose what these robbers
stored away in the cave.
When the Standard Oil band meets at Fair
haven, the robbers will gloat over the vastest
accumulation of loot disclosed in the records
of the human race.
They have had a free rein for a full genera
tion. They debauched Public Opinion by
gifts to churches and schools; by the purchase
of public men, and by the employment of
Press Agents. They have enjoyed immunity
from punishment by hiring the best lawyers,
intimidating the witnesses who could not be
bought, and bribing the Judge where they
could not hire the Judge’s son or son-in-law,
or nephew to act as their “Attorney.”
From whom did the robbers take the loot—
THE ONE THOUSAND PER CENT NET,
PROFIT?
And how did they ever manage to steal so
much? /
The American people are the victims; and
the two old political parties supplied the ma
chinery by means of which the robbers filled
the cave.
The Standard Oil band have been enabled
to steal $490,000,000 from the American people
in seven years because the American voter
is so fond of the Democratic and Republican
parties that he would rather be robbed by
those Twins than to be protected by any new
political organization.
In other words, the fools are Wedded to the
Knaves AND NEITHER WILL SUE FOR
A DIVORCE.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1905-03-03/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1904&amp;index=17&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+trust+Trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE FIGHT against the Standard Oil Trust by
the people of Kansas is attracting world-wide
attention and people in all sections of the country
are showing their sympathy for Kansas. On Feb'
ruary 21, tho Illinois legislature adopted a reso
lution offering to lend tho state of Kansas tho sum
of $100,000 without interest, for a period of six
years to aid in establishing a stato oil refinery.
This resolution refered to the Standard Oil trust
as "that merciless octopu3 whoso tentacles now en
circle every state in tho union." Another resolu
tion provided for tho appointment of a joint com
mission to confer with the stato officials of Kansas
and to agree on steps to bo taken for pipe lines to
aid common carriers. Indiana oil producers havo
organized to fight the oil trust and they will urge
the erection of a stato refinery. Tho bill ha3 been
introduced in tho Texas legislature, making tho
pipe lines of that stato available to independent
producers and it is proposed by somo that tho
state erect a refinery. Oklahoma Is likowiso con
sidering tho erection of a stato refinery, together
with the proposition to make oil producers preserve
a uniform price throughout the stato.
AN INTERESTING DESCRIPTION of the trou
bles between Kansas and the oil trust is
given by Frank P. Gallagher, the staff correspon
dent for the Omaha World-Herald, in a dispatch to
that newspaper, under date of Topeka, Feb. 21. Mr.
Gallagher says: "It was a bitter experience with
the sinister influences of Standard Oil that led the
people of Kansas, but as late a3 two years ago tho
oil industry amounted to little. Twelve years ago
Standard Oil wriggled into Kansas under the de
ceptive title of the Forest Oil company. Depart
ing from its historic policy, the Standard Oil man
agement determined to develop the fields without
waiting for the people to catch the oil fever. Near
Neodesha, in Wilson county, many wells were
sunk, but the oil refused to gush-and the borings
were abandoned. Standard Oil relinquished its
leases to hundreds of acres and surrendered the
task of development to the prospectors and pro-
moters."
THE FIRST IMPORTANT STRIKE was made
by Charles Knapp, six years ago, at Chanute,
near one of the abandoned properties of tho For
est Oil company. A little later it was found that
Peru, Kan., was located on a vast oil deposit. Soon
nearly every town lot had its oil well, and the For
est Oil company returned to the field with renewed
vigor. As the business developed the Forest Oil
company underwent several changes. Its small
capitalization disappeared, and on January 7, 1901,
it took the name of the Prairie OH and Gas com
pany and increased it3 capital stock to $2,500,000.
Tho company then built pipe lines to Neodesha
from Chanute and at the latter point a refinery
was established. In 1902 the supply of oil was
still unsatisfactory to the Standard Oil folk, and
in order to create a boom it suddenly raised the
price of crude oil from 90 cents to $1.10 a barel.
The effect" was magical. In twelve months the out
put grew from 322,000 barels with a value of $289,
000 to 1,018,000 with a value of $1,120,018. A
greater part of the output was taken by the
S'tandard Oil company, but each day E. J. Web3ter,
who has built an independent refinery at Humboldt,
Kan., took 200 barrels.
IN THE MEANTIME, Standard Oil, according to
Mr. Gallagher, had been whetting its cimitar
with the intention of striking down tho entire Inde
pendent oil industry of Kansas. The capacity of
its plant at Neodesha was added to until it had
reached 300,000 barels of crude oil a day. The
pipe lines wore extended until tho main conduit
ran from Tulsa in the Osage nation south of the
Kansas 3tato line through Kansas to Kansas City,
Mo. At Caney, Neodesha, Altoona and Humboldt,
the Prairie Oil and Gas company built giant tanks,
and began to store oil. By January 1, 1905, it had
a total stock on hand of 5,448,034 barrels. Until
last August, when the Standard finished its sys
tem of pipe lines through the 3tate, oil had been
bringing prices ranging from $1.20 to $1.40 a bar
rel, according to its specific gravity. It was at
this juncture that Standard Oil sprung its trap,
in which the oil producers and consumers of Kan
sas and tho single independent oil refiner, E. J.
Webster, are still squirming, but with a show of
life that astonishes the captor. The price of crude
oil began to fall. In four reductions tho prices
wore cut to 72 cents for a barrol of tho best oil.
Another smash of 2 cents was mado on January
31, 1904. To what a low lovol prices for cnido oil
had sunk is illustrated In tho following compara
tive table: Wcstorn crude oil prlqes -32 dogroo
and above, 70c; 31 to 32, C5c; 31 to 31, GOc;
30 to 31, 55c; 30 to 30, 50c; 29 1-2 to 30, 45c;
29 to 291-2, 40c; 281-2 to 29, 35c; 28 to 281-2,
30c; 22 to 28 heavy, 29c per barrel. Bartlesvillo,
I. T., 82c per barrol. Eastern crude oil prices:
Pennsylvania, $1.40; Tlona, $1.55; Corning, $1.07;
Now Castle, $1.32; North Lima, 93c; South Ioina,
88c por barrel. Indiana, 88c; Somerset, 81c; Rag
land, 53c; Petrolla, Ont., $1.33 per barrol.
THE PRAIRIE OIL AND GAS COMPANY then
mado such rules relative to teats that tho
owner of a high quality of oil received no more
than one whoso output was of an inferior quality;
moreover, tho Standard Oil's inspectors did all
tho grading. In somo Instances they graded tho
oil high and when tho time camo to buy thoy re
graded the same oil in a lower classification. There
wore other injustices that aroused intense Indigna
tion among tho producers, but tho worst blow
was yet to fall. As soon as the Standard had com
pleted Its conduits it could transport Its oil with
out shipping by rail. This the Independent dealer
could not do. It was then that tho railways ad
vanced tho rates from 10 cents to 17 cents por
100 pounds. In addition to this, tho railways arbi
trarily ruled that a gallon jshould be hold to 7
instead of 4 pounds. Tho effect was to raise the
cost of shipping a car of oil to Kansas City and
other river markets from $$45 to $98. The further
effect was to prevent tho producers from shipping
their oil and thoy were compelled to accept Stand
ard Oil price3 at tho wells. Tho most remarkable
fact in this connection is that tho four railways
Involved, tho Santa Fo, the Missouri Pacific, tho
'Frisco and tho Missouri, Kansas and Texas, abso
lutely went out of the lucrative business of trans
porting oil and they did this simply because the
Standard had so commanded.
SPEAKING to this correspondent, J. M. Parker,
secretary of the State Oil Producers' asso
ciation, said: "If tho railways would give us tho
original rate of 10 cents per 100 pounds, or $45 a
car, we could ship all of our oil to Kansas City and
other points and it would give U3 $1 per barrel at
tho well. It would give the railways 100 carloads
of freight every day. But the Standard Oil com
pany tells the railroads to desist from hauling
any oil whatever, and by an exorbitant rate forc
ing us to sell to the Standard, the only market
in the fields, at a price of 47 cents a barrel, which,
under the compulsory rates demanded from tho
railways by the trust, nets the producer 7 cents
more than if he had used tho railways."
MR. GALLAGHER adds: "While the men who
are attacking Standard Oil realize the great
power of this corporation they express confidence
that Kansas will yet be able to gain the mastery.
I regretted that I could not bring to them better
cheer from Nebraska, the sister state. When I told
them that Nebraska, far from trying to cast off
the yoke of the octopus, was about to put it on by
erecting a Rockefeller memorial, I saw in their
eyes not a little consternation and a steely glint of
scorn and resentment. They have a habit of being
in deadly earnest down here. The people are a
unit against Standard Oil. Consequently it is dif
ficult for them to realize that any stato in the
union, least of all Nebraska, should regard Rocke
feller bondage with anything but aversion and hor
ror. Secretary Parker of tho Kansas Oil Pro
ducers' association gave expression to this idea
when he said: "The legislature of Nebraska is in
session. It has a duty to perform. It should take
such action as will render the acceptance of a de
grading gift front Rockefeller Impossible. Natur
ally it is inconceivable to us hero in Kansas that
such a plan 3hould ever have been entertained.
It would be dreadful if Nebraska should bo content
to wear such a badge of senility."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1909-03-19/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1904&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Three Important Judicial Decisions
-' The decision of the Missouri state supremo
court barring the Standard Oil trust from Mis
souri, the decision of Federal Judge McPherson
rdeclaring the Missouri two-cent passenger fare
rand maximum freight rate laws to be confisca
tory and, therefore, non-enforceable, and the
decision of Federal Judge Anderson at Chicago
'acquitting the Standard Oil trust, occurred,
f practically, during the same week.
It will not be surprising, therefore, if the
American people are inclined to view these three
: judicial results together.
Is it significant that the only relief from cor
porate imposition, so far as concerns legislative
action, has been given through the legislative
machinery ' of the states?
Is it significant that the one judicial opinion
seeking to apply the law to a powerful corpora
tion that has seemed so inclusive, so complete
as to bring the powerful lawbreaker to a posi
tion where it is actually willing to beg for terms
was rendered by the supreme court of a state?
Is it significant that on this occasion, as on
other occasions, the decisions upon which those
great corporations depend for escape from pun
ishment are rendered by federal courts?
No more important decisions have been ren
dered than the three herein referred to.
To be sure the decision barring the Standard
Oil trust from doing business in Missouri will
be appealed to the United States supreme court;
but it will not go to that high tribunal in any
deceptive .form. T.he highest court in the land
will be required to bluntly meet the issue -whether
the people of a' great state the very power
that creates corporations have the right to
specify the terms upon which these creatures
of law shall do business within the borders of
the commonwealth.
While Federal Judge McPherson's decision re-
lated directly to Missouri', two-cent passenger
rate law it will, if sustained, affect all other
two-cent rate laws; for if confiscation may be
shown in the great state of ivfissouri certainly
it may be shown in other and perhaps smaller
states. Indeed there are already signs that rail
road officials are laying plans for an organized
effort looking to a restoration of the three-cent
rate .wherever the two-cent rate has been put in
force.
From a fine of $29,240,000 by Judge Landis to
a verdict of acquittal by .Judge Anderson is a
long leap even for the Standard Oil trust that
is quite accustomed to rapid passage above
yawning chasms.
Judge Anderson based his verdict of not
guilty upon reasoning as follows:
That the law in the case as announced by
the circuit court of appeals governs and con
trols in the trial of the case and is binding upon
both court and jury and that this decision indi
cated that the government lad practically failed
to prove its charge.
That the government failed to establish the
very foundation of the charge against the oil
company in failing to prove that there was any
established or fixed rate of 18 cents between
Whiting, Ind., and St. Louis, and Chapoll, Ind.,
and St. Louis, a deviation from which was neces
sary to a violation of the Elkins act.
That the government In relying to prove the
eightcon-cent rate upon an unfixed, shifting and
changeable classification, In which only maxi
mum rates were named, and which classification
was prepared and fixed by the state railroad
and warehouse commission, which is a body en
tirely Independent of the federal authorities
regulating Interstate commerce, was relying up
on incompetent evidence.
That aside from the law and the insufficiency
of the evidence, there was a variation between
the counts in the indictment and the proof, and
that while the government charged one thing in
the Indictment It offered proof about an entirely
different thing.
That the fixed rates, assuming that even the
unproved elghteen-cent rate was an established
rate, had not been properly posted and pub
lished in accordance with the Elklns law pro
visions. The . Associated Press quotes "an Important
law officer of the government" as saying; "A
four-horse rebate team can be driven through
the Elklns law n,s It now stands after the de
cision of the United States court of appeals and
that of Judge Anderson in the Standard Oil case
at .Chicago. An attorney who could not protect
a' client from a charge of rebating, If those de
cisions are sustained, would not be worthy of
his hire."
This law officer pointed out that Judge Landis,
who Imposed the $29,000,000 fine upon the
Standard Oil company, held that it was the duty
of the shipper to make reasonable inquiry as
to whether the rate he was using was lawful or
not. Judges Grosscup, Seman and Baker of the"
United States circuit court of appeals, reversed
that statement of the law and held, substan
tially, that the government had to prove that
the shipper knew he was getting an illegal rate.
In the opinion of government officers that rarely,
if ever, could be done.
In this view Judge Anderson has not only
released the Standard Oil trust from all punish-
TI1E CONGRESSIONAL RECORD
The New York Evening Sun makes a timely
protest In behalf of the most Important govern
ment publication when it says:
"Mr. Taft's suggestion at the Carnegie hall
meeting for negro uplift, that perhaps his hear
ers read the Congressional Record provoked the
risibles of the audience. Nevertheless, the com
pendium of legislative proceedings to which he
referred could be read with profit by many
men who rarely or never see it, but profess to
take an intelligent interest In public affairs.
The inveracities of the Record, such as the post
delivery embellishment of speeches and the
publication of undelivered speeches under the
leave to print, are negligible in comparison with
Its veracities. Taken as a' whole, it furnishes a
quantity of useful information Indispensable to
an adequate knowledge of the workings of our
government."
A Commoner reader recently suggested that
the Congressional Record be made available
to every citizen at a stated price per year. This
' Is certainly a good suggestion. Instead of pok
ing fun at the publication wherein is recorded
the doings of the world's greatest legislative
'assembly, men who hope to participate in the
ment In this particular case but his decision,
followed by other federal judges, will mako it
Impossible to convict any one on the charge of
rebating.
When Judge Landis assessed the fine of $29,
240,000 against the Standard Oil trust there
were many who questioned tho policy of such a
large fine. There woro some who intimated that
it was a bit of demagogy on tho part of tho
federal judge who was brave enough to call to
account tho most powerful trust in tho world.
But nowhere, outside of tho pleadings filed by
tho attorneys for the trust, has any one ever
seriously contendod that tho Standard Oil trust
was not guilty of tho offense chargod against it.
The proof scorned so complete that a judge
whose ability aa a lawyer and whose character
as a man Js unquestioned assessed tho enormous
fine of $29,24 0,000. It was so complete that
public opinion which was somewhat divided as
to tho policy of assessing such an enormous fine
was practically unanimous in believing that tho
trust was guilty as charged. Yet In the light of
the opinion rendered by the court of appeals,
speaking through Judge Grosscup, Judge Ander
son is not only ablo to wipe out tho fine of
$29,240,000 but he is ablo to give a verdict of
acquittal a verdict that washes tho Standard
Oil trust "pure as tho driven snow."
Does any Intelligent man or women bpUovp
that tho republican managers would have, per
mitted, prior to election day, decisions which
destroys tho two-cent fare rate law and dis
charges the Standard Oil trust from accounta
bility for its lawlessness?
Does any ono believe that in the light of tho
tendency, of this day clearly showing tho utlor
indlfforonco to public opinion on tho part of
representatives of special interests tho work of
reformers is at an end?
Does any one imagine that popular govern
ment can be preserved for a long period of time
If this disposition to give license to corporate
lawlessness Is to continue unchecked?
Should not the very audacity of the champions
of tho trust system, the very contempt they
show for the public rights, encourage democrats
everywhere to renew their devotion to the cause
of the people? It is truo the people are generally
patient in enduring great wrongs; they are often
thoughtless In the presence of opportunity to
cure those wrongs; but always they are powerful
enough to crush the system that oppresses them
and, in all reason, they are human enough to
retaliate when their eyes have been opened to
tho solemn truth.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1904-05-22/ed-1/seq-31/#date1=1904&amp;index=6&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ANEW force in the
trust conflict is afield.
Spurred into action
by repeated attacks in the public prints, the
Standard Oil Trust -at last has come out of
the shadows and invaded the field of litera
ture, evidently proposing to try the effect of a
little publicity all its own.
This, at least, is the conclusion which
must be drawn from the study of a new phe
nomenon in the publishing#world. About a
year ago a book by Gilbert Holland Mon
tague, bearing the title "The Rise and Pro
gress of the Standard Oil Company," made
an appearance. It was published by Harper
&amp; Brothers, and that house, with unique gene
rosity, has undertaken to give the little vol
ume a wide circulation.
LAST fall the libraries of the country—North,
South, East and West—began to receive free
copies. A slip Inserted in each volume an
nounced that it came "With the compliments of
Harper &amp; Brothers." Free distribution of the book
has recently taken a fresh spurt.
College professors and clergymen all over the
country are now receiving copies, also with the com
pliments of Harper &amp;%rothers. Why Messrs. Harper
&amp; Brothers have suddenly become so liberal is the
question no one seems able to give adequate answer.
AFTER reading the volume little doubt remains in the
mind of the gentlemen favored, however, that Har
per &amp; Brothers represent, ana, indeed, are acting
for, the Standard Oil Company in this literary propaganda.
The book, as one critic of note has aptly said, is simply a
brief for the Standard Oil Company. It might, indeed,
very well have been written by their eminent attorney, S.
C. T. Dodd. In fact, the information comes directly from
no less authority than John D. Rockefeller himself that
Dodd did have something to do with the book.
A few months ago Mr. Rockefeller was talking with
an old friend about-the articles on the Standard Oil Com
pany now appearing In one of the popular magazines.
"They are not true," Mr. Rockefeller said pathetically.
"If you want a true history of the Standard Oil Company
you should read Montague's. Dodd helped Montague."
Anybody who has read the many defenses of the
Standard Oil Company written by Mr. Dodd, and com
pared them with the little volume now being so com
pletely circulated, can easily believe that Dodd did help
Montague.
"DOOK THAT WENT BEFORE
° TOLD THE OTHER SIDE
The situation is rather amusing when the fact la
recalled that some fifteen years ago the Harpers brought
out that vivid and violent attack upon the Standard Oil
Company by Henry D. Lloyd, entitled "Wealth vs. Com
monwealth."
This book made a tremendous sensation In its time.
Intemperate and one-sided though it might be considered,
It was documented so thoroughly that the Standard Oil
Company was never able to refute or even to answer it
The magnates of the Standard Oil are said to have been
very indignant at the Harpers for publishing such a
book, and when four or five years ago the publishing
company failed, they were not a little rejoiced.
It will be remembered that after their failure the
Harpers fell into the hands of Colonel George Harvey
Now Colonel Harvey has always been, more or less asso
ciated with corporate interests. It could not be expected
that with his associations he would look with any sym
pathy on such work as that by Mr. Lloyd.
No doubt he was glad to make peace with Mr Rocke
feller by publishing Mr. Montagues "Brief for the Stand
ard Oil Company." It is reported that the book was
THE GREAT OIL TRUST MASTER IN THE ACT OF.
TELLING MINISTERS THE VIRTUES OF
\ HIS METHODS, WHILE THE *
\ OCTOPUS LISTENS
Bl in glee
THE St. PAUL GLOBE SLlNiiA\, MAY 2C 1901
Great Trust Master's Story Trips Its
~ Readers Into Mistaken Beliefs by the Great
Truths It Does Not Tell, Declares This Critic
[the nvriter, from years of intimate acquaintanceship ivith
the secret history of the Standard Oil and its business methods,
says he is able to substantiate e-very statement made beloav.
For personal reasons, hoiicvet, he requested the editor to
withhold his name.]
bought outright by Mr. Harvey. Then the free distribution
began.
It seems hardly likely that Mr. Harvey -would be
bo generous as to give all the libraries, clergymen and
college professors in the United States, 150,000 of them,
free copies of a dollar booK. All things considered, it
seems very fair to conclude that the real distributer of
the book is Mi-. Rockefeller, or the Standard Oil Com
pany, in whose interests it is so apparently written and
published
To any one at all familiar with the history of the
Standard Oil Company and the methods it pursues, the
book written by Mr. Montague offers interesting, though
perhaps somewhat irritating, reading. The argument of
the book is based upon the assumption that when Mr.
Rockefeller began to wipe up early refiners he was by far
the strongest refiner in the United States. This is an
inexcusable mistake.
HOW MR. ROCKEFELLER BECAME
THE BIGGEST AMERICAN REFINER
At least ten other operators in the United States pos
sessed refineries as large and as economical of operation
as Mr. Rockefeller when he started out. Mr. Rockefeller
obtained his whip hand in the oil business through a
scheme known as the South Improvement Company.
Mr. Montague slides over this scheme in a beautifully
general way, representing it as very similar to the rail
road pools then in progress. He says that when the South
Improvement Company attempted to gather control of
the oil business, it included among its members the
strongest group of refiners in the country, the combined
capacity of whose plants exceeded by far that of the un
organized refiners.
This is a fundamental mistake. The South Improve
ment Company, when its great scheme was sprung, con
trolled, according to the best statistics of trade at that
time, just 4500 barrels a day. At that time 45,000 barrels
were produced in the United States every day.
RAILROADS HAD TO BEAR
ALL THE HARSH CRITICISMS
Mt. Montague overlooks the fact entirely that Mr.
Rockefeller obtained his extraordinary lead in the oil
business by using the contracts of this secret company
to scare the early independent trade out of Cleveland.
Within three months Mr. Rockefeller literally bluffed
twenty refiners in that city to sell to him. Where before
the daily capacity of his refineries was 1500 barrels, he
raised it to 10,000. It was in this way that Mr. Rocke
feller became the biggest refiner in the country, not, as
Mr. Montague says, through the_ superior efficiency of
his methods.
According to Mr. Montague the rebates which Mr.
Rockefeller secured were the regular thing in the busi
ness. They were always, he asserts, awarded to the big
gest shippers. He overlooks the fact that from the be
ginning of Mr. Rockefeller's career the entire outside oil
industry was united against the rebate system. The
operators almost unanimously fought in Congress, in the
Legislatures, in the courts and in the press against it.
Never at any time after Mr. Rockefeller began the use of
the rebate system to unjustly gain power did the oil in
dustry consent to it. Not only did the individual operators
combine against the system, but the courts declared it
to be contrary to public policy. Nevertheless it was con-
One of the most outrageous features of the rebate
system as practiced by the Standard Oil Company was
obtaining drawbacks on other people's shipments. The
fact that the Standard Oil Company did such a thing is
established by documentary proof. And yet Mr. Montague,
from start to finish of his book, scarcely alludes to this
practice!
One would suppose from the book written by Mr.
Montague that everything the Standard Oil Company
has done was in accordance with accepted busi
ness practices, and that everybody else in the
oil trade did the same. As a matter of fact,
there was always an organized opposi
tion, supported by both press and
courts, against most of the things
*By an Expert
Mr. Rockefeller was doing.
All the way through the book, wherever allusion is
made to an unjust practice by the Standard, It is charged
to the railroads. This is an old dodge of the Standard.
Somebody else is always forcing it to do wicked things.
As an illustration of the way the terrible raids upon
other people's business by the Standard are treated, it is
interesting to note Mr. Montague's allusion to the union
of the Tidewater Pipe Line and the Standard Oil Com
pany in 1883. The decrease of rates in freight to the
Standard which followed the success of the first seaboard
pipe line is charged to the railroads. As a matter of
fact, the Standard Oil, in order to block competition,
forced the railroads into making contracts with it. When
the Tidewater by a series of business moves, only fair to
call piratical, was pressed into an alliance, Mr. Montague
mentions it in one line.
SECRET BESIEGING, DIRECT
ATTACKS AND UNDERSELLING
"Finally," he writes, "the Tidewater was forced to
cease its opposition"!
Many curious errors are" to be found In this book.
They are of such a nature as to gloss over the specific
criticisms generally filed against the Standard Oil Com
pany. Nobody denies that the company has conducted its
business with remarxable ability. Nobody denies, either,
that Mr. Rockefeller and many of the gentlemen com
bined with him were leaders in the oil business from the
start. But that they could have built up their present
great monopoly without the use of special privileges, or
without persistent attacks on everybody who has at
tempted to enter the oil business during the past thirty
years, nobody can believe.
It is clearly established that, by besieging the rail
roads secretly and insistently, they obtained special rates.
By direct attacks they forced the various pipe line sys
tems to sell out to them. By a system of criminal under
selling, practiced persistently all over the country, they
have driven refiners out of business, and maintained the
price of refined oil.
These are actual facts, which can be proved by docu
ments. But Mr. Montague glides over them without as
much as a glance, and represents the great combination
as the inevitable result of superior methods and the oper
ation of natural law.
Especially ingenious is Mr. Montague's closing para
graph. .
"The power of the Standard Oil Company," he writes,
"is tremendous, but it is only such power as naturally
accrues to so large an aggregation of capital. In the per
sistence with which competition against it has continued,
in the quickness with which that competition
increases when opportunity for profit under
existing prices appears, and in the ever-pres
ent possibility of competition lie the safe
guards against the abuse of this great
power."
A most casual investigation would con
vince any unprejudiced mind that the oppor
tunities for profits have, indeed, not been re
stricted for the Standard Oil Company.
Hundreds of millions of dollars realized by
their methods prove the fact to be a fact.
But that the safeguards against the great
power, mentioned by Mt. Montague, are not
operative is also proved by the long record
for lawlessness and destruction made by the
Standard Oil.
It seems a very clever trick upon the part
of Mr. Rockefeller to circulate such a con-
Eoling book. It serves a double purpose. It
is at once a balm to his injured feelings and
dust in the public eye.
It appears, however, still up to Mr.
Rockefeller to prove that a great variety
of untoward acts described in the public
prints are not true before he can
expect the public to
accept Mr. Mon
tague's book
eve</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88086023/1904-10-18/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Octopus+Standard+Oil+Control+Railroads+Rockefellers&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.042,0.804,0.443,0.48,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Standard Oil Company ii'lw Control
of Many ltallroails.
New York. Oct. 17. Wall street Is
watching while Standard Oil gradual
ly but suvely dominates the railroad
?vstems of the country. Changes in
directorates of various trunk lines
foreshadow complete ascendancy of
Standard Oil Interests in the most Im
portant railroad systems of the coun
try and the elimination of the tradi
tional power of the Vanderbllt-Mor-gan
party.
Within the last three years the
Rockefellers have gradually obtained
a foothold In the New York Central;
New York. New Haven Hartford,
Chicago Northwestern and other
lines usually known as Vanderbllt
Morgan railroads.
New methods of doing business will
be introduced in the New York Cen
tral railroad. One of the most Im
portant changes. It is said, will be the
retirement of Senator Depew, chair
man of he board of directors.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1905-02-20/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Kansas+Strikes+Standard+Oil+Opposes+Transfer+Big+Octopus+Frenzied+Revolt&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.398,0.471,0.484,0.525,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Opposes Transfers to
the Big Octopus
Legislature Passes Six Bills
as Result of Frenzied
Revolt

Topeka Kan., Feb. 20. The Oil Pro
ducers' Association has engaged Sena
tor Fitzpatriek and Representatives
Beekman to go to Washington to op
pose the transfer of the Foster leases
in Indian Territory to the Standard Oil
f "mmny. The Kansas delegation in
congress will be asked to oppose the
transfer.
A Topeka special says: The state of
Kansas, with $400,000 and a stiff
backed population, has set about the
task of fighting Standard Oil, with
$400,000,000,000, and tentacles spread
ing all over tho United States and for
eign countries. The battle between the
Sunflower state and the greatest of all
monopolies nnd its ultimate outeomo
will be worth watching.
Back of tho state of Kansas are
powerful influences which have not yot
appeared upon the canvas. The peo
ple of the state have appealed to Thos.
W. Lawson, of Boston, who has already
paid his sarcastic compliments to
Standard Oil, to take the generalship
of the fight, but it is doubtful if he
will accept. However, it is figurod he
may bo relied upon for any friomlly
counsel.
In six days the Kansas legislature
has passed the anti-trust legislatien:
Anti -discrimination bill Aimed at
.standard Oil.
Maximum freight rate bill To pre
vent railroads favoring Standard Oil.
linilroad commission bill To pro
vent Standard Oil dominating stato
railroads.
Stato refinory bill To compote with
Standard Oil.
Anti-gas pumping bill To prevent
use of artificial powor, thus keeping
Kansas gas within her borders.
Pipe lino common carrior act
Throws open oil conduits to all competition.
Delegations of hundreds of stalwart
ami determined men swarmod up to the
state capital today from the oil fields
and positively demanded that tho bill
pass. It is also true that not all of
theso min were oil producers. l"n their
ranks one could see many speculators
men who have invested in "wild
cat" oil schemes. Those men are anx
ious that the stock they purchased at
10 cents on the dollar should become
worth a trille more than the paper up
on whirh the certificates are written.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1905-02-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Congressman+Campbell+Standard+Oil+Fraud+Regulation&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.108,0.868,0.297,0.322,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Campbell Again Has Con.
ference With Iloosevelt.
Senate Wants Other Trusts In
cluded in Investigation.
Washington, Feb. 21. Senator Long
this morning received a telegram from
the president of the Kansas senate and
speaker of the Kansas house of repre
sentatives containing the text of the
concurrent resolution of the Kansas
legislature in regulation to what is
known as the Foster lease in the Osage
Indian reservation declaring against the
extension of the lease.
Senator Long at once called for the
president and secretary of interior and
they informed him that the matter had
been definitely settled and that their
decltion in the matter would not be
changed.
It was stated that an agreement had
been reached between the secretary of
a. '"-r"v V' i
,iZ J TiTT"--.-.-'
X 7
I' yy
Congressman P. P. Campbell of Kansas Who Has Become Famous for His
Fight on Standard Oil.
Interior and the oil men interested in
the extension of the lease which agree
ment had bean inserted as a provis
ion in the Indian appropriation bill re
ported yesterday to the senate.
The president and secretary of inter
ior were very positive in stating that
this agreement was satisfactory to
them and would be carried out.
The provision is to the effect that
any allottmerts on Osage reservations
in Oklahoma made under the Foster
blanket lease of March 16, 1X96, which
leases and sub-lea.e were executed pri
or December 31. 1904. or executed after
that date based on contracts made
prior thereto and approved by the sec
retary of interior, "To the extent of
680.0'XI acres in the aggregate," are ex
tended for a period of ten years from
March 16, 1906, and provision is also
made for increase on royalty on gas
from $50 to J100 per annum.
Representative P. P. Campbell re
ceived a similar telegram containing
the Fitzpatrick resolution. Mr. Camp
bell also visited the president and later
in the day consulted with Senator Long
in regard to the matter.
Senator Long presented to the senate
today a copy of the concurrent resolu
tion number 21 of the Kansas house of
representatives which he received today
from J. R. Burrow, secretary of state
and which provides that "Our represen
tative in congress be requested and our
senators directed to prepare, urge and
perfect such national legislation as will
control the Standard Oil company and
protect the oil industry in Kansas from
destruction by the greatest monopoly
the world has ever known."
Representative Campbell again visit-
ea tne president today and conferred I
with him further regarding the gov-1
ernmental investigation of standard nil
The president again took occasion to
assure Mr. Campbell and through the
senate of Kansas that investigation
would be most thorough.
The Kansas legislature has taken
another rap at the Standard Oil com
pany. Both houses have adopted a
resolution calling upon our congress
men to prevent the renewal of the
oil leases in the Indian Territory and
to work to annul the Standard's leases.
This is interesting, because it is sup
Posed that at least one member of
the Kansas congressional delegation is
very much concernea m the Indian
Territory oil leases.
The senate Monday afternoon adopt
ed the following resolution presented
by Senator Fitzpatrick:
"Whereas, The Standard Oil company
has a blanket lease for oil and gas of
the Osage Indian reservation, known
as the 'Foster lease,' which, if it con
tinues to hold, will make it able to de
stroy private producers and drive them
out of business; and
"Whereas, The secretary of interior
has declared in public prints that this
lease, which is commonly known as the
Foster lease,' passed into the control
and ownership of the said Standard Oil
company by fraud; and
"Whereas. The secretary of the inter
ior has consented under protest to re
new to the Standard Oil company, o"r
its agents and representatives, the lease
of nearly 700,000 acres of this land; and
"Whereas, The 700,000 acres he has
selected is in the heart and body of the
oil and pas portion of the reservation,
leaving for individual lessees or pur
chasers only pasture land; and
"Whereas, The said 700,000 acres is the
richest portion of the western oil field,
and its continued use and development
by the Standard Oil company would add
to the power of that,company to anni
hilate other production; and
"Whereas, The Standard Oil company
has been declared by public opinion to
be an outlaw, and by its tyrannival prac
tices and unfair competition the enemy
of honest commerce; therefore, be it
"Resolved, By the senate of the state
of Kansas, the house concurring there
in, that the president, the secretary of
interior, and the congress of the Uni
ted States be, and they are hereby re
quested to hold up and annul the said
'Foster lease," in whole, which the sec
retary of interior has declared in pub
lic statement was originally obtained
by fraud.
"Resolved, Further, that copies of
this memorial be telegTaphed by the
president of the state senate, and the
speaker of the house, to the president
of the United States, the secretary of
interior, the president of the senate, the
speaker of the house, the Hon. Chester
I. Long and the Hon. P. P. Campbell;
and that Senator Long and Representa
tive Campbell give it as wide publicity
as possible.
"Resolved, Further, especially ad
dressing the Kansas delegation in con
gress, that this is a contest of the hon
est industry of the land against insolent
greed and commercial out-lawry, and it
is the duty of all men who hold offi?e
by the suffrage of the people of Kansas
to help in a war which their state ha3
first declared by legislative action."
The vote on the resolution was as fol
lows: yeas Betts, Elaker, Brewer, Buschow.
Chapman. Sonnor. Dolley, Fitzpatrick,
Fulton. Getty, Gilbert, Griffin, Has
kell, Hodgts. Huffman, Hughes. Mar
tin of Bourbon, Martin of Woodson. Por
ter of Crawford. Quincy, Simons. Smith of
Edwards. Stillings, Tucker, Wilkerson,
Young 26.
Nays Benedict, Benson, Lower, Noftz
ger. Porter of Montgomery, Smith of
Franklin, Waggoner 7.
Absent Hamme. Harrison, Hayden.Mil
ler. Peck, Stewart 6.
Senators Benedict, Samuel Porter and
Noftzger opposed the. resolution on the
ground that the statements made could
not be substantiated. This brought Sena
tor Fitzpatrick to the defense of the res
olution and in a lengthy speech he gave
the history of the "Foster lease."
He told of the round about way in which
the Standard Oil secured the blanket
lease on the 700.000 acres of oil lands in the
Osage reservation.
"The senators here who have spoken
about this 'Foster lease' know whom I
speak of when I refer to "the gentleman
from Wisconsin,' and I get it from this
gentleman from Wisconsin that he had
made arrangements to enlist every promi
nent politician in the interests of the In
dian Territory Illuminating Oil company
to secure a rowan! of that lease," said
Senator Fitzpatrick In part. "Those who
have been in Washington have been there
in the intcreMs of this company.
"With a weapon, such as 700.000 acres of
blanket leased oil lands, the Standard Oil
will he able to supply th.s countrv and
the world with oil and it will be impos
sible for any independent refinery to sur
vive against those who own the refineries,
the pi;e lines, the cars and such a lease.
When the people of this country are ris
ing up in every town and village to ask
that this monster be crushed, then for the
government to step in and lease a reser
voir of 700.000 acres of oil. is something the
government will not knowinglv do."
Senator Smith, from Franklin, explain
ed his vote against the resolution by say
ing that the style of literature in the res
olution reminded him of a heated cam
paign speech, and he was opposed to the
language and not to the resolution.
The Fitzpatrick resolution concern
ing the Foster lease was sent imme
diately to the house and there it was
passed by a unanimous vote. The
memorial was telegraphed to Wash
ington, to the officials named in the
resolution, last night at a cost of $65.
Resolutions Offered in Lower
House of Legislature.
Backing Up Kansas in Her Fight
on the Standard.
WOULD LOAN US MONEY
Propose to Furnish 100,000
JVithout Interest.
For a Period of Six Years for
Refinery Project.
CALLS FOR COMMITTEE.
To Confer With Our Legislature
on Subject.
Expresses Accord With Effort
for Commercial Freedom.
Springfield, 111., Feb. 21. The house
today adopted two resolutions affect
ing the Standard Oil company. One
offered by Representative Allen offers
to loan the state of Kansas the sum
of J 100,000 without interest for a
period of six years to aid in establish
ing a state oil refinery and refers to
the Standard Oil company as that
"merciless octopus, whose tentacles
now encircle every state in the union."
The resolution was adopted by a close
viva voce vote amid considerable con
fusion and laughter.
A resolution by Representative Mc
Goorty of Chicago asks for an investi
gation of the laying of pipe lines
through Illinois by the Standard Oil
company and provides for the appoint
ment of a joint committee to confer
with the state officers of Kansas to
agree on steps to be taken toward de
claring such pipe lines common car
riers. This resolution was adopted
without a dissenting vote. Mr. Allen
is a Republican and Mr. McGoorty a
uemocrat.
The McGoorty resolution declares the
present house to be in hearty accord
with the fight of the Kansas legislature
for commercial freedom.
Representative McGoorty explained
when the resolution was introduced
that it was not intended to make any
investigation of the Standard Oil com
pany. "I merely want an investigation of
the pipe line which now extends to
Galesburg and Monmouth," he said.
"This, pipe line later extended to In
diana. If necessary the report of the
committee .appointed may be followed
by a bill to make the company a com
mon carrier and subject to the same
regulations and penalties."
The text of the resolution is as fol
lows: "Whereas, The state of Kansas,
through its legislature and chief execu
tive has taken steps and adopted meas
ures to provide against the aggression
of the Standard Oil company.
"Whereas, Kansas has become a great
oil producing state and under proper
enabling legislation purposes to supply
to the consumer oil and its bi-products
in defiance of threats of extermination
and ruin, reported to have been made
against said state by Standard Oil com
pany, and
"Whereas, In this regard the assertion
by Kansas of her rights and powers as
a sovereign state of this union, has
awakened the hope that this most me
nacing of all combinations is amenable
to the law of the land, and
"Whereas, It is reported that pipe lines
and conduits controlled by the Standard
Oil company, extending from the oil fields
of Kansas to certain cities of the state of
Illinois intend to supply oil to such cities
are rapidly apiroaching completion and
that such pipe lines are proposed to ex
tend across the state to its eastern boun
darv; and,
"Whereas, The people of this state have
the right to know and be fully advised as
to the purpose of the Standard Oil com
pany In this regard and under what rights
and terms it may claim as a common car
rier or in any other capacity; now, there
fore, be It
"Resolved. By he house of representa
tives of the general assembly of Illinois,
the senate concurring therein, that a joint
committee of this Joint assembly consist
ing of five members, be appointed forth
with, three of whicj shall be appointed by
this house and two of which members
shall be appointed by the senate, for the
purpose of conferring and communicating
with the Kansas legislature and its state
officers and determining and representing
to this general assembly and to both
branches thereof, the scope and extent of
said pipe lines and such other information
necessary to enable this general assem
bly to safeguard and protect the people of
this state and its commercial interests. Be
it further'
"Resolved. That the members of this
general assembly are in hearty accord
with the efforts of the Kansas legislature
and its chief executive in the great fight
for commercial freedom."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1905-08-25/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Kansas+Ida+Tarbell+Rockefeller+Standard+Oil&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.101,0.348,0.681,0.738,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>What lias Happened la Kansas.
Miss Ida M. barbell, in the Septem
ber McCluro's emashos Iho last refuge
of thoso apologists of John D. Rockc
fcllor and v his associates who, whon
tainted monoy discussion was rifo,
cried that if Standard Oil had been
an offender onco it had now reformed,
and put itsolf nbovo reproach..
"If ono wants a noat demonstra
tion," says Miss Tarboll, "complete to
tho Inst detail, that the Standard Oil
Company is today, as always, con
spiracy in restraint of trade,' ho should
go to Kansas. Tho 'oil war' in that
state, which in turn amused, bowil
dorcd and excited tho country during
tho earlier months of tho present year,
was tho direct result of a suddon real
ization by tho Knnenns that tho Standv
nrd had been playing in tholr torrltory
a gamo 30 years old, playing it under
their vory noses so quickly and doftly
that, koon as thoy prido thomsolves on
being, thoy had not realized its moan
lug until thoy began to fool tho pres
surol" Tho story of tho Standard's attempt
to gobblo .tho Kansas oil Hold is tho
history of ita earlier practical aggres
sions repeating itself, but with a dif
ferent onding. In Kansas it encoun
tered a now'brand of public spirit, and
wont into .tho contest with this onlight
onod and electric commonwealth, han
dicapped by its post sins; tut for a
whllo, until public sontimont was
Jnrousod, Standard Cdl had ovorythlng
its own way.
Miss Tarboll lolls In tho Soptombcr
number what Standard Oil did to Kan-
sas, how it enmo into tho ptato after
fortune had boon sunk in locating
tho oil, and by tho operations of its
old, wol-trlcd juggurnaut, tho railroad
rate, proceeded! to gobblo tho fruits of
tho pioneers' sowlbg. Miss Tarboll
shows in tho clearest and most inform
ing way just how tho railroad operat
ed as tho socrot allies of tho Stand
ard. Tho wholo railroad situation ap
pears In mtniaturo in this story of tho
Standard Oil's smothering of tho Kan
sas oil Industry. What happonod thoro
Is going on nil ovor tho- "United Statos,
but tho Kansnns nro tho only Ameri
cans who havo put tho sttHo abovo
'special privilege "You may bo in
vesting $15,000,000 for taking caro of
our oil," eald tho pooplo. "You may
do tho work moro promptly and per
fectly than nny othor concorn ovor
could, but justlco is moro important
than millions, and every man shall
havo a cbanco in Kansas. Wo aro go
ing to stop your gamo. You must play
fair with ui If you stay In Kansas.
This is not tho tono that stntos usu
ally adopt toward tholr' business rul
ers. Kansas is tho first to try It. What
has boon tho conscquonco to Kansas
of this determined attitudo, Miss Tar
boll xosorvos for tho Octobor numbor,
in which sho will tell "What Kansas
Did to Standard Oil."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1906-05-10/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Grafting+Exposed+Standard+Oil+Topeka+Wilhoit+Espionage+Cheated&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.234,0.374,0.209,0.227,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MORE GRAFTING
IS EXPOSED
CHICAGO, May 10. —E. M. Wil
hoit of Topeka, former Standard
Oil agent, at the Interstate com
merce commission hearing today
testified that tho Standard Oil com
pany ordered him to pay for in
formation concerning competitors
and that the Standarl Oil main
tained an ospolnago system through
out the country. "Water White,"
"Perfection" and "Headlight" are
three grades of oil gold from the
same tank. Ho said:
"I know I cheated, hut so they
instructed me. The Standard Oil
company values a man only by the
dirty work he does. Self respect
compelled me to quit. I used
chocks to bribe railroal employes,
as I told the commission. The San
to Fe and other railroads reduced
tariffs as gifts to tho Standard Oil
company."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1907-10-31/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Standard+Oil+Trust+Kansas+Supreme+Court</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>OIL TRUST HEARD
Standard Files Its Replies in
Supreme Court.
Kansas Business Not Directed
From 26 Broadway.
86' Broadway. Here are a few of -the
questions ana answers:
Q From whom, if any person, does
the Standard Oil company of Kansas
purcnase crude our
A From the Prairie Oil 1 and Gas
company.
Q To whom and Jn what manner
does the Standard Oil company of
Kansas sell refined oil. gasoline, and
other oil Droducts?
The answer shows that the oil is all Found That It Ended Sooner
som to me eranaara uii companies or
DALTOyETURNS.
His Four Months Parole Ex
pires Today.
HOW IT
Indiana, Kentucky, New Tork, Ne
braska, and Ohio; to the Continental
OPERATES. I company and the Granby Mining
omeuinr company.
Q By whom and in what manner
are the prices fixed at which the
Than Expected.
HOCH CANT BE FOUND
Prairie Oil Company Merely a standard ou company of Kansas pur- Was Thought That He Would
cuncrcs truos on ana ai wnicn it sens
refined oil, gasoline and other oil pro
aucts
A The Standard Oil
Frcducing Concern.
Be Pardoned.
Enormous Sums Paid in DiTi-
dends on Kansas Holdings.
company of
ZSZmF.iX rud.? 0,1 a e "ket Says That He Has Been Treated
prices and sells oil products at prices!
This was Standard Oil day in the
Kansas supreme court. Amended an
swers in the Standard Oil ouster suits
were filed by the Standard Oil of Kan
sas, the Standard Oil of Indiana, and
the Prairie Oil and Gas company. The
two former filed with the court their
answers to all the interrogatories pro
pounded by the state.
In the amended answers and in the
replies to the interrogatories, the fact
Is freely admitted that the Standard Oil
companies of Kansas and of Indiana
are owned by the Standard Oil com
pany of New Jersey; that the Prairie
Oil and Gas company is owned by the
National Transit company, and that
the Standard Oil of New Jersey owns
the National Transit.
This in itself would constitute a
prima facie case against the Standard
for violation of the anti-trust laws, but
the answer sets forth the novel defense
that each of the companies does its own
line of work, and is in no sense a corn-
fixed by itself.
Tables are presented to show the
amount of the product of the Kansas
company and the total gallons of re
nnet! oils, napthas. gas oils, fuel oils,
lubricating oils, asphalt and acid oils
are as xonows:
1903
1904...
1S0S
Well In Topeka.
At 3:10 this afternoon, Emraett
Dalton, who for four months has been
out on parole from the state peniten-
19,573,992 tiary, took the Union Pacific train for
31.517,713 ILansing, to reenter tne state peniten
47,179.632 tiary, under a life sentence.
CLOSE UP TIIE 'ARCHWAYS.
No Vehicles "Will pass
State House.
Around the
isuo... 66. 088,005 I Rowmnr Tlnnh. Khn It lean thomht
Q Is it not true that the Standard I r..i.. n.,ni.
mr.r Tr l I c-.c.v. I""
w" .cSm.. K,. ,i un
reports of all Its business to the
Standard Oil conmanv of New Jersey? not returned to lopeka, and ail er-
A No
The answers of the Standard Oil
company of Indiana are very similar to
those of Kansas, being prepared by
Alfred L. Kday. the general attorney
and attested by William P. Cowan, vice
president of the Standard Oil of Indi
ana. In the list of stockholders of the
Standard Oil of Indiana appear
such well known names as John D.
Archbold, 1.801 shares, H. H. Rogers,
2.001 shares. W. H. Tilford's profits
on his shares have by his orders been
paid to the Standard Oil company of
New Jersey. There have never been
more than ten or a dozen shareholders.
peting company, and consequently no I Back in 1900, J. D. Rockefeller's name
appears as owning one share. Then in
1901, he dropped out, and William
Rockefeller appeared On the list for
one share. William Rockefeller stuck
until early in 1903, when his name
ceases to appear.
Bearing In mind that the capital
stock of the Standard Oil company of
Indiana was only 11,000,000, it is in
teresting to observe the size of the
dividends paid. They are listed as fol
lows:
June 7, 1900. 749.925
Sept. 12. 1900.
Dec. 20, 1900...
March 18. 1901.
May 29, 1901...
combination has been formed.
The answer alleges that the Prairie
Oil and Gas company is merely a pro
ducing company: that it confines its
attention to pumping oil out of the
earth and transporting it through its
pipe lines.
The Standard Oil of Kansas refines
oil and sells it at wholesale.
The Standard Oil company of Indiana
purchases the products of the Stand
ard Oil company of Kansas, and sells
these products in a wholesale and re-
tall way.
The Standard Oil of New Jersey, it
is solemnly asserted, has never done
uni. hfia1n nt Anv lrinri In 1tanftlll
Thnn th. whole scheme of Standard Sept. 11, 1901
fill munanment Is set forth and the bis: I Feb. 21, 1902..
Rockefeller trust !s out in the open, Sept. 16. 1902
flchtlne- for its life. Jan. 21. 1W3..
Each of the amended answers filed Feb. 27. 1903...
asserts that there are no agreements June 20, 1908
between the various members of the Dec. 10, 1903.
Standard Oil family: that each head March 8. 1904...
of the hvdra does its own thinking. May 17. 1904
and that No. 26 Broadway, N. T., does Oct. 18, 1904.
not control or direct any of the affairs. Dec. 7, 1904
But the answers to the interrogatories Feb. 21, 1905
show that the various subsidiary com- May 23, 1905....
panies are eacn contronea Dy ine oig Dec. 12, 1905.
guns of the Standard Oil of New Jer- Feb. 26, 1906
sey. and so it isn't really necessary Nov. 14. 1906
that the orders should come direct Jan. 2, 1907..
from 26 Broadway. I Feb. 21, 1907..
The. amended answers to the petl-1 March 21. -1907
lions oi me state aiso set lorin -the
anti-trust laws of Kansas are In
violation of the bill of rights, the con
stitution of the state and the constitu
tion of the united States.
The amended answers in the case are
signed by Alfred D. Eddy, W. S. Fitz-
Patrick, R. R. Vermillion, W. E. Stan
ley, and Earl W. Evans on behalf of
the Standard OH of Kansas and of In
diana, while for the Prairie Oil Gas
company the answers are signed by
J. B. F. Gates and J. D. McFarland.
April 10, 1907...
May 14. 1907...,.
May 31, 1907
July 30, 1907
Sept. 6, 1907
otal
LOOK OUT FOR POLICE.
One of the most astonishing things Special Officers Sworn In to Take Care
revealed by the Interrogatories is the
fact that the Standard OH company of
Kansas, with 11.000,000 capital, has paid
32,233,300 in dividends, while the Stand
ard Oil of Indiana, which is the big
clearing house for the retail profits,
with only $1,000,000 capital, has in less
than seven years paid over $50,000,000
In dividends.
The answers of the Standard Oil of
Kansas show that the 10,000 shares of
stock in that company are owned as
follows: H. M. Flagler, 6,000 shares;
James A. Moffett. 8993. shares; A. M.
Dunks, A. Swoboda, Thos. Black. W.
P. Cowan, W. M. Burton, G. W. Stahl,
J. C. McDonald, one share each. H. M.
Flager is vice president and director packed with
or tne stanaara on or isew jersey. I morning.
ana James A. Aioirett is a director or
the same. Cowan and Burton are
stockholders of the same company.
The following is a statement of the
amount of dividends which the Stan
dard Oil' company of Kansas has paid:
of Halloween Offenders.
For the purpose of circumventing Hal
loween depredators, a large number of
special policemen have been sworn in
for. tonight. They will lurk in the dark
places all over the city, unmarked by
brass buttons or shining star, and grab
crossing lifters, gate destroyers and
other disturbers, without warning. Ow
ing to the class of devilment attending
the date on former years, the police
court will not be over lenient with of
fenders caught by the officers tonight.
and the police expect to have the Jail
young
May 19, 1894 100
June 6, 1895 100
January 19. 1897 100
June 1, 1898 6.000
1, 1899 8.000
1, 1900 20.000
1. 1901 10.000
2. 1902 10,000
25. 1906 750.000
November 16, 1906 600.000
February 5. 1907 200.000
June 28, 1907 400.000
October 3, 1907 250.000
Croker's Horse Beats the King's.
Newmarket, Eng.. Oct. 81. Rich
ard Croker's Rhoder, ridden by W.
Bullock, won the Dunhurst plate to
day, beating King Edward's Perrier,
which was second.
DEATHS AND FUNERALS.
June
June
June
June
June
Total $2,233,300
The company denies that it has a
private telegraph wire leading from
16 Broadway, New Tork. to the man
aging office of the Standard Oil com
pany of Kansas, or that the policy of
the Kansas company is dictated from</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87056245/1911-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Supreme+Court+Dissolves+Trust+Sherman+Anti&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.178,0.083,1.004,1.088,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>5UPR,F,V3E COURT DISSOLVES THE STANDARD OIL TRUST
iXountv ifec order iJanlO
WEEK
REPUEL
CAN
i
J
V
Epoch Making Decision Marks the High
way of Industrial Progress InAmer
ica Prevents Combinations for the
Restraint of Trade.
(From Chicago Tribune)
petition11 to such an extent as tobe
a combination of conspiracy in re
straint of trade in violation of the
first section of the Sherman act and
also to be an attempt at a monopo
lization which became a perennial
violation of the second section.
"We see no cause to doubt the
correctness of these con elusions,"
said the chief justice, "considering
HAVE FRIENDSHIP DAY
English Roses Sent Prom the Grave
of Ann Hathaway by Mrs.
Young Alice Freeman
Palmer.
Washington, D. C, May. 15 The
Standard Oil company of New Jersey
and its nineteen subsidiary corpora
tions were declared today by the
Supreme Court of the United States
to be a conspiracy and combination
in restraint of trade.
It also was held to be monopoliz
ing interstate commerce in violation the bfat from every aspect'
nf tbfl Sherman anti-trust law. The
dissiolution of the combination was Ruthless Crushing of Rivals,
ordered to take place within six Ranging over a career of thirty
month?. (two years, the Standard Oil corn
Thus eilded the tremendous 6trug- paay is found by the court to have
gle on the part of the government had one continuous purpose the
to put down by authority of law a crushing out of rival. In subject
combination which it claimed was a ing to scrutiny the acts and doings
menace to the industrial and econ- of Standard Oil in the long distant
omi3 advancement of the entire past for the purpose of getting
ountrv. .assistance in discovering intent and
ipurpose, Justice White said:
limits to "unaue nestraini. ttWe tMnk no disinterested mind
At the same time the court inter- can survey the period in Question
.pretod the Sherman atti-trust law without being irresistibly driven to
so as to limit its application to the conclusion that the very genius
acts of "undue' restraint of trade for commercial development and
It was on this point that the only organization which it would seem
discordant nete was heard in theVas manifested from the berinn:ncr
ouri. soon b'ejrot an intent and purpose to
Justice Harlan dissented, claim- exclude others, which was frequently
in? that cases already decided by manifested bv .acts and dealinsrs
the court had determined onee for wholly inconsistent with the theory ters from those members who have
all that the word undue or that they were made with the removed from Plymouth,
"unreasonable," or similar words, sn?:e conception of advancing the! Mrs. Ada Corbin responded from
were not m me siaiut?. ne ue- development of business power bv
clared that the reasoning of the nsuai methods, but which, on the
court in arriving at its finding was contrary, necessarily involved the
in effect legislation which belonged intent to drive others from the field
in every instance to congress and anj to exclnde them from their
not to the courts. j right to trade and thus? accomplish
The opinion of the courtwas an-themasiery-whichwa5 the-- end- in
H rouneecr rhy Chief" Justic e White. yjew
Tn printed form it contained more
than 20,000 words. For nearly an Monopoly Intent Continuous,
hour the chief justice discussed the "And, considering the period fiom
t ease from the bench. goin: over most the date of the trust agreements of
-of the points in the printed opinion 1879 and 1882 up to the time of the
but not once referring to it in order expansion of the New Jersey cor
poration, the pradual extension of
the power over the commerce in oil
which ensued, the decision of the
v far the gT3ater portion of the
opinion of the chief justice was de
voted to the justification of th6
court in requiring that the "rule
of reason ".be applied to restmins
of trade bef ore they were held to be
violations of the Sherman antitrust
law.
The court found this justification
-in the common law of the fore
fathers and in the general law of
ihe country at the time the Sher
man antitrust law was passed.
In short, the court held that the
technical words of tt .statute were
to be riven the meaning which those
-words had in the common law and in
ihe ,vw of the country at the time
nf the enactment.
This meaning of the words accord
ins totheeourt called for the ex-
-erises of. reason in determining
what restraints on trade were pro-
fiiUtcd.
XZzzi Ccnpicta cf Trxits.
In the course of tee opinion,
Chief .Jnstiee White recalled that
-tha ltrwcr court the United States
Circuit Court of Eastern Ifirccrl
had foend that the effect of the
tcquHtbn by the Standard OilCom-
Ti-nv of New Jersey ox tne snares oi
other corporations in exchange for
Irs eertiScates, irate to the corpora-
iicn an enlarged and mere perfect,
sway and control over tha trade and
commcrca in petrol run and its pro
ducts,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1908-01-31/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=President+Roosevelt+Law+Defying+Rich+Attacked+Standard+Oil+Fraud&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.137,-0.064,1.274,1.274,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The President in a Special Message
Compares Crimes of Standard Oil
to Murder Fraud and Ballot
I Stuffing
ROOSEVELTS PLATFORM AS HE 1
STATES IT IN SECOND MESSAGE
We ixek to control lawdefying wealth in the first place to prevent its
doing dire evil to tho Republic and In tho next place to avoid tho vindictive
and dreadful radicalism which If lert uncontrolled It Is certain In tho end
to arouse
Sweeping attacks upon all property upon all men of means without re
gard to whether they do well or 111 would sound the death knell of the Re
public and such atucks became Inevitable If decent citizens permit those rich
men whose lives are corrupt and evil to domineer In swollen pride unchecked
and unhindered over the destinies of this country
We act in no vindictive spirit and we are no respecter of persons If a
labor union does wrong we oppose It as firmly as we oppose a corporation
which doc wrong and twe stand equally stoutly for the rights of the man of
wealth and for tho rlchts of the waco worker
We sock to protect the property of every man who nets honestly of every
corporation that represents wealth honestly accumulated and honestly used
We seek to stop wrongdoing and we desire to punish the wrongdoers only as
far as Is necessary to achieve this end
I Special to The Evening World
I WASHINGTON Jan 31President Roosevelt sent a special mes
sage to Congress today which is quite the hottest state document he
V ever penned
It is in effect a defense of his administration with respect to his cam
picn against corporations And there are some who will find in it an
ack upon the Supreme Court of the United States
I Never tcfore has he been so bitter in attacking malefactors of great
b wealth He jumps on the Standard Oil Company in vigorous fashion
takes a fall out of tricky corporation lawyers and compares men who bribe
J Matures and illegally manipulate corporations for their own profit to
the leeche who fatten upon blood money from dens of vice gambling
houses and saloons
It is plain to be seen That the Presidents message is an answer to
the broadside campaign of abuse that has been heaped upon him by ad
vertisement and pamphlet since he instigated corporation prosecutions
He stands pat on his record promises further action and eternally lam
tastes his enemies He practically accuses the Standard Oil Company
and certain railroad interests with instigating these attacks
The President disclaims any responsibility for
the panic of last fall and the resulting hard times
lIe blames it upon the speculative folly and flagrant
dishonesty of a few men of great wealth who seek to
shield themselves from the effects of their own
wrongdoing by ascribing its results to the actions of
those who have sought to put a stop to the wrong
doing
In his message the President repeats much that he has said in for
mer messages and in his public speeches but on no previous occasion
has he cut loose with such freedom and vigor It is a message that is
sure to arouse a storm of comment and every citizen who takes the
slightest interest in business or politics should read it carefully I
president Fires a Broadside I
at Men Who Oppose His Policies
i The excuse for the message IE betrayed In ho opening paragraph The
president says
The recent decision of tho Supreme Court In regard to the employers
liability act the experience ot the Interstate Commerce Commission nnd
of the Department of Justice In enforcing the Interstate commerce nud anti
trust lava and the gravely significant attitude toward the Jaw and its ad
ministration recently adopted by certain hells of great corporations render
It desirable that there should Ixi additional legislation as regards certain
II of the relations between labor and capital and between the great corpora
lions aud tho uubllc
Hho Supreme Court has decided the employers liability law to be un
constitutional because its terms apply to employees engaged wholly III intra
elats commerce as well ai to employees engaged In interstate commerco
By a substantial majority the Court holds that the Congress has power to
deal with the question in BO far us Interstate commerce is concerned
As regards the employers liability law I advocate Its imnicdlitto re
cnactmont limiting its scojio so that It shall apply only to the elites of
cases as to which the Court says it can constitutionally apply Jut slrclIlth
m</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-battleships/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033078/1863-07-23/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.066,0.19,0.547,0.593,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Three Days Battle at Gettysburg.
A GRAPHIC ACCOUNT.
[Special correspondence ol the Boston Journal.]
Near Gettysburg, July 2.
How poor, how tame, how insignificant
are all descriptions ot a great battle. Vic
tor Hugo stirs your blood with his des
cription ot Waterloo. Kinglake gives you
the battle ot the Alma in detail, with a
minuteness that wearies, and yet neither
ot them has produced a picture much like
the reality. 1 shrink from the task ot
attempting even an outline of the series ot
battles at Gettysburg, where nearly two
hundred thousand men have met upon the
fi Jd. 1 cannot picture tiie ground, the
hills, ravines, fields, houses, roads, rocks,
trees, the little things ot locality all im
portant to a military commander; neither
can I place the men in proper position in
line ot battle, behind walls and fences,
sheltered by hillocks, gathered in groups
in some all important position, the holding
cf which may turn the tide ot battle.
Then there are the batteries in play, fiash
ing and thundering, hills smoking like vol
canoes, and hollows remitting flames, as it
subterranean fire were bursting upward.
All this to the sight, and quite as much
to the ear —the rolls ot musketry, like
ocean breakers on the beach the rattling
fire, which is as you have heard hailstones
upon a window pane, or the great drops
ot a summer shower upon a roof. There
is the screaming of the shot, the explosion
of shells, the terrifying whizzing ot pieces
in the air; and then there are the groans
of the wounded, which touch one’s sensi
bilities, and it he be not indurated to
scenes of suffering it takes l strength
away and unmans him.
GETTYSBURG.
it is the county seat of Adams, Penn
sylvania. Nearly forty miles, a little
north ol cast from Frederick on the head
waters of the Monocacy. Rock creek,
which in spring time leaps over huge
granite boulders, ruus south, a mile east
of the town, ami is the main stern of the
Monocacy. Being a county seat, ic is
also a grand centre for this section of the
State, contains six or eight thousand in
habitants,; and lias a beautilul location
surrounded with scenery of quiet beauty,
bills, valleys, the dark outline and verdure
clad sides ot the Blue Ridge in the west,
and the heaved up,billowy Oacoctiu range
on the south. It is a tocus lor roads
north, east, south, west, from nearly all
points of the compass. You are reminded
of a spider, or a bug, or an old daddy
long-legs, with its numerous limbs reach
ing in all directions.
Notice its locality. Tue Cacoctm range
of mountains is south ot it—knolls, here,
but ten miles down, over the State lice,
they become mountains ot respectable
size. There are two ranges—the Cacoc
tin, and the South mountain, with a nar
row valley of surpassing richness, fertili
ty and beauty between. Gettysburg is at
ttie heau ot ibis valley. Down in Mary
land, the mountain walls have lew gate
ways, so iew that Lee having massed his
army at Gettysburg, could not be flanked
through those passes except by a very
large tores. To attack him there from the
South, or from the direction of Hagers
town would be a complete division ot our
army. It would be comparatively aueasy
matter for him to fall upon our iulerioi
force, debouching through the Suuih
Mountain passes and annihilate it, because
it would not be in supporting distance of
any force moving upon him from the east
at Gettysburg. Or, if a superior force
went to move through those passes to at
tack him, he being at the bead ot the
mountain range, would have an open road
to Baltimore.
I make this explanation in regard to
locality that the motions, the marchings
and the concentration ot the Union araiy
may be clearly understood. Lee chose
Gettysburg fora battle ground because he
knew he could not be Hanked ou the
South; that any attempt to flank him
there would be just what he would like
to see. Chess players sometimes set traps.
Perhaps he thought Meade would rush
through those gaps to cut him off’ from
the Potomac at Williamsport.
Ou Saturday last the army was at Fred
erick, and Meade was placed in command.
Early, of Ewell's corps of rebels, was at
York and on the Susquehanna, threatening
to cross at the Columbia bridge. Rhodes
and Johnson of his corps were in front of
Harrisburg. Philadelphia was greaiiy ex
cited for tear that Lee was about to make
a grand dash for its capture. The army
must be manceuvered to circumvent him.
It he crossed at UarrisLurg, Meade mast
cross below to preserve his short line of
march to keep the inside of the track and
get in ahead. Or if he was not intending
such a scheme, it was necessary to keep
the army in position to head him off from
an advance upon Baltimore and Washing
ton. It may be ea-ily seen that if Meade,
alarmed for Philadelphia, should throw
his entire army over to the Susquehanna
north of Baltimore, that by a rapid march
to the mouth of the Monocacy, he could
keep Meade at bay, and hence Baltimore
and Washington would be at his mercy.
Some each considerations as these doubt
less were elements in Lee’s calculations.
But the Union army has not been thrown
over tv") the Susquehanna, neither has Bal
timore or Washington been uncovered,
bat has been so manceavertd that it coaid
be concentrated right or lett, as circum
stances might require.
THE MOVEMENTS.
On Sunday, the 28th of June, the First
and Eleventh corps were at Middletown,
in the valley between the Cacoctiu and
the Blue Ridge. They were moved east
to Frederick, and then directly up the
Monocacy valley, on the west side of the
stream, through Mechanicstown and Em-
metsburg to Gettysburg, where they ar
rived yesterday. Their line of march was
direct, and therefore shorter than the
routes ot the other corps. The Oacoctin
range was a wall to them all the way,
preventing Lee from making a counter
movement, and attacking them in hank.
Ihe Second and Fifth corps were made the
centre column, and were thrown across
the Monocacy, easl, three miles above
Frederick, and moved northeast through
Union to Frizlesburg, which is near the
State line. The Third and Twelfth corps
took the ilidd'ebarg road, which is mid
way these, ami of course a little nearer to
Gettysburg as a centre than that taken by
the other two corps. The Sixth crossed
the Monocacy east of Frederick, and
ished for Westminster.
The lines of march were like the sticks
of a fan—Frederick being the point of ra
diation. By taking these routes the army
was placed in position lor quick movement
to keep Baltimore covered—to cross the
Susquehanna by pontoon below Harris
burg, if need, be, and save Philadelphia,
r, lor preventing Lee from slipping down
past the Cacoctin tor a rapid movement
on Washington. On Sunday afternoon
the troops all moved from Frederick upon
these projected lines. Tuesday afternoon
the sixth corps was at Westminster, the
Second and Filth at Frizlesburg, the Third
and Twelfth a* Taneytown, the First and
Eleventh at Emmettsburg.
They were ail in motion on these lines,
when suddenly orders were given for a
change of direction—a change to ail ex
cept the First and Eleventh. They had
their faces set duo north up the Frederick
and Gettysburg pike and kept on. Yon
see all the other slicks ot the fan bent
northwest and gathered to a point at Get
tysburg.
D
Lee’s movements necessitated tms sud
den change. He withdrew from Harris
burg and York on Monday. He was con
centrating at Gettysburg. If Meade kept
on his lines of March Lee would have
him wholly in flank. All the while his
main army had been no further north than
Chambersbarg. He was moving Long
street and A. P. Hiii directly east, anl he
would come upon the corps separately and
crumble them up—splinter them as you
can broom a walking stick—by pounding
it endwise with a hammer.
These simple straight lines will show it:

s
Ewell.
13 2
Longstreet.
II 12 5 6
mil. JBSS*
The distance from the First to the Third
is ten miles from the Third to the Second
is tea miles; and from the Second to the
Sixth ten—making the Sixth thirty miles
from the First. On Sunday Ewell begins
to fall back. On that day Lmgstreet and
Hill are pretty well advanced from Cham
bersbarg oat toward Gettysburg. Lee is
waiting for his opportunity, as a cat waits
foi a mouse. You see the movement at a
glance—the entire Union array sweeping
north in a line, like a rank ot mowers in
a hay field. Ewell moving rapidly south
along the Cumberland Valley—on its east
ern edge, to Gettysburg, Longstreet and
Hill moving east,
Lee is foiled in Ids anticipations of splin
tering the end of the column and driving
his blows its entire length. Suddenly the
Union array begins to shut itself together
like a telescope. Instead of being a length
ened column it becomes a mass a Gettys
burg. The Ist and 11th reach the town
on Wednesday morning, Juty Ist, the 3d
and 12th arrive in the afternoon, the 2d
and sth Thursday morning, and the Gth
Thursday afternoon.
THE GROUND.
I have said that Rock creek runs south
about a mile cast of the town. As you
approach the town from the south-east on
the Littletown road, or the Baltimore pike
as it is called, you have a gradual ascent
nearly a mile from Rock creek before
gaining the top of the ridge—not an even
inclined plane, but undulating—the ground
being broken, heaved up on either hand
into rocky hills and knolls, nearly all
cleared —here and there an oak and chest
nut grove, scattered houses, small gardens,
apple orchards, stone wails in abundance—
the ground divided into small patches to
get rid of the rocks. As yon approach
the top of the ridge your face set to the
northwest, you notice a hill a half mile to
your right, quite sharp and steep, and
wooded. Remember it, because it is an
ini; ortant point; on it, ns we shall see,
rests our right wing.
Looking straight ahead you notice on
the very top of the ridge a house. It is
not a dwelling house, hut the gateway of
the Gettysburg cemetery. This is the
strongest and highest point of Meade’s
position. The 11th corps is there, and
Reward has his batteries standing over
the mouldering forms ot the dead who have
been borne hither in times ot peace by
mourning Irieuds. Roses, C} press and
daises are in bloom, scenting the morning
air; but the hoofs of horses, the rumble
ot ammunition trains, and the roar of
cannon resound through the streets of the
silent city.
You look a half mile distant in the north
east and sea the wooded hill before men
tioned. Turning northwest, right in front
ot you on the western slope is the town.
It is not more than torly or fifty rods to
the buildings. On the north side of the
Baltimore pike, between the buildings and
the wooded hill are newly mown fields.
In these fields are batteries with breast
works thrown up by Howard on Wednes
day night—light affairs, not intending to
resist cannon shot, but to protect the can
nonies from sharp shooters. You see his
lines ot infantry behind stone walls. The
cannoniers are lying beside their pieces—
sie ping perhaps, but at any rate keeping
close, tor, occasionally, a bullet comes
this way.
Away off beyond the town northwest,
is a hill wood-crowned, sloping gradually
to the south, dotted witti the white can
vas of wagon trains. There the road from
Oardsle omes in. Down at its base is
the Lutheran Theological Seminary, h
laige brick building, half hid by the tall
forest trees tuat surround it. Between
the seminary and the town are smooth
meadows, with here and there an oak or
walnut standing alone in the landscape.
Tnere, south of the seminary, is the fine
residence of Dr. Schmucker, well known
in the Theological world as an able writer
and thinker. The distance from the cem
etery to the seminary is a mile and a half.
Looking nearer, at oar own line, you
see, as yon turn your face from the north
west to the sooth, that this ridge tends a
little to the southeast. Adjoining the
cemetery is r.n oak grove on the eastern
slope and an apple orchard on the western
side. Then you come to cleared fields.—
Coming up from the south, is the Teuey
town road. On it is a mean little house,
on the south side of the road, the Ameri
can fiag dying in front of it. There are
horses hitched to the fences and nibbling
the grass in the fields. Officers with stars
on their shoulders are examining maps,
writing and sending off cavalrymen. It
is Gen. Meade's headquarters. It is on
the battlefield. TV hen the rebel batteries
open it will be a warm place.
The nege, as X have said, along here, is
smooth, but a mile south ot the cemetery
it suddently rises to a hillock, rocky,
knobby, with boulders, and covered with
wood. It is Round Top Hill. The trees
on the top have been cut away and there
is a signal station, There is the extreme
left of Meade’s line.
Looking now along the western aiupe of
the ridge, you see the Emmetsburg turn
pike running southerly, while the ridge
itself, as I have said, runs a little to the
east ot south. Our skirmishers are west
of the Emmettsburg road, our batteries
are on the ridge, and the Third corps i
lying in the meadow along the east side of
the Emmettsburg ros J.
Looking now. once more, into the north
west, to the Theological Seminary, yon see
a counter ridge of land, lower at the sem
inary than at the cemetery, also running
south, with groves, hedges, single trees,
hillocks and undulations, nut so abrupt as
on the eastern ridge. Here is the rebel
line. Let us start now at the hill on cur
right—the hill we noticed as we came up
the Littletown road—for a walk along the
entire line. We go halt a mile i little
south of west to the town, ihen southeast
for a mile and a halt, the line being almost
two miles long. Behind this is concen
trated Meade’s entire army, with the ex
ception of cavaliy. Lee being outside, of
course Las a longer line, but in its general
direction Lee’s conforms to Meade’s, the
cemetery being Meade’s angle and the sem
inary Lee’s. I speak now ot the position
on Thursday and Friday.
fiebi day’s ENGAGEMENT.
Gee, Reynolds had received information
that there were rebels in the vicinity of
Gettysburg, He was encamped several
miles south of the town, on Marsh creek,
one of the affluents ot the Monocacy. He
was moving from Emmetsburg, starting
at 7 A. M., and reaching the town at 10.
He sent Buford’s cavalry with a battery
ahead, and found the enemy in force west
ot the town, near the Theological Semina
ry, approaching by the C’asulown road,
which leads to Ghambersburg, west.
Cutler’s brigade, of Wadsworth’s division,
was leading the column, and moved into
the open field near the seminary, on the
double quick Meredith’s brigade ot the
same division also came up rapidly and
formed on the left. This is called the
Western Iron Brigade, composed wholly
of western troops.
Skirmishing commenced, and Reynolds
ordered the divisions to advance, which
was done, and the rebels driven from
their position.
Finding them in strong and increasing
force, Robinson’s division was brought up
on the right of Wadsworth. The sharp
shooting still continued. Gen. Reynolds
rode over the field toward the house of
Dr. Schrnucke to reconnoitre, when he
received the fatal shot through the head.
He had sent a note early in the morn
ing to Gen. Howard, who was behind
wiih the Eleventh. Gen, Howard taking
another road, that there might be no in
terference of trains with troops, made a
rapid march of thirteen miles, and arrived
on the field at half past one. Gen. Dou
bleday was then id command. Gen.
Howard assumed command of the two
corps, Gen. Schurz taking command of the
Eleventh.
Meanwhile Ewell’s entire force of
twenty-five thousand men was pouring in
from the north-east on the York and
Carlisle road, and there was imminent
danger to the First. The arrival of the
Eleventh was most opportune. Gen.
Howard sent a messenger to Gen. (Slo
cum, who was a few miles behind, inform
ing him of the condition of affairs, and at
once made a disposition of his tried force
to meet the onset of Ewell.
Gen, Howard, with a quick eye, on his
advance had noticed Evergreen Cemetery
as a strong position. Seeing also that
the enemy was superior to him, and that
he might be forced to retire, he sent
Sleinwetr’s brigade with a battery of re
serve artillery to hold it. He sent Schurz
and Barlow to the aid of the First corps.
The troops went through the town on
the run. They were eager to efface the
stain of Ohaucellorville upon their honor.
They came into position on the right of
the First corps, along the Carlisle road.
They had hardly got into line when Ewell
came down the hill with his entire corps
in four lines upon the extreme right flank
of the 11th, as it intending to work his
way into the town and cemetery. The
11th held its ground manfully, but gradu
ally the flank began tc bend. At the same
time. A. P. Hill moved soulh ot Rev Dr.
Schmucker’s house through a grove and
orchard, over the ground where Reynolds
fell, and attacked the First corps in flank.
It was an attempt on the part of the ene
my to fold up the wings ot Howard, gain
the town on both sides and have him im
prisoned.
Alter resisting the overpowering force
from one till four P. M., the order 'was
given to fall back.
Daring die three hours fighting a largo
number of prisoners were taken, but when
the order came for falling back, the regi
ments became exposed in tiling through
the town, and the enemy improved the
opportunity to taxe about fifteen hundred.
Col. Howard, a brother of the General,
was sent to urge Slocum to advance with
the 12th, He was then five miles distant.
W hen he arrived he took position on the
hill by Rock Run, the position he held
during the two succeeding days’ engage
ments. The Third corps, Sickles’, came
up and took position on the Emmettsburg
Pike. The enemy, evidently well pleased
with what they had done,and perhaps mis
trusting a trap, or that the entire army
was lying behind the cemetery, or perhaps
also waiting tor Longstreet and Lee, made
no attempt to push their advantage that
night. The town was occupied by the
pickets of both parties.
Messengers were sent to the corps which
had not yet arrived, and from all quarters
Union and rebel troops were hastening
Wednesday night—marching in the clear
light of the full moon toward that pleas
ant town tor one of the greatest conflicts
of modern times.
There Is no doubt that this engagement
was prematurely brought on by ben. Rey
nolds. Gen. Meade desired to find the
enemy, and compel Lee to make the at
tack. But perhaps, after all, it was the
very thing needed. The enemy was flushed
by the success. He was confident. He
had beaten us both at Fredericksburg and
Ohancelioreviile. He had done it in the
first conflict in Pennsylvania. He telt he
could always do it. A mistake. There
are tides in the affairs of men ana nations.
Stars are not always in the ascendant.—
But stimulated, encouraged, he lelt con
fident ot crushing the General who never
had been heard of except as a plain, mod
est, unassuming corps commander.
Alter the engagement on Wednesday,
Howard seized the cemetery as a pivotal
point, a strong position, which he was
confident of holding till the rapidly ad
vancing columns conld arrive—quickened
in spirit by hearing the ooom ol his can
non, and knowing that at last, alter a long,
toilsome march, they were up with the
enemy.
The Ist and 11th were there the 12th
came up at dark the 3d arrived in the
night, and the sth at ten o’clock on
Thursday forenoon, leaving Hanover at
lour o’clock and marching fourteen miles.
The 6th came up the Baltimore pike
Thursday afternoon, having made a forced
march from the extreme right of Meade’s
line of advance north.
During Wednesday evening, Howard
being in command of the three corps,
placed the 11th on the Baltimore pike, his
left reaching to the Taneytown road and
extending north of the Baltimore road to
the angle where the line turns east. The
Ist extended from the angle nearly to the
woods and hill near Rock creek. Oj the I
liili was the I2th, forming the extreme 1
right and reaching to the creek
General Meade arrived at eleven o’clock
from Taneytowa, and approved what had
been done. The Second corp*, when it
arrived, took position on the lelt of the
Eleventh, and the Third was sent slil fur
ther down to Round Top Hill.
When the Filth arrived on Thursday
forenoon it was held in poution west of
Rock creek, on the south side of the Balti
more pike, near the centre ot the entire
fores. 1c was about equidistant from toe
extreme points or the line, from the wood
ed hill on the right, from the cemetery at
the angle, and from Round Top on the
left. The leserve artillery, as it came in,
was also parked there, and the ammuni
tion. The cavalry was kept east ot Rock
creek on the Baltimore pike. On either
side of the road, in the wide fields, caval
ry has been appropriately called the wings
of the army. The wings were folded here
like a swallow’s, behind the body, to be
spread in an instant.
The Sixth Corps, when it came up on
Thursday afternoon, was also put in the
centre, on the ground where the Fifth had
been, which at that hour had been called
for on the left centre.
SECOND day’s BATTLE.
Thubsday, July 2.
On Thursday morning, when I reached
the ground the sth corps was crossing
from the H mover road to the Baltimore
pike, the men throwing themselves upon
the ground to gain a little rest and sleep
after their long and weary march.
There were signs of the approaching
storm. Few rebels could be seen; two
miles to the north single horsemen were
in view galloping furiously over the fields,
disappearing in groves, down the
road to the town, and again returning.—
There was a battery in position north of
the railroad, and as I looked narrowly at
an opening between two thick groves I
saw the glistening of bayonets, and a line
as if a column ot men was marching east
toward the thick forest on Rock creek.
It was surmised that they were to attack
our right upon the wooded hill by ad
vancing directly down Rock creek through
the forest. Prisoners captured said that
Ewell had sworn a terrible oath to turn
our flank if it took his last man. To
guard against such a flank movement Slo
cum threw up breastworks from tbe crest
of the bill down to Rock creek. Two
batteries were placed in position on hil
locks south of the turnpike to throw shells
up the creek.
Riding along the line south, I found,
joining the Doubleday’s division
I of the First corps lying in the oak grove.
Stannard’s Vermont brigade of nine
months’ men were there, tbe 12th, 13th,
14tb, 15th and 16th regiments, from the
mountains ever verdant.
The Second corps, Hancock's, was next
in line, then the Third, Sickles’, extending
down to Round Top hill. Sickles had ad
vanced two divisions into the meadow,
just east of the Emmettsburg road. On
his extreme left was the 9th Massachusetts
battery, (Japt. Bigelow close by him was
Phillips’ battery. Along the line the
sharpshooters were at it, over behind the
fences along the Emmettsburg road, and
the rebels behind the fences and in the
fields of waving grain in front of their
line.
Let us walk along the entire line before
the battle begins, and see the exact po
sitions of the troops, commencing at Rock
creek. On the extreme right are Slocum’s
12th corps, Gen. Lockwood’s division
holding the ground from Rock creek np
to the crest of the hill, Gen. Williams’ di
vision on the summit, and Gen. Geary’s
reaching down the western elope through
the woods to Wadsworth’s and Robinsou’s
divisions of the First corps, which ex
tended to the town.
Here, as 1 have said, the line makes
almost a right angle, and instead of walk
ing nearly west, you turn to the south.
Then in the cemetery and in the field
north of it, are the remnants of the Elev
enth corps—Gen. Ames’ division holding
the angle, Schurz and Steinwehr being in
the cemetery, with an apple orchard and
stone wall for protection. This is our
strong position. To take it in front is an
impossibility, but if Ewell makes ins oath
good to lake the wooded hill where Slo
cum is posted, Howard will be in an un
pleasant position, tor the hill is nearly as
high as the cemetery, and he will then be
subject to a lire in front, on his right
flank and in his rear. You admire this
position of Howard, for trom here he can
do what no other man can—he can reach
every foot of the enemy’s lines, from
Ewell, away up in the north-east,on Roek
creek, to A. P. Hill, across the town at
the seminary, to Longstreet,dowu in front
of Round Top.
Major Osborn is in command of thirty
four pieces of artillery here. He will
wield tremendous power. Lee knows it,
and you can see from the preparations
along the enemy’s lines, the planting of
batteries, that here will be a continuous
storm of shot and shell. Osborn will re
ceive a concentrated tire. Lee must si
lence the lips of these thirty-four before
he cau Lope to take and hold our weakest
position.
Grossing the Youngtown road, you
come to the Second corps, Hancock’s.
Here you are in fields. You see Hayes’
division on the right, Gibbon’s in the cen
tre, Caldwell’s on the left. Hayes is in a
grove ot ismall oaka, Gibbons and Cald
well are taking down the rails from the
fences, and are laying them up for a bar
ricade, and men with shovels are digging
a trench tor a rifla pit about four rods
west of the highest part of the ridge.—
There are the batteries behind, in position
to fire over the men in the trench—to
sweep the meadows and fields in front.—
This is our weakest part of the line —no
natural defense, simply a little smooth
swell of land, with a clear, unobstructed
open field in front; no obstruction, ex
cept tbe fences along the Emmettsburg
road, good musket shot distant.
Beyond Hancock is Sickles’ Third
corps, advanced torty rods Irom the ridge,
lying sheltered by a swell of land.
This is the outline. But inside of this
is the Filth corps, Sykes’, and the Sixth,
Sedgwick’s—moveable pieces, to be used
as supports, braces or blocks—timbers to
strengthen the weak parts of the building
when the storm comes on. You admire
tbe arrangement. In fifteen minutes
these two interior forces can be thrown to
the extreme right, to the extreme left, or
to the angle in the centre. Here also is
the reserve artillery, admirably parked, to
be brought into use in an instant; and
then behind, east of Ruck Creek, is Pleas
anton, with Gregg and Kilpatrick, to pre
vent any attack on the rear. A few
waves ot a flag from that small house on
the laceytown road will spread these
wings instantly, the right one lur a sweep
around Ewell, the letc one for a longer
stretch beyond Round Top. at .Long
street.
Tou are pleased at the concentration of
force its disposition. If Longstreet and
Hill combine to sweep over the slight
barriers which Hancock is throwing up,
these two blocks can be placed upon the
ridge to roll them back. If Ewell and
Hill creep down Rock creek under the
shade of the grand old oaks, they can be
placed with Slocum to make it still more
a hill of difficulty to the enemy.
the advance.
In the afternoon the 3d corps was or-
dered to advance across the fields and re- i
connoiter tbe enemy on the left. Some j
movements had been noticed in the wootie
beyond Steven>’ run. Sickles advanced
nearly a mile. Bigelow's battery was
taken lorward nearly to the Emmettsburg
road to cover the advance or the recoil.
It was the intention of G c n. Meade to
bring on the battle, but the enemy was
ready, and in reality had began to move
at tba time the 3d A battery
opened on Longstreet's extreme riatht.
Another and another. The lire ran alone
the entire Irom line up to Rev.
Scbmucker’s house. It was furious. I
was at the moment mar the cemetery. It
rained shot and snell. over the
marble slabs, shattering the iron fences,
disemboweling horses, tearing up the
graves. The air was tail ot wild, hideous
noises—the low buzz of round shot, whiz
zing ot the elongated ride bolts, scream
ing and screeching, the sharp stunning
explosions of shells—over head and all
aronnd.
There was a quick response. In three
minutes’ time the earth shook with the
tremendous concussion of two hundred
pieces of artillery. The skirmishers came
up and engaged the 3J corps, followed by
two lines of the enemy—thirty to forty
thousand men. Tney came with cheers—
yells, like Indians sounding a warwhoop.
The men who stood like granite blocks at
the apex of the triangle at Ghancellorville
against the impetuous dash of Jackson,
were not to be easily turned back. The}
engaged the entire mass of the enemy,
holding Longs reef in check till word
could be sent to Meade as to what might
be expected. While thus holding them,
a ciivisiun was detached by Longstreet
which moved upon Sickles’ left flank, to
get between him and the base or Round
Top hill.
Send up batteries and send up men,”
was Sickles’ request. They were close
upon Bigelow’s battery. It "was its first
experience under tire.
I want yon to hold on till I can get up
two batteries on the right,” said Major
McGilvray, in the artillery
on the left. Give them grape and can
nister, he added. Capt. Bigelow gave
them all he had, the last round, and com
menced on spherical case.
The rebels were desperate. Sickles was
pushed back. It was impossible ler him
to stay so tar in from. There was no
rout —no disorder, but a steady, backward
movement toward the ridge as orderly as
if at dress parade.
A rebel battery hastened up and unlim
bered close upon Bigelow, He gave them
a shot and they limbered up again. The
two batteries were not yet up, and the
Captain and his brave men would not
leave. The rebels rushed upon his guns.
He blew them Irom the muzzles, and tilled
the air with legs, heads and arms. Bull
they came with demoniac screams, climb
ing npon his limbers a.nu shooting bis
horses. Sergeant Dodge went down, kill
ed instantly; also Sergeant Gibson. Lip
man, Ferris and Nutting, three of his
cannoniers were gone, twenty two of his
men vvere wounded, and himself shot
tbrongh the side; also lour men missing,
yet he held on till McGilvray got hjj his
two batteries He brought oil five lim
bers and two of his pieces, dragging them
in part by Land I More than half his
horses were shot. The rebels siczed the
lour pieces with shouts, waved their flags
and came on for new triumphs.
But the two batteries, with McGilvray
there to superintend them, were doing
finely. The division which had come on
Sickles’ flank received an enfilading fire,
and was driven back. Bigelow’s gum
were recovered.
Now is apparent the beauty of Meade’s
plan. The Fifth corps started from the
position upon the ran, reached the ndge,
came up to the front and were ready to
give the Third a little rest.
Before the Fifth arrived the Second was
engaged, and Doubleday’s division of the
First. Hotter grew the fire. The rebels
became desperate. As there were no par
ticular signs of an attack in front of Slo
cum, two of his divisions were sent over.
Still the rebels pressed on. The reserve
artillery was called for, battery after bat
tery. The Sixth corps, which had just
arrived, all weary as they were, moved up
with alacrity and became supports.
From live P. M, till eight the struggle
went on. The rebels charged repeatedly
upon our lines, but were as olter. driven
back, and then our men improving their
opportunity would dash out ana gather up
prisoners—fifteen hundred were brought
in, offsetling our losses of yesterday. They
were all from Kill’s and Longstreet’s com
mands.
Where was Ewell? Ho was not in
sight. We found him suddenly, while the
lire on the left was hottest. Oar pickets
on the right discovered here and there a
rebel coming stealthily dawn Rock creek.
A scathing lire begun. Ewell, with the
remainder of the rebel army, was coming
down Rock creek, and was within musket
shot of our lines before discovered.
Looking down from his position on the
hill, Howard saw them two hundred feet
below him, a halt mile distant. The guns
among the tombs, which had been hading
death fur off to the southwest, were wheel
ed to the northeast, their muzzles de
pressed, and then with the utmost rapidi
ty from forty pieces there was hurled a
continuous storm of shells into the wood
ed ravine.
But Ewell pressed on. He Lad sworn
to break through and reach oar rear. His
men climbed the steep ascent. Slocum’s
skirmishers fell back from rock to rock
and from tree to tree. But gradually the
line of fire crept nearer the top. Another
battery now opened south of the turnpike
its line of fire being directly up the creek.
Hotter, fiercer grew the musketry, more
terrible the cannonades.
On the right the rebels rushed up to the
rifle pits. There were desperate hand to
hand encounters—thrusts with the bayo
net. Men nerved themselves for despe
rate efforts. It was the fury of tigers.
Foes became impaled on each others bayo
nets and fell to the ground together. But
the line had been so much weakened that
notwithstanding Slocum’s efforts his ex
treme right was pushed back a little from
the creek. The door was partly opened.
There was a little break, and one more
vigorous push on the part ot Ewell might
be fatal. Late at night both parties’ceas
ed their efforts and prepared for the morn
ing.
Longstreet had failed —Ewell had part
ly succeeded. The first thing tor tha
morning was to close the Rock creek door
and send Ewell back. The Sixth corps
was moved back to support the Twelfth
and the First. Two batteries were bro't
into position, on some rocky hillocks be
ween the Baltimore pike and the Taney
town road, their muziles pointing north,
straight up Rock creek.
Ewell, doubtless well pleased that he
had gained a foothold, kept his troops on
their arms in Slocum’s rifle pits. He was j
within forty rods of the Baltimore pike.
If he conid gam it then there would be
trouble in Meade’s camp. Ail night long
in the pale moonbeams shimmering through
the leafy brandies ot the forest the pickets
watched each other. Occasionally there
were rifle shots —some deadly ones on each
side, but the men on either side were too
wearied to keep awake over such trifling
matters and they reposed as sweetly upon
the ground which at daybreak was to be
their last earthly resting place as when in
childhood they were soothed to slumber
in a mother’s arms. All knew that at
daylight the terrible contest be re
newed, and that thousands would sleep in
death but as I passed along the lines at
nightfall I never saw men more cheerful
more determined. It was not an unthink
ing carelessness of the uncertainty or
rather, the certainty of the morrow, but
the calm resolution to yield their lives
cheerfully for their country. We who lie
down upon *'nr beds at home to quiet
-lumber know bin little ot the indurating
process which nun must undergo before
they can sleep so composedly with the
conviction on their minds that before
another night their souls will be beyond
the scenes of earth, friends—all that makes
life desirable will be shut forever from
them, and they launched npon the great
uncertainty and unknown.
In this terrible tight on the right Gen.
Green’s division of blocum corps sustained
the onset of Ewell till a brigade from the
First corps was moved down to assist.
TEE SECOND ATTACK ON TEE LEFT.
Ou the left, when the Fifth corps was
brought into actiou, Gen. Barnes was sent
with his division to the base of Round
Top hill.
The euemy fell upon Col. Vincent, with
the S.l Brigade, first. Their first attempt
to turn our flank nad driven the Third
corps L ac k from Its advanced reconnois
sance, but the vaior ut the Second corps
Lad checked their advance.
The second attempt was still u f oj the
fl nk, and was made with greater rasiu ess
than the first fhe Third was in rear of
the Filth, ready to support, if necessary,
their galiant comrades.
Die voice ot Col. Vincent ra n g clear
alu'Ve the din of preparation and the
tramp, tramp, tramp of the advancing
enemy. Don’t yield an inch” were his
words. He jumped npon a rock, waved
his sword, and at the moment received a
ball which shattered his thigh. Col. Rice
took command, and the men stood stead
ily up to the terrible work, taking delib
erate aim.
General Barnes was cool and as firm as
the massive boulders of granite around
him. Nearer came the rebels—no longer
marching, but running for a bayonet
charge. General Barnes did not run. His
men did not. They stood. They met the
shuck. The lines mingled. There was a
contused mass of men. Swords were
swinging in air. There were pistol shots,
market shots, bursting shells from the
rebel batteries, tornadoes of grape and
canister from our own. There were cuts,
thrusts, explosions, flashes, clouds of
smoke, yells, curses, groans, hurrahs—an
infernal uproar—men falling, heads blown
off, arms and legs tossed into the air—a
horrid, indescribable scene confusion,
carnage, death!
It is terrible to think of it; horrible to
behold, but it is the stern necessity. So
justice comes through suffering—so peace,
pure, gentle, beautiiul, holy, through the
atonement for crime.
While this was going on in Barnes’ di
vision, General Ayers’ division came in
just in time to save the First from being
pushed back, or trampled down by the
still advancing enemy. General Ayers’
division has the two brigades of regulars,
those who all day long hung to the hollow
in tront of Fredericksburg, and refused
to retire even when their ammunition was
gone, and all hope of winning the heights
had departed.
As they came in fresh troops came up
for Longstreet, and again the contest went
on —the rolls of musketry like the roaring
of the wind through a forest—the thunder
ot the cannonade incessant, reverberating
far away along the mountain passes.
While all this was taking place in the
field and pastures, the Fourth and Fifth
brigades ot the Pennsylvania Reserves,
commanded by Gen. Crawford, were sent
by Gen. Meade to clear the enemy from
Round Top hill, which they had secured
in their desperate onset. It is exceedingly
rocky and covered with scrub oak. The
Buck tails led the charge. Col. Taylor,
leaulng them, was shot, but they moved
on, gained the summit, drove the rebels,
poured over the other side and swept down
upou the flank of the forces attacking
Baines and Ayers at the base. Hazlitt’s
battery, by almost superhuman effort, was
dregged, or lifted over the rocks to the
top and as the darkness came on, lighted
up its tires, hurling death upon the masses
below.
We are not to forget that while this is
taking place an hundred pieces of artillery
along the ridge reaching up to thy ceme
tery are hurling shells and bolts here and
there upon the straggling infantry and
upon the rebel batteries across the fields,
and that from beneath those distant trees
beyond the little gurgling brook that
winds through the meadows there is an
answer lor every shot, a cannonade kept
up, till Longstreet’s shattered columns
have fallen back, discomfited, into the
woods from whence they came. Confi
dence in themselves and confidence in their
leaders were the marked features in the
morale ot the army that night. They had
no tear for the result of the morrow.
THIRD DAY’S BATTLE.
Feioav, July 3.
Boom! boom! Two guns, deep and
heavy, at four o’clock. It was a cloudy,
sultry morning. The clouds hung thick
and heavy, and came down low upon the
hills. Two more, and then more rapidly
than the lick of a pendulum, came the
concussions. The cemetery was hid from
sight by the thick sulphurous folds rolling
over and over, unfolding and expanding.
There were flashes irotn two hillocks
south of the turnpike, flashes in the woods
along Kock creek. The dour which had
been opened against Geary last night was
to be closed, and this was the beginning
of the effort.
Without cessation, increasing in torce
and intensity, was the cannonade, break
ing the stillness of the morning and drown
ing all other sounds.
There were a lew musket shots in the
woods upon the hill from Che pickets in
advance. Beneath the trees were biocum’s
lines, preparing to regain what had been
lost during their '.absence. It was seven
o’clock beiore he was ready to make the
attempt to close the door. The men
moved up slowly, but determinedly. The
rebels were in the pits and a lunous ure
began. A thin veil ot smoke rose above
the trees and floated away before the
morning breeze. More rapid was the fire
of musktry, more terrific the cannonade.
E well was evidently determined not to be
driven back. He held on with dogged
pertinacity. But in vain his oath, in vain
his effort. The door was closed, the rifla
pits regained. Ewell was driven hack
inch by inch, up Rock creek, and the line
was intact.
CAVALRY OPERATIONS.
A dragoon came dashing in from the
Bonaughton road, with the
that tbe rebel cavalry was coming down
upon the turnpike to capture our trains.
Generals Pleas an ton’s compliments to Gen
erals Gregg and Kilpatrick. He desires
General Gregg to cneck Stuart on the
right and protect the trains. He also de
sires Kilpatrick to sweep down beyond
Roucd Top and leel of the enemy in the
direction of Pairheid Gap. “That’s good,
first rate,” is Kilpatrick’s exclamation.—
He'rubs his hands with satisfaction as you
have seen children.at unexpected pleasure.
His eyes gleam. His face lights with
smiles. His division is close by, and in
live micates you see his long column of
horsemen defiling along Rock creek, as
cending the bank, sweeping over the fielc.B
and disappearing in the woods beyond
Round Top.
A hair hour passes, and you see far
down toward the hills of the Cacoctin,
the pillars of smoke rising above the for-
esta, and you here the sullen roar from bis
light battery. He is upon Longstreet’s
flank, pushing on, and evidently troubling
that General.
Gregg bas gone north, and is at it with
Stuart. Riding up the Bonanghtou road
we find him in position, sending shells
over a long stretch of field into the rebel
column, just visible in the edge of distant
forests. Stuart replies and retires. He
would like to get at that long line of wag
ons coming in, but he will be foiled in
every attempt. Later in the day he en
deavors to out round Pleasanton at the
Two Taverns, but is thrust back uncere
moniously.
TEE LAST or. AND ATTACK.
I must pass over the two attempts of
the enemy on the left flank. Ido not at
tempt to give a history of the three day’s
engagements, but simply an outline. Twice
during the forenoon of Friday there were
attacks which were successfully repulsed.
I could hear at times tar off to the north
a dull report of artillery, and could see
little handfuls of smoke in the air in the
direction of Carlisle. It was not Grgg,
neither Kilpatrick nor Buford, for they
were otherwhere. Who then i Couch
or Smith, coming down on Lee’s flank
What he has to do must be done quickly.
He will have anew foe at hand to-morrow.
There arc new 6 g ,s fme coming strug
gle—ammunition going up to the batteries,
boxes of spherical case shells, grape and
canister.
You see movements along the enemy’s
lines—troops taking positions south of
Dr. Scbmncher’s. The forenoon passes.
Between one and bait past one, a rebel
battery north of the seminary fires a gun,
and then ail along the rebel line, from the
right to the left, the rebel batteries pour
a concentrated fire upon Howard’s posi
tion. The lines cover an hundred and
eighty degrees of the circle.
TEEIR INTENTION.
Their intention is well understood—to
silence Howard’s batteries because they
enfilade the slacking force, ready to
move over the fields toward the centre
our weakest point. If they can give to
the living a quiet as profound as that ot
the sleepers beneath the ground molderir g
to dost, then they may hope to break
through the thin line of men at the sec
ond corps.
But Howard is not a man to be kept
silent at such a time without especial
cause. It rains, hails, pours upon him.—
His battery horses are knocked to pieces,
the tombstones are knocked over, iron
railings torn, shrubs and trees cut down,
uere and there a limb damaged, but he is
not silenced, He keeps at it coolly and
spiritedly.
Not only Howard’s, but all the batteries
along the lines of both armies are in full
play.
HEADQUARTERS A HOT PLACE.
The rebels have evidently discovered
that the American flag floating over the
cottage on the Taneytown road is the
headquarters’ flag. Gen. Meade is there,
surrounded by his staff, A hundred
horses are standing in the dooryard, teth~
ered to tie palings or nibbling the grass
by the roadside. Engineers are down on
their knees, examining maps. Wearied
correspondents are making notes beneath
the shadow of the gable. There is an
ominous silence all along the lines. It be
gins—the internal din and uproar. A
shell screamed over the house startling
those who were there. Another—a third
—a half dozen—twenty—over the house
—through it—into the yard—burying
themselves in the earth—exploding in the
air—tearing horses to pieces—knocking
in the sides of the building. Gen. Meade
quietly remarked that they had better ad
journ to the barn, but the barn was
equally exposed, borne officers walked
hastily into the grove near at baud. Some
went down cellar with a couple of corres
pondents. One correspondent mounted
his horse with commendable alacrity and
galloped down the road at a tremendous
rate, running the gauntlet of lire for a half
mile.
I remember the fire at Antietam and at
Fredericksburg, but never have I beard
such a roar ot field artillery—three hun
dred guns firing with the utmost rapidity
—the rebels to disable and silence ours,
while their infantry moved across the
fi-lds to attack our centre. They had
tried the right and the left, had Tailed, and
now with all energy, power, desperation
and madne s they were to attempt our
weakest position.
THE MOVEMENT.
Howard allowed them to think that
they had silenced him. He slackened fire
to allow his guns to cool. The time had
come for Lee to make his last grand ef
fort.
Stand then by the cemetery and look
south along the lines. Across the mead
ows, emerging from the woods, is a long
line of skirmishers in doable ranks.
Behind you see tbe first attacking force
and then the second attacking force. The
lines are long and straight. They march
excellently. The ranks bend over a hil
lock, dip into a hollow, but are unbroken.
The open field is a half mile wide. Solid
shot plow through them. Shells make
great gaps. Men toss their armc wildly
and fail headlong, but the movement is
still on. The movement mainly is against
the Second, Third and Fifth corps. Hill,
Longstreet and Anderson’s reserves are
expected to be there—forty thousand
men.
The Second oorpa is like a thin blue
ribbon —a single line. The men are kneel
ing in the rifle pits—not in reverent acta
of worship, but to shelter themselves
from the fire of the foe. Forty pieces of
cannon cut and gash the line as it comes
on. It does not Neither does
the line of men in blue.
General Gibbon —in command of the
Second, now that Hancock is wounded—
walks composedly along the ranks. “Hold
your fire, boys—they are not near enough
yet,” Is his command. Still nearer, and
then with bayonets at the charge, they
sweep up to the rifle pits, A lino of fire
flashes suddenly from the ranks of the
Second. Scores, hundreds of rebels go
down, but they do not falter. They
charge over the pits. Gibbon orders his
men to fall back to the rear of the bat
teries. It is done, without confusion, to
allow the artillery the privilege of using
grape. Still on, up to the muzzles of’ the
guns. They are blown away —mangled,
torn, piled in heaps.
They move to their right. The flank fa
perhaps fifteen rods distant from Howard.
The time has cou.e for a decisive blow.
Forty pieces ot artillery pour grape and
can nis ter into the ranks. They melt away.
You cannot burn a sfraw in a candle flame
with greater rapidity, Their courage, de
termination, bragadocio and bravery do
not triumph. They flee. The plain is a
mass of discomfitted rebels. The ground
is thick with dead. They lie thick as fal
len leaves of autumn.
TAXIS’© PRISONERS.
The enemy was repulsed—cow was the
time for action. Webb’s brigade, without
waiting for orders, dashed into the flying
mass and came back with eight hundred
prisoners. Stannard’s brigade of nine
months’ Green Mountain boys, their uni
forms clean and new, improved the op
portunity and took as ruaoy more.
The Massachusetts lorn, reduced to two
score of men, rushed imo the melee and
came back with four stand of colors.—
Hall’s brigade, including rbe 19:h and
20th Massachusetts, the 7 h Michigan and
a Pennsylvania regiment, captured eleven
colors.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033123/1864-06-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.189,0.513,0.402,0.435,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>On the Lett at Gettysburg.
BY H. L. ABBEY.
Soldier of the picket guard,
Keeping midnight watch and ward,
While a mighty nation sleeps:
On your dark, beleagured steeps—
On the heights at Fredericksburg—
Tell ns how at Gettysburg,
On the left at Gettysburg.
a'or stayed disaster;
When the raiding Bebel crew,
Hurled upon our weary few
Columns dense, and vaster,
Ten to one. than they who stood,
For a grateful nation's good,
On the left, at Gettysburg.
Beating back disaster,
•‘Deeds befit a soldier best,
We were ot the van who pressed
First to meet the braggart Lee.
With his tattered chivalry,
In their great invasion.
On they came, a hungry pack,
Watching at their leader's back.
For a town to burn and sack—
Deeming such occasion
Nobler than a testing fight;
Then they fell up n our right.
Knowing well our force wat small
Seamed our ranks with cannon ball,
Which we paid them later.
Though, before their fierce attack,
Bight and centre both fell back,
Scarce three hundred Ulster men.
Linked with brawny sous i Penn,
Ail that day at Gettysburg-
On tne left at Gettysburg—
Held at bay the traitor.
Weary with the march and heat,
Dead and wounded ut our feet.
Battle round us like a sea,
Stood we earning victory;
While our dauntless manner
Bought respect, the coin of worth—
Yet they sent their cohorts forth.
Round their lying banner:
Charging on us, up they tot',
Eaters ofthe sacred soil,
Wavering at each volley—
Till at last they turn with fear,
Losing relish for our cheer:
Thus we made their charges dear,
Ou the ridge at Gettysburg-
On the left ar Gettysburg,
Taught them of their folly.
“Storm of thunder broke and fell,
hizzing shot and bursting shell;
While in Gettysburg each bell
Clashed its frightened clangor.
O'er us moaned the sudden bull,
Now our comrade heroes fall
Loud the drummers’ tattoos beat,
Folds ttie smoke a winding sheet,
Or in plumes for many a bier,
And the grim guns tar and near,
Flash their iron auger.
A captain down the t raitor ranks,
Blood upon bis horse's flanks.
Rides, and cheers eacli man on;
Still we brush them off like straws,
Feeling now a noble cause
Worth a hundred cannon.
In the night relief was born,
Re enforcements with the morn,
Poured in fast, and faster.
Then we beat the vipers forth.
From the gateway ot the North,
Vile white trash and master-
But that dnv at Gettysburg,
On the left at Gettysburg
Valor stayed disaster.”
Ho I watcher of our destiny.
Tell us yet if Liberty,
On the Nation's forehead
Sets her crown, no lunger scoffed
By the blazoned curse, that oft
Made her name abhorred.
If the stain be cleansed away,
Not in vain upon that day,
On the left at Gettysburg.
Fought our sons and br there.
If the curse must still remain.
Vain their fight, our longing vain;
And the tears of mothers
Will not find a balm to soothe
Marsh never will be smooth.
Torn with waves of sorrow
But the right shall rule, we know,
Lo! the morning splendors glow
Of the golden morrow.
Mothers tears ate pearls, that buy
Many a nation’s liberty,
Making freedom vaster
Pray for those who vainl;. weep
For their darling sons, who sleep
Where they tell at Gettysburg,
On the left at Gettysburg,
Beating back disaster.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022770/1863-07-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.257,0.581,0.532,0.577,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Rebels in full Retreat
FEDERAL CAVALRY IN PUR
SUIT.
Capture of Let's Pon too* Bridge at T Vil
liamrpcrt The Potomac Swollen by
Rains and Unfordable.
Conflicting Reports of the Capture and
Death of the Rebel Generals Longstreet
and Hill.
The Flight of Bragg—He Destroys Bridges
to Delay the Federal Ad ranee—Our Cav
alry Press him t/ose—The Rebels Demor
alised—Deserters Flocking to the Federal
Lines.
GREAT FALL IX GOLD!
We are under a thousand obligations to
W. T. Say ward, Esq., of Port Ludlow, for an
S. F. Bulletin of the 7th, from which we ex
tract the following most exciting news. It is
the death-blow to rebellion. The news has
of late, contrary to custom, improved the
ntoro we got of it. Usually, we have had the
best version first, then came gradually the
truth, abating from its excellence, until what
was heralded as a victory turned out to be a
drawn buttle, or eveu a defeat. 13ut this time
we have been given the good wine last. Ev
ery additional flash of light upon the fields
about Gettysburg, soaked with the blood of
three day's terrible fighting, shows clearer
than before the extent of Lee's defeat, the
completeness of Meade's victory. The most
lusty wishes fathered no such bravo thought
as this. The rebel raid is turned into a
flight. The invasion that thicatencd Phila
delphia, Baltimore and Washington is con
verted into a run for life towards Virginia
again, leaving their dead unburied, their
wounded in our hands, prisoners by the thou
sand and cannon and battle-flags by the hun
dreds, as tiophies.
Washington, July 5.—-Gen. French' has
captured the pontoon bridge from the enemy
at Williamsport. The receat rains have
swollen the Potomac, thus rendering the river
unfordable; an important fact, in view of
the present military operations.
Gen. Sickles arrived here to-day. His left
leg has been amputated, but it is thought he
will recover.
Reports concerning the death and capture
of Longttreet and A. P. Hill are conflicting.
The following is the latest official dispatch:
Headquarters, Army of the Potomac. July
5—8:80 A. M.— To Gen. Halleck—The ene
my retired under cover of the night and a
heavy rain, in the direction of Fairfield and
Bashtown. Our cavalry are in pursuit. I
cannot give details. Our captures in prison
ers, colors and arms are large. Upwards of
2tfl battle flags will be turned in from one
corps. My wounded and those of the enemy
are in our hands. MEADE.
Philadelphia, July 5.—A gentleman who
lives on the road to Fayettcville, 15 miles
from Gettysburg, who arrived here to-day,
says at 4 o'clock yeaterday afternoon he heard
heavy firing, which continued till nearly dark.
This mornrng at an early hour it again com
menced, and continued till 7 o'clock, but not
nearly so heavy as the night before. When
he left, at 9 o'clock, the firing had not been
renewed, but sounded in the direction of
Gettysburg.
Baltimore, July 5.—A person who arrived
this morning from the field at Gettysburg,
having left there yesterday afternoon, says the
enemy was then believed to be retreating on
the Chambersburg turnpike and the adjacent
roads, having left one strong corps posted in
a defensive position half a mile or mora be
yond Gettysburg, presenting a heavy battle
line to oppiose our pursuit and protect their
retreating columns. This position of theirs
is so strong that it gt.ve opportunities for an
enfilading artillery fire on the attacking col
umns, that an attack on the front seemed
hardly advisable, and up to Saturday, noon
no attack had been made. It is not impossi
sible, however, tbat the flank of this line
could bo turned. The column* of the enemy's
army can be distinctly seen retreating. Their
OLYMPIA, WASHINGTON TERRITORY, SATURDAY MORNING, JULY 18, 1863.
wagon teams also are being hurried off as
fast as possible.
Harrisburg, July 6, a. m. -—Nothing is
known as to the exact situation. Lee is
probably trying to retreat by both routes. It
is supposed that he docs not know of the de
struction of his pontoon bridges.
The position of tho rebel army last aight,
was with the left near Hunterstown, ani ths
right across the Emmetsburg road, thus form
ing a semicircle around Gettysburg, Gtn.
Meads operates from the centre. Gen. Leo
da an are of a circle.
Cincinnati, July 6.—Gen. Burnside has
received the following, dated Washington,
July 4 After three days sanguinary battles
at Get'ysbtfrg, Gen. Meade has defeated Gen.
Lee who is now in full retreat.
E. M. Bt anton. Sec. War.
Chicago, July 6.—A despatch from Talla
homa the 4th, says McCook's corps occupied
Winchester to-day, his pickets extending to
the foot of the mountains. Thomas's corps
occupy Dechard, his advance being up to
Cowan, at the opening of the tunnel. The
enemy's flight from Tullahoma was rapid.
They destroyed all the bridges on Elk river,
thus delaying the Federal pursuit. Several
corps pressed ahead, however, crossing on
pontoons last night, and are now crowding
the enemy up the mountain road. Bragg'»
army is terribly demoralized, deserters com
ing in by scores, who say the mountains arc
full of men afreid to show themselves, not
knowing what may befall them, yet resolved
to fight no more.
New York, July 6.—Gold this morning
was 1.38.
We Capture IS,OOO Prisoners and 118
Pieces Artillery
Report that Lee had asked a Suspension of
of Hostilities to bury his Dead, but that
Meade refused, saying he would only be
satisfied with an Unconditional Surrender!
50,000 REBELS KILLED MD Wdll)
Iff hold the Mountain Passes and Cut Off'
The Rebels Seek the Potomac—Preparations
to Intercept them there—Fears lest their
Advance may have already Crossed the
River.
Ihe Rebels recapture Bra shear City, La.—
Federal Loss 1,000 Men and 18 Pieces of
Artillery—Our Out pouts fall buck to But'
Icr's Station, 20 miles from New Orleans
—that City safe!
BOMBARDMENT OF PORT HUDSON
Chicago, July 6.—Special despatches re
ceived lute last night assert that Lee's retreat
is competely cut off; that Meade captured
18,000 prisoners and 118 peices of cannon
that Lee asked a suspension of hostillities for
the purpose of burviog his dead Aud curing
for the wounded. Mead replied lint he
could be satisfied only with an uncondition
al surrender. I send this only as a report,
not vouching for its correctness.
New Orlenns letters, dated June 26th, tays
tlmt Brashear City WHS captured by the reb
els on that day with all the troops, artillery,
such that our loss wa? 1,000 men including a
camp ot 600 convalescents and 18 or 20
pieces of heavy calibre. Our r.iitposts had
fallen back to butler's station, 20 mili'B from
New Orleans, 'l'liecoriespondeut says that
as fur as New Orleans city was concerned, it
was secure. The guns of the fleet command
tho city, and Gen. Emery lias disposed his
command so that it can effectually defend
every part.
From Port Hudson there is nothing of im
portance. The bombardment continues.—
Another assault was expected on the 27th of
June.
Indianapolis, July s.—Dispatches hare
been received at the Executive office, from
Oen. Boyle of Louisville, calling for all troops
immediately that Indiana CHII SPHRE. The
facts appear to be tbat Morgan, at the head
of 4,000 cavalry, had crossed Cumberland
river, near Somerset, on the 3d of July, and
was attempting to Btrike the Nashville and
Loataville Railroad somewhere in Kentucky,
and* then march upou Louisville. Great
cousternation is said to exist in the butter
city. All aide bodied men are preparing for
defense. Two regiments ntul oue lattery
were sent from bei'e, and other troops are to
follow soon.
Memphis, July 3.—A letter written by an
officer of Gen. Ousterlmub' command says
that the position of Johnston's forces is better
now than at any pr«>cHiing datu. Skirmishes
between his «ncurrence. Our loss in prisoners during the
last ten days, captured by Johnston'a men,
was about 300.
New York, July 6.—-The Timet says that
the contents of Jeff. Davis* despatches whioh
were captured are a peremptory order to Lee
to withdraw from Pennsylvania, aaaigning as
the reason that his position was too haaard
ous, aud that the condition of Richmond ia too
defenseless to warrant hia remaining any
longer. He also refuses Lee's request to al
low Beauregard to reinforce him, and orders
Lee south of the Potomac forthwith.
The Timtt' Gettysburg dispatch confirms
reports that Meade had almost annihilated
the rebels, who left nearly SO,OOO killed and
wounded on the ground.
SECOXD DISPATCH.
the Rebels an that side,
CONTINUED.
Hancock's corps, which defended the cen
tre, was thanked by Meade in the name of
the army and of the countnr.
OB Friday evening, July 84, Sixth and
Seventh corps attacked the enemy's right,
gaining a good deal of ground. Our cavalry
to-day is playing on ths rebel flank and rear.
Harnsburg dispatch to the Htrm'i, da*
ted July 4th, saysr that Qovsrnor Curtin had
received a dispatch from Hanovpr, stating
that 80,600 rebels and over 100 cannon were
>tsktq, and that Gen. Fleasanton occupied
the Aduntaln pass neft ChaiMbwsbnrg, cut
ting off the retreat of the enemy. We hold
all the mountain passes uid have formed a
junction with the militia, so as almost to sur
round the enemy. It is reported that a re
bel column on the Virginia side of the Poto
mac was unable to reinforce Lee on account
of the high state of the water.
New York, July 6.—Paroled prisoners say
that the rebels captured 3,000 of our troops.
Headquarters Army of the Potomac, July
sth.—The rclel Generals Kemper and John
ston were killed, and Ponder was wounded.
Gen. Farnsworth (Federal) waa killed, But*
terfield's wound was severe but not serious.
There is no truth in the reported of Long
street or Hill.
Gen. Meade has issued a congratulatory
address to the army, saying:
The enemy baffled and defeated, has with
drawn from the contest. Our task is not yet
accomplished. The commanding General
look* to the army for greater efforts to drive
the enemy from our soil.
Gettysburg, July s.—The rebels retreated
towards the Potomac. The rebel pontoon
bridge at Dam No. 5 has been destroyed by
our cavalry. Our cavalry has gone to Wil
liamsport to destroy bridges there.
Other preparations are progressing to in
tercept Lee's passage of the v Potomac. Our
army is in motion. It ig feared that Lee's
advance reached Williamsport in time to
cross unopposed. Lee yesterday paroled
about 2,000 Federal prisoners.
DETAILS DESCRIPTON OF BATTLE
NEAR GETTYSBURG.
Chicago. July G.—Tho following is
condensed from Saturday's New York
Herald. The battle of 'Thursday (J uly
2) lasted all day. More or less picket
firing bad taken place on tbe left,
which became pretty sharp batween 2
and BP. M. Some movements were
in progress behind this tire, aud to de
velop these, Sickles was ordered to ad
vance with the whole of the 3d Corps.
Under cover of fito trom 8 brass pieces
in a battery on the open field, the corps
went forward in line of battle. Theu
the enemy's artillery, so long silent,
began on tho left ut our pieces in the
held. In turn our pieces on Cemetery
llill opened on those of tho enemy
in the field. Other batteries of the ene
my nearer our centre fired on those on
Cemetery Hill, and so it went around,
until our guns on the northern face of
the hill engaged the enemy's batteries
two miles across tho country, on our
right. Meantime the musketry fire on
our left seemed to become every mo
ment more fierce. Already the Third
corps had once beeu driven in disorder
from the ground it had won, but, ral
lied by General Sickle*, in person, it
had again gone forward, now held its
place with desperate ferocity against a
very heavy force. This advance on our
left" had developed that the enemy's
force was in reality massed here, and
when the Third corps took the initia
tive it only precipitated the attempt
on the part of the enemy, which mignt
otherwise come when wo were not so
well prepared to receive it Between
5 and 6 o'clock the Third corps having
withstood, with frightful lon, many
successive charges ot the enemy's in
fantry of many times their nnmbera,
began to show signs of weakness, and
the Fifth corps was ordered to change
in relief of them, wbich tbey did with
n will, and forced the euemy back a
mile aud a half, taking many prison
ers.
Persons who never witnessed a battle
can have no oouception of the gran*
dear of the scene. The air was per
fectly thick with bursting shells, -and
the firinjrof musketry filled the spsce
with bullets like hailstones in a sum
mer show or, scattering death and de
struction on every side. This was un
doubtedly the fiercest conflict of the
war. The loss on both sides must be
terrible. The enemy were most des
perate in their attacks. Brigade after
brigade were marched up against Gens.
Sickles and Hancock's positions, in
the most demoniac futy, and having
delivered their fire their strength being
tpent, would fall down to Ist another
line march over them, and petfbrm the
same maneuver, while they would de
ploy and recruit for a repetition of
the same role. This advance devel
oped still further the intention of the
enemy, whioh was to get around oor
left flank, and so get at the Emmet*-
burg road, and perhaps at our ammuni
tion wagons near it.
LATER,
As the division of regulars and
Griffin's division of the Fifth corps
went forward, and before the fire that
swept from their left down the line and
on tne right, a brigade of the division
of regulars was wheeled so as to face
that way. No sooner had it done ao
than a fire in front opened, which then
owe in the rear of the right brigade
and threw it into some confusion; but
enemy before it until it had taken a
position preiriously occupied by one of
the enemy's batteries. Here a fire
was concentrated on these two divisions
from batteries further to the roar, and
at the same time the enemy was re
ported on their left At once the line
was ordered to retiro.
It went back steadily to the crest of tbe
hill, half an bour before sunset. Tbe same
final attempt with wbich the rebels usually
endeavor to close up their great engagements
—an attempt which certainly has in the larger
number of instances been crowned with suc
cess—here, however, met a different fate.
Two divisions, wbich proved to be Anderson's
and McLean's of Longstreet's corps, were
formed for this attempt, and came forward in
magnificent style. They had a difficult ground
to cross, but onward they came over rocks
and through low woods, until within fair dis
tance, when they made a rush with yells.
They did not keep their line very even, but
were scarcely less impetuous as a mass than
they would have been in line. Tbey killed
our men on the crest ot the bill and over tbe
crest, and our men were even driven well
down on the other side. But these rallied on
thoae that had held their places, and bullets
were hurled into the rebel mass by vollevs.
Checked, broken and beaten back by this
one Titanic effort of the Fiflh Corps, tun at
tacking column scattered down the hill, and
the battle was over on the left with the ene
my completely beaten.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020712/1863-07-14/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.635,0.863,0.188,0.204,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE BATTLE OF GETTYSBUBG, PA.
From all-the accounts we can gather! it anneai
"tbat a exeat and hlnodv haltl lonV r hi.t.-..n
tr u iuv
Confrderate army under Gen. Lee, and the Yankee
J .army under Gen. Meade, at Gettysburg, Pa.' The
ngntmg commenced on Wedcesd
sy. July 1st. aud con-
"Boed till Saturday evening the 4ih. For the first two
days, it seems thAt our forces whipped the enemy and
captured a number of prisoners, but at the close of
the four days' fighting, Gen. Lee fell back to Ilageis
town to prevent the enemy from getting in his rear and
catting off his communications.
Below we giv all the news that we think reliable,
and the reader can form his own conclusions as to the
condition of affairs:
The following unofficial despatch from the tele
graphic superintendent at MartinsLurg was re
ceived at the War Department:
Maetinsiiurg, Va., July 8.
u non. J. ji. Hctldon, Scv'y of ar
From all reports, we gained a decided and tell
ing advantage over the enemy at Gettysburg on
Wednesday and Thursday, July 1st and 2d.
On Fridav we chaTced his works, and took thorn
.but were unable to hold f hem. nnd ftdl JifiMr in
wards Hagerstown.
Kvcrything'is so indefinite that it is impossible
to form a correct idea of the fight.
Four, thousand prisoners are now at Williams
port, on thejrwey to Richmond. Mauy of hosei
who rere slightly wounded were paroled to-day.
Another;, dispatch from Winchester, Va., eays:
The Confederate General Archer. was. captured
by the enemy.
Generals Heth, Pender, Hood, Anderson, Scales,
Pettigrew and Semmes, aro certainly wounded,
generals Barksdale, AFmistead, Garnett and Kem
per are killed all Confederates. At least fifty
field officers have been wounded.
The Yankee General Grabam
our hands.
ts a prisoner in
Gen. Stuart, while on a raid near to W?ashiog
ton, captured one hundred and ninety wagons and
twelve hundred mules.'
The Yankee cavalry attacked our ambulance
train near Greencastle on Sunday, but they were
driven off by Gen. Imboden.
The Yankee cavalry, infantry and artillery at
tacked our trains at Williamsport yesterday even
ing, and were repulsed, after two hours' fighting,
by Gen. Jones.
Gen. Fitz Lec is said to have come up withhe
enemy, while they were attacking our wagons near
S.harpsburg, yesterday evening, and drove them
off capturing two hundred prisoners. We have
lost some one hundred wagons by capture.
The Pennsylvania people are calling for peace.
Richmond, July .10. A dispatch dated Mar
tinsburg, July 9th, says: We had a heavy caval
ry fight yesterday. We drove the enemy seven
miles, capturing a number, of prisoners. Our ar
my is quiet at Hagerstown.
We suppose the cavalry fight spoken of took
place at Williamsport.
Richmond, July 10. All the papers. of this morning
give more cheering accounts from our army in Mary
land. The uneasiness prevailing yesterday has given
place to a feeling Of confidence in the ability of Gen.
Lee to resume the offensive.' The Martinsburg corres
pondent of the Dispatch, under date of the 5th, says
all the information relative to the bailie of Gettysburg
received through was brought by Hawks. Ewell's
coi'ps left Gettysburg on Saturday morning.. He says
our loss tn the first two-days was not very great. On
fySj4ally io Piekett's Division:
Gen, Trimble lost a leg-and Hood an arm
A wounded, ffictr who arrived in Richmond yester
dayt Bftys oar army fell back with; the greatest order
and, deliberation; there wft3 no demoralization. It is
generally understood that the falling back was caused
by the difficulty in obta'rtring supplies through so long
a line of communication. The. men are in fine spirits
aad'reaily for another .fight'.
Richmond, July IlNo news from Maryland to-day.
AH :quit here.. t
ck NORTHER .ACCOUNTS."
PThe Raltimof' GajeV the 7tb inst., sayst
"What we really' fcnow' as regard the battle before
Gettysburg amounts iiimpljr id; thisr .TCbe -Confederates
were attacked 4n Wednesday, bf lwa army
cerps, which they drp?fi back wltlt reat slaughter,
captutipg many fprisonraL OorTItrs4ay after
noon the vihole VertL:px'cB'jkfo$ke bjthe
Confederates, and afteaf iangntnaiy aflict the
Copfedcrates were repulsed; ?On Fridjjhe Rattle
was renewed and lasted the entire day, resulting ia
a more signal repulse of the Confederates than
that of the previous day i
The loss was extraordiDarilj .sercrtj oti both
sid.es. The Federal loss In general officer U be
yond all precedent. -r -V-'- i -On
Saturday night Gen. Lee fell back towards
the mountains, and what followed einee is almost
wholly conjecture, bat it is admitted ihat Lee
holds the passes in South Jlountaio and to will
fight or retire as circumstances may dictate'.
w The Pontoon Bridges at Williamsport bate not
been destroyed.
Later.
received.
The Philadelphia Inquirer of 8th has been
A dispatch dated Harrisbnrg, July 7th, 9 o'eldtk p.
m., says a big fight was going on at WillUmfppri.
The whole rebel army appears to be on the bank or the
river, and is no dqubt making a desperate fight-
The Inquirer "says there is no newi froca-tbe army of
special importance. Meade was eloaely watching his
discomfitted but wily antagonist, and -nn'engagement
was expected in a day or two. The Inquirer claims
3,000 prisoners, besides the wounded left behind, and
says thesslaughter among Confederate Generalj and
officers wasreat." r.
r The Federal loss could riot be less tlran fifteen, and
may rWaeta twenty thousand. The Inquirer mjs thAt
the -worst-feature of the disaster is that "to many Fed
eral officers, the most skilled and efficient, are either
killed or incapitated. Butterfield is much worse than
expected injured internally.
FIGHTING AT JACKSON.
Jackson, July 10. An .attack on this place
by the Yankees under Grant has begun. Oar
batteries opened on the Federals finely. The
enemy is evidently in heavy force. A heavy in
fantry and artillery skirmish is going on. The
enemy is shelling the city and has killed several
soldiers and citizens. No general engagement has
taken place yet. Our tropps are in excellent
spirits, and if the enemy makes a general attack
it is believed our success will bo certain, .hvery
man is at his post.
Heavy skirmishing continues on. the Lunton
Road. The enemy is slowly working around our
left. The attack may not become general before
the morning, though their troops are still pressing
forward." IJut few men have been lost on our side
yet. The enemy must be suffering for water as
aU tjje ciscrns amj ponJj, Ua5 l,cen destroyed.
The Thermometer is at V'Z.
Jackson, July 10, 6 p. m. Artillery firings has
cetased. The enemy's sharpshooters, and our skir
mishers are blazing" away. Our lass to-day will
not exceed 50.
MR STEPHENS' MISSIOX.
Richmond, July 11. The correspondence explanato
ry of Vice President Stephens' mission, shows that he
went to Fortress Monroe as a military commissioner,
to obtain from the Federal authorities an agreement to
conduct the war hereafter according to the usages of
civilized nations. -After a meeting of two days, Ste
phens was informed that the proposition for a confer
ence was inadmissible. He therefore returned.
LATEST NEWS.
Taking all the news together, we do not look upon it as
unfavorable or discMKging. The Confederacy is stronger
to-day .than it was tyrelm month ago. 116 fall of Vicks.
burg is notbiiig Iik! equal to Uk blow w received when
New Orleans fell. We survived the loss of Nw Orleans,
and we can and will conquer notwithstanding the surren
der of Vicksburg. This is no time for despondency and it
most not be indulged. The weak-kneed class might as
well feel contented, for thre can be bat Ons result to tho
war the complete independence of the Southern States.
This will be. as 6 lire a death, though we may all yet hare
to endure much more suffering and privation, and those of
us who'are not in the field may have to turn out. It would
be worse than death to give up the contest now as a con
quered people our condition would inded be most miser
able and disgraceful. Itather than submit to this the peo
ple of the South can subsist on lfflf-rations and' put two
hundred thousand mow men in tho field. The business
in all our towns can be snsprnded and a host of men sent
to the army. In fact, if all the people of the South will
rise in their might and'reaolve to conquer, their enetuks
can be scattered and almost exterminated. Then-fore, h-t
no one be disheartened or give forth auy discouraging
sounds. A better day is coming.
Iu our columns to-day we give alT tho news we have
been able to gather. The news nhows that On. Ijeer was
not defeated at Gettysburg. As an otfret to the loss of
Vicksburg, we have gained some important posit to ua be
tween Port Hudson aud New Orleans, and the Miitnusippl
liiTer.is'still closed to tW dt-teted yankee nation, and
will remain closed until peaee in declared.
PROM GEN. LEE'S ARMY.
Confederate account of the Battle cf GeVytlurg General
Lee falls back in food order to llaya sloven Our army
Kill not evacuate Martland 10,000 Ymnktes coytureii.
From the Richmond Dispatch of Friday, 10th.
A wounded oflicer of Wright's Brigade, who arrived
iu Itichmoad on the 0th, gives some highly interesting
particulars of the battles of Gettysburg, which entirely
changes the face of the news published fiom Korthern
solirces. He left Gettysburg at 1 o'clock on Saturday
morning. From his statement we gather the following
particulars:
In the fight of Wednesday and Thursday we whipped
the enemy badly. .On Friday the fight again com
menced, being chiefly done by our centre, which wis
composed of Longst reel's corps and two divisions of
Gen. A. P. Hill's corps. Aeither the right nof left
wing was seriously engaged. We drove the enemy lack
five miles to the heights which he had fortified. In
driving them this five miles we broke through two of
their lines of battle formed to receive the onset of our
troops, and finally charged them to the heights. Here
pur men were ordered to charge the heights, and the
order being executed resulted in our repulse.
On Friday night our wagon trains were ordered to
fall back, and commenced going to the rear. It Is sup
posed that our army fell back from wart of provisions.
There was no scarcity of ammunition, for there were
many trains of ordnance out of which not a single
cartridge or shell had been taken. Some of them were
attacked by the enemy, but luabodcii's cavalry sac
cessfully drove them otf. Those of our men who were
slightly wounded and could walk were sent off Satur
day abont noonv Those who were severely wounded
were left in hospitals near the battle-field.
In the fights of -"Wednesday, Thursday and Friday,
Gen. Lee took about 10,000 prisoners, who were
prontptly sent to the rear, and who, our informant
thinks, will reach Virginia safoly. During the same
time we lost about 4,000 prisoners and about 11,000
killed aud wounded making our loss 15,000 In nil.
The battle was the most furious that has taken place
in this couutry, and the losses of the enemy in killed
and.wounded must exceed ours. Iu the charge upon
them-which drove them five miles, their I033, while
flying before our troops, was. enormous.
Our informant says that our army fell back with the
greatest deliberation and order. None of the officers
hare auv idea. that Gen. Lee intends- to re-croas -the-
Potomac. It was generally and dUtinclly understood
that the falling back was caused by the difficulty Tn
obtaining provisions through so long a line of commu
nication fts that from Gettysburg to Williamsport, and
no one In the army believed that it was intended to
evacuate Maryland. The men were in good spirits,
aud ready for. another fight with the enemy.
We last night conversed with two wounded soldiers
of Pickett's division, who left Gettysburg at 12 o'clock
on Saturday. They report that Pickett's division was
with Longstreet in the centre, on Friday, and partici
pated fh the charge upon the heights. The charge re
sulted in a repulse but nothing else. The enemy did
not leave his fortified Jieights'to. try a battle in the
field-again tbat day. Our two informants, who were
wounded, wt-nt back to their tents on the same ground
they had occupied the nrht .before, and the next day
at noon were sent off to Martinsburg. They report the
loss in the division as very heavy.. They say fhat in
the falling back of our army there was no strangling,
and that it was done in excellent order.
We were informed in an authentic quarter late last
night, that a gentleman had arrived in Richmond from
Washington yesterday evening, w ho left the latter city
on Sunday Bigot, lie reports iiiai me news reoeiveu
there up to that time was decidedly unfavorable to the
Federal arms, and that a deep and manifest feeling of
quence of the intelligence. "Efforts were made to
preveat the Information received by the authorities
from going to the public. Little confidence was felt in
the ability of Meade's army to prevent Lee's advance
pa that city wbea be should attempt it, and much
anxiety was felt for the safety of the city. No security
was felt against its fall.
It was rumored doring the. afternoon of yesterday
that a despatch bad been received by the President
from General Lee, stating that his army, in good order,
had fallea back to Hagerstown. We inquired of the
President of the tfatb of this report, and -were assured
that no such despatch had been received by him. It
is stated, however, thai a despatch-was received, (by
whom we could notlearn.) from the Commandant of
tfce Post at Marthrsbarg, 'slating that the army had
reached ITagerstown, with a large nnmber of prisoners,
and that oar forces were eutrmching themselves on
tho-bills around the town.
A giaUemaB who lived all tho early part of his life
in Gettysburg, makes the foilowiag statement, from
which it wil be seen how difficult it. is to surround.os
cot off General Lee t v -'GejUysbrg
lies" NWhrtasl of .Baltimore 52 miles,
80 miles front Washington on the road through Freder
ick, which is Stfutb-east from it a distance of 32 miles.
There is a chain of mountains lying on the West of
aad within 8 miles of Gettysburg, on the West, emend
ing Sooth through Frederick county. If Gen. Lee fell
back, towards the Potonae be ,had the advantrgeof
these mountains, as parselag army would have to go
arooad them soathward through Frederick, or eUe be
exposed to,the narrow passes of these mountains."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84027060/1863-07-11/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Gettysburg&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.152,0.407,0.916,0.993,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE BATTLE OF GETTYSBURG.
Desperation of the Contest.
GLORIOUS UNION VICTORY.
A Detailed Account.
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE POTOMAC,
GETTYSBURG, Saturday, 7 p. M., July 4,
1863.—At 7 o'clock in the evening of
June, Major General George G. Meade
becauie commander of the Army of the
Potomac. That same night he issued or
ders to the several corps to move, and on
the following morning the army moved as
if unconscious of the change of command
ers. The army was encamped about Fred
erick, Maryland. The main portion was
ordered to move into Pennsylvania,through
Emmettsburg, where the First, Third
and Eleventh Corps encamped Tuesday.
The Sixth was ordered to Carlisle. The
Second and Twelfth were also near Em
mettsburg. Early on Wednesday morn
ing the First Corps, commanded by Major
General Reynolds, and the Eleventh,
commanded by Major General Howard,
were ordered to Gettysburg, where it was
reported the enemy had taken position.
The detachment was commanded by
General Reynolds.
The troops were pushed forward rap
idly, and arrived at Gettysburg, on the
Baltimore pike, at half past ten o'clock in
the forenoon.
The First Corps was in the advance. The
enemy's outposts were encountered in a
wood west of the town, near the Seminary.
Gen. Wadsworth, who commanded the 1st
division, immediately engaged the enemy
in his front, and fought him for the wood.
DEATH OK E\ RKYNOLDS.
Gen. Reynolds rode forward to inspect
the ground and select a position for the line
of battle. The enemy distinguishing him
as well from his soldier^ bearing as from
his uniform to be an officer of high rank,
opened upon him with heavy volleys of in
fantry fire. He was struck by several
balls and died instantly without uttering
a word. His Acting Adjutant-General,
Capt. Bond, was at his side and caughthim
in his arms to prevent •him falling from his
horse.
This gallant officer, well and favorably
known to the army and the country, never
fought battles through orderlies and aids,
but always in person. Like Sumner, in
battle he was at the head of his column to
direct—and, by his own example of per
sonal courage, sustain his command when
death reigned fearfully all around.
That he was too rash will be alleged by
many that he was a superior soldier and a
brave man, is the testimony of every one
who knew him.
He fell fighting nobly for his country.—
Still more, he died iu the defense of his na
tive State. No treason-bleeding soil
drank up his blood,'but all of him that was
mortal is buried in the bosom of his own
native State.
Major General Doubleday succeeded to
the command of the First Corps, and«vigor
ously continued the operations commenced
by Reynolds, Wadsworth being already
engaged near the Seminary, west of the
town. Robinson's Division formed on the
right and Doubleday's Division on the left
of Wadsworth, and the whole line ad
vanced through the woods, driving back
the enemy. Soon, however, solid masses
of rebel troops were seen coming up and
taking position on the right and left llanks,
and it was evident that hot work was on
hand.
Gen. Doubleday so distributed his forces
as to hold a neck of woods on an eminence
which was the key to the position. He
continued with desperate fighting to hold
his ground until the Eleventh Corps arriv
ed and came to his relief. Maj. Gen. How
ard then assumed command of the forces.
One brigade from Steinwher's division, was
sent into the town to hold it. Gen. How
ard, seeing the vital importance of seizing
upon and hold the commandind positions,
directed Gen. Steinwher to take his re
maining brigade and the reserve artillery,
place it on the Cemetery hill, and to de
fend the heights.
The divisions commanded by Schurz and
Barlow were sent up to the immediate sup­
•3 BURLINGTON ^WEEKLY HAWK-EYE.
port of the First Corps. The troops were
led forward with the memory of Chancel
lorsvillebefore them, and wltn a determin
ation to retrieve their lost honor. The two
divisions moved through the town and
took a position on the right of the First
Corps, and fought desperately against
Ewell's corpSjWnich outnumbered them
three to oue. The first and second charges
were stoutly resisted by the Eleventh
Corps on the right, bnt on came a third
charge with four regular lines for overlap
ping the little force on both flanks. Tht
men still undaunted fought until both
flanks were turned near half a mile.
The force now opposed to the 1st and 11th
comprised the corps of A. P. Hill, and Ew
ell, numbering over 60,000 men. Yet
against this fearful odds the gallant band
fought for hours, inflicting great slaughter
on the enemy.
Reynolds and Zook were dead, and Paul
and Barlow wounded, and Schimmelfen
ning a prisoner. Many field and line offi
cers
had been lost and nearly half the men
before the order was given to retire to the
bights held by Steinwehr.
Gen. Howard had carefully examined
the topography of the surrounding coun
try. He knew that a very strong force of
the enemy lay in the valley he felt, there
fore, that the holding of Cemetery Hill,
which commanded the whole surrounding
country, was of the most vital importance.
Accordingly he took the responsibility of
falling back south east of the town, to the
commanding bights on both sides of the
Baltimore pike.
The troops retired in the face of an over
whelming foe with a commendable steadi
ness. At times there was a little wavering
but nothing even approacihng a panic.—
The corps by their conduct on Wednesday
and later in the battle are entitled to great
commendation, and the Chancellorsvilles
disgrace is swallowed up by the achieve
ments at Gettysburg.
Gen. Slocum with the 12th and Sickles
with the 3d Corps, came up and took posi
tion to the right and left of Howard, on the
hills.
During the battle in the afternoon, when
his troops were outnumbered and sorely
pressed, Gen. Howard sent to Slocum, who
was within five miles, to oome to his re
lief. He sent a second time but received
no reply. Gen. Howard then sent his
brother, Major Howard, to urge upon Gen.
Slocum to come up in person if he Would
not send troops. Slocum replied that he
did not wish to take the responsibility of
the fight.
In the mean time, however, he moved up
his corps to be ready to aid in defense of
the hights if necessary.
Gen. Sickles on receiving Howard's re
quest, at once moved up rapidly but owing
to the great distance he was in rear his
corps did not arrive until the second posi
tion had been taken.
The enemy was not disposed to attempt
the carrying of the hights and here tne
battle ended.
Two advantages were gained. The ene
my was obliged to exhibit his strength and
to commit himself to a position and the
commanding positions were seized and
held by the national troops.
During the night Gen. Meade and staff
came up to the front. The Commanding
General carefully examined the surround
ing country, and after considering the lo
cations and positions in all their strategical
and tactical bearing, he approved of the po
sitions taken by Gen. Howard, and so
disposed his forces on the several hills or
"round tops" and ridges, as to construct a
battle line in the form of a crescent, with
the centre to the southward from the cem
etery.
The hills present outcrops of sandstone
rocks in ledges having a dip of from 20 to
90 degrees these ledges in many cases are
full 20 feet high, and afford admirable
shelter for troops. The slope of the hills at
places is moderate and regular, in some
instances abrupt, and even sometimes pre
sents vertical rocky faces.
The enemy was in a valley or on hills at
a distance too great to be of use for shelter.
The roads on which the enemy would de
sire to march were commandeu by Meade's
guns, and hence Lee must fight with the
hills against him. For once, then, in the
history of the Army of the Potomac, the
enemy has been compelled to give battle at
a disadvaniage.
On Wednesday night all the troops but
the Sixth Corps, commanded by Gen. Sedg
wick, arrived on the field. The veteran
division, known as the Pennsylvania Re
serve Corps, was attached to the Fifth
Corps. The Second Vermont Brigade, nine
months' men, were assigned to the First
Corps. On Thursday morning the line was
formed as follows: Slocum's corps on the
right, Howard joining on the left, Han
cock's (Conch's) Newton's (Reynold's) and
Sickle's Corps in the centre and Syke's
(Meade's) on the left. Numerically, com
mencing with the right, the line was form
ed on the 12th 14th, 2d, 1st, 3d, and 5th
Corps.
This was essentially the position during
Thursday and Friday, though Gen. Meade
did not fight his army by corps. As the
battle raged more fiercely here or there de
tachments of divisions or brigades were
sent to support, and would remain till
wanted elsewhere.
So admirably were the several resistan
ces and onslaughts managed that whenev
er and wherever supporting columns were
needed then and there they would be found
in sufficient force to accomplish the object
desired.
All the hights, and every advantageous
position along the entire line where artil
lery could be massed or battery planted,
frowned down on the enemy through brows
of brass and iron.
There was no conceivable advance of ap
proach that could not be raked and cros
sed with the artillery. ,The reserve artil
lery and all the essentials to insure victory
were in position at the right time. The
immense cavalry force, too, for once, was
present, covering both Hanks of the arniv
and continually harassing the enemy.—
This was a new and an encouraging fea
ture that gave confidence to the men and
security to the trains.
There were no ghosts of stampeding corps
or other scapegoats with liorm fast in the
bushes ready to bear away what ever cen
sure might befall one too weak to bear the
burden ol'his own folly. These the caval
ry prancing along Uie flanks frightened
away to the swamps of the Chickahominy,
the banks of the Rappahannock, or to An
tietam's bloody fields,where erst they were
wont to congregate*
Early on Thursday morning the enemy
commenced feeling the lines of Gen.
Meade's army. Skirmishing continued
more or less severe until 4 o'clock in the
afternoon. Suddenly, at about this hour,
the enemy opened a terrific fire on the
Cemetry Hill held bv the 11th Corps on
the right—center held by the 2d Corps.—
The artillery in front of the enemy's fire
replied vigorously, and for two hours the
roar and thunder and flame and smoke of
artillery, and the screech of shells, so com
pletely filled the heavens that all' else
seemed forgotten.
One form, however, with mind intent oh
high purposes, stood on an eminence lean
ing slightly forward, and with eagle eye
pierced the vail of smoke, and saw and
felt and knew that an hour more terrible
by far than the present was coming rapid
ly—'was even present. It was evident the
wily commander of the rebel forces had de
termined on some desperate charge, but
when and in what manner it would be
made was unknown to the man who stood
calmly yet with deep solicitude regarding
every pulsation of the battle.
On the left, through the woods, black
masses were seen moving—larger, more
frequent nearer! Skirmishing in that
gicklesisand
art of the field becomes sharper. Gen.
ordered forward to develop the
enemy's intentions. The black columns
come out of the wood and suddenly the
thnnder of artillery eeased,and,with cheers
and yells, tjie roar of musketry and. flash
of bayonet, full 50,000 men from Long
street's and Hill's corps, came rushing
against our lines. The Third Corps stood
firm for a while, but afterward gave way
beneath the weight of the attacking column
ahd on they came ten-fold ihore furious
than before.
Sickles fell severely wounded in the leg
and his corps was litterally cut to pieces.
The Second
Corps was thrown in the breach
from the right and the Fifth from the left.
The Second suffered fearftilly. Hancock
received a painful flesh wound in the thigh
but refused to be led from the field whUe
the engagement continued. Here, too,
Gen. Gibbon was wounded in the shoul
der. The terrible charge and fierce battle
raged with unabated fury. The Fifth
Corps, including the Regulars and the
Pennsylvania Reserves, struggled in the
hereulean labor with the determination of
men born to conquer in battle.
The aid of the 12th Corps, from the ex
treme right was called for, and a division
was ordered up, and about the same time
Sedgwick came up with the 6th Corps, af
ter a march of thirty-six consecutive hours.
The men were footsore, many without any
shoes on their feet, hungry and wea^, and
ready to drop on the road from exhaustion.
When, however, the situation flashed into
the minds of these weary soldiers, the fire
and zeal for which this Corps is so justly
celebrated, was kindled anew in their brave
hearts. They awaited but the order, and
that impatiently,to be led against the ene
my. The order was given, and, like men
fresh from camp, they went down upon the
haughty foe like an avalanche. The rebel
column staggered and reeled, and then fell
back in confusion, leaving their dead lying
against and across each other in this field
of slaughter.
The sun went down. Suddenlv as the
western hills eclipsed his rays the battle
carnage ceased on the left.
Equally sudden, a fierce charge dashed
against the weakened lines of the right
wing. The suddenness of the attack and
the weight of Ewell's column gave some
advantage to the enemy. Reinforcements
rcuw was aeiermined to go
through the right and gain control of the
valley roads. The failure to turn the left,
and the snatching the victory from their
clutches, hurling their broken columns
back defeated and confused on the left,
made their case more desperate, and the at
tack on Slocum was furious even to mad
ness, The 1st and 6th Corps came up
promptly to the support of the 12th Corps.
From dark until 91 o'clock the battle raged
with unabated fury. The lines moved to
and fro, each in turn advancing and falling
back. At this hour of the night the enemy
made his final charge on the left of the
right wing, held by Gen. Geary's division.
He was repulsed with terrible slaughter,
and refused to renew the attack. At 10 o'
clock the battle ceased, and during the
night all was quiet.
Ewell had been largely reinforced, and
held a position of some advantage. Gen.
Meade determined that he should be dis
lodged from the place, and as a matter of
personal honor, assigned the task to Gen.
Slocum, who had previously occupied the
same position, but was compelled to aban
don it because of the reinforcements sent
to the support of the left wing, overwhelm
ed by Longstreet's and A. P. Hill's divi
sions.
Gen. Slocum accordingly made prepara
tions for the work assigned. His own corps
was in strong position, and determined to
regain the ground lost the night before.
A division from the 6th Corps was pos
ted on the right of the 12th, thus forming
the extreme outpost of the right wing.—
The 5th Corps was sent over as a reserve,
and Gen. Wadsworth's division of the 1st
Corps, took position to strengthen How
ard's right where it joined Slocum's left.
These were the preliminaries. The men
well knew what sort of work they would
be called upon to do in the morning, and
nerved their hearts and cheered each other
against the hour of trial by tire.
On Friday morning at 4 o'clock, Slocum's
line opened a terrific fire on Ewell's men.
The enemy responded in a most furious
charge, for which mode of fighting they are
justly celebrated. The fighting on Thurs
day on the left, where Longstreet and Hill
fought with most terrible desperation for
three hours, aud the subsequent battle on
the right by Ewell, ^re regarded by the
oldest officers in the a/my as the most ob
stinate aud deadly contest of the war. Of
ficers and men lay dead in fearful num
bers. But the enemy's charge in response
to Slocum's fire seemed ten times more
furious.
With fiendish yell and such contempt of
death during six full hours, they hurled
their solid masses against the well-defend
ed lines. The National troops stood like a
wall of fire, whose flaming tongues en
wrapped in death whatever came near,
whose foundation were firm as if one with
the primal rock on which it rested.
Nothing during the war has equalled
this six hours' carnage. In front of Grang's
position were more rebel dead than the
number of the entire list of casualties in
the 12th corps. The dead were lying liter
ally in heaps, many hit in all manner of
degrees, from a clean shot'through the head
to bodies torn to pieces by exploding shells.
At 10 o'clock Slocum had repulsed and
driven back the enemy at every point, and
reoccupied his original position. The bat
tle ceased at 11 o'clock, and there was a
pause like to the stillness of death that
rested for three hours on the living and
dead.
No matter how long pressed by the ene
mv the Union troops felt even in the front
rifle pits that the Commanding General
was conversant with their situation, and
would not suffer them to be overwhelmed.
The officers would say to the men, and the
men to each other, "Meade will send you
help—just hold on a little longer."
Nor were they disappointed. If the Gen
eral in command was possesed with a de
gree of calm deliberation truly wonderful,
and seemed intuitively to know what was
necessary to be done and toi be endowed
with a superior genius in the distribution
and handling of his forces.
At 12 o'clock on Friday afternoon Lee
opened a liue of artillery tire from about
one hundred guns, concentrated against
Cemetery Hill and the position along the
centre held by the Second and a part of the
First Corps.
The firing was responded to by all the
batteries on the hill, and then ensued three
hours of cannonading unsurpassed in in
cessant fierceness by any artillery battle
on this continent. The sight and sound
were awfully sublime. The hills trembled
beneath the percussion. The sound filled
the heavens, and Nature, as it were, stood
still to contemplate the scene.
Horses were shot down by scores, gun
carriages were demolished, pieces dis
mounted, caissons exploded, whole bat
teries were swept away, and cannoniers
and officers killed and wounded in num
bers almost incredible. No less than fif
teen caissons were exploded on the hights,
and two regular batteries on the right of
the cemetery were completely demolished.
Much of the enemy's firing was wild,
and scattered near ana far over the field.—
Gen. Meade's headquarters were forced to
take refuge behind the rocks near General
Slocum's headquarters. The non-combat
tants were especially alarmed, but the fight
ing members thought it fc,good joke to see
their associates flee the wrath to come, pent
up in rebel shells.
Gen. Howard's headquarters were in the
Cemetery, and were raked in a fearful man
ner men fell all round him, but himself
and staff escaped.
The abode of the dead was made the
theater of deadly conflict. Tombstones
aud beautiful monuments were demolished
great holes were torn in the eJrth by the
explosion of shells, and ilie surface check
ered with furrows.
The artillery fire continued till about 4
o'clock, when the solid columns of rebel
infantry were again moving in the wood in
front of the center, held by the 1st and 2d
corps.
During the fierce cannonading the men
and officers were ordered to shelter them
selves behind ^Jie hills and rocks. When
however, the rdbel infantry was seen in
the woods, several officers came to Gen.
Doubleday, volunteering to carry mes
sages to Meade and ask that the center be
strengthened.
Doubleday replied to the officers that
they might trust to Gen. Meade that he
would keep his eye on the movements of
tne enemy and have his forces ready to
meet his attacks. Out they came, and
rushed rapidly over the fields in solid mass,
with less fury than before,
lhe head of the column was directed
against a position held by Gen. Webb, com
manding 2d Brigade, 2d Division, 2d Corps.
His troops were old, and steady and brave
7T'tustood the charge. The steady fire
of the National troops staggered the ene
my, Rebel Gen. Armistead, who
lead the charge, wishing to steady his col
umn, halted it for a moment at a fence.
Gen. Webb seeing, called out to his brig
ade, "Charge! the enemy is ours." And
true enough he was. The commanding
Gen. Armistead and 3,500 men were cap
tured by the closing in of the Second Corps
on the right and the First on the left.
The £nemy was driven back over the
fields with great slaughter. The enemy
then withdrew from the field, and the
batr-
tle ended.
During the battles of Friday,. Gen. Han
cock, though severely wounded, lay under
a tree and gave orders, fighting until the
battle was ended.
On Friday night, the cavalry, which dur
ing the several days of battle had rendered
valuable service and kept the Rebel cava!
ry close within the infantry lines, reported
the enemy retreating on the Cooktown
road. Large cavalry forces were sent out
to watch his movements.
Early on Saturday morning
Gen. Slocum
was ordered to make a reconnoissance by
yond Gettysburg, and in order to feel the
enemy's position. He was found intrench
ing himself in front of the Gap. This was
supposed to be a feint, and also a defense
to cover his retreat.
In the morning, also, a brigade from
Steimwehr's division, 11th Corps, occupied
Gettysburg, driving out the Rebel shftrp
shooters.
The sfteets were barricaded and the place
put in a defensive condition. General Lee
sent a message under a flag of truce, to the
effect that if the National troops were not
withdrawn from the town it would be shel
led. General Meade replied that he would
dispose his troops as best suited his pur
pose of course, the troops were not with
drawn, nor was the army.
The rebel army is hedged in and will
hardlgr escape with an organization.
The slaughter on both sides has been ter
rible, 15,000 will scarcely cover the casu
alties in killed and wounded in the Na
tional army. The rebels must have
suffered
a loss of 25,000 in killed, wounded and pris
oners.
Rebel prisoners report Longstreet a pris
oner. Gen. Gibbon announced to his troops
that they had captured Longstreet and a
member of Kilpatrick's staff says he saw
Longstreet a prisoner, mortally wounded,
lying in a barn. One of your correspond
ents the same day saw the dead body of a
Major General in the rebel uniform in the
baru alluded to. Ewell is reported woun
ded. Gen. Barksdale is dead, and buried
in our lines.
The citizens of Gettysburg affirm that
Lee is certainly wounded.
General Barlow, who was wounded and
taken prisoner, is in Gettysburg, not pa
roled the enemy was pressed for time.
Gen. Schemmelfennig was not a prisoner
but disguised as a private, he lay concealed
in the town shelled.
No movements were made on Saturday,
save by the cavalry and the reconnoissance
by Slocum. The enemy abandoned the
field with his dead and wounded in the
hands of the victors. The victory is com
plete. Meade is master of the position.—
No matter what Lee may design, General
Meade's head is clear and his heart earnest
in the cause.
Officers and men are in good spirits. The
only thing talked of is the capture or des
truction of Lee's entire army until our
forces arrived. He is with his command.
Gen. Meade has greatly distinguished
himself in the management of this most
terrible of battles. The Army of the Poto
mac was fought as an army, and has won
a victory with fruits commensurate with
its labors.
All things are in readiness, and Meade
and his army are always in a condition to
fight, and because of rain will not retreat,
but rather advance. With the swelling of
the Potomac in his front, Couch and French
on his flanks and Meade's victorious army
in his rear, Lee has the alternative of hav
ing his army annihilated as an army, or of
surrendering to the National forces.—
Meade will give him but little time to de
liberate.- Cor. N. Y. Tribune.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030213/1863-07-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.154,0.899,0.37,0.401,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE REBEL INVASION.
ene
SEVERE BATTLE NEAR GETTYSBURG.
at
Fighting Continued Yesterday.
pr

Heavy Attack on our First
Army Corps.
Brave Endurance of the Troops.
OE SEAS KILLED,
TIMELY ARRIVAL OF RE-ENFORCEMENTS
The Rebels eared and Driven.
Reported ey 6.000 Prisoners.
The Whole Army of the Potomac
Brought Up.
Strong Positions Taken During the Night,

The Army Enthusiastic and Eager
for Engagement.
Iridave.
Pa.. Thursday, July 2, 1863.
The battle opened yesterday morning, by revere
The First
ported by Pleasanton’s cavalry and artillery, en-
fpecisl Dispatch to The N.Y
CorLtMBiA
shirmishing, and Eleventh Corps, sup-
gouged with Ewell's forces, near Gettysburg, toward
Beudersville. The fight continued throughout the
day, with variable results.
The battle was renewed this morning, and con-
tinned up to 4 o'clock, our forces gaining npon the
Rebels whea our messenger left the field. Siuce o
o'clock, the firing bas been much heavier and wore
rapid, pertaining to a general engagement,
Gen. Lee's forces are said to be concentrated fon
miles north-east of Gettysburg, This afternoo
Sedgwick's corps is reported pressing upon the rear
of the enemy. The 20 Army Corpe ie woving uj
from Hanover this morning.
bvthe IY
The reported burning of Gettysburg
ja unfounde?; only two buildings were desiroy
by shell in the suburbs.
special Dispateh to The N.Y. Tribune
Wasninerox, Thureday, July BEd
Gen, Meade, iu 8 telegram received to-day ways
that all appearances lust pizht indicate that ther
would be a pitched battle between the two art
to-day. Yesterday Hill aud Ewell fo ht two of
our corps, and Longstreet, with whom was Lee, u's
appeared to Le endenve ring to get into the ati
Gen. Reynolds fell early in the batt'e while placi:
bis men in position. He took puins that no
ghonld know that he had received his de:
until he bad ridden some distance out of the act
announced that
th we
when he quietly got off Lis horse,
be wae seriously wounded, and directed a sn peon
be sent for,
A distressing accident ocenrred at Harper's Ferr;
yest rdsy af the garrison were eval natiog the fort
ficatione of Marylaud Heights, which result din the
death of ten soldiers and wonnding of alont fori
Tue killed and woanded belonged to the teh and Sil
Maryland Regiments. The accident resulted frou
carelessness of some of the roldiers in knocking to
pieces barrels of powder. Three explosions too
piace at about 3 o'clock, The powder in tie muge-
zine did vot cateb,
The men wounded by the accident, with a
wounded at Harper's Ferry, numbering 300, were
removed ww thie city to-day by bost down the Cum.
berlaud Canal. The wonnded
br. D. B. Beuet, U. S. Volunteers,
of thei
l
Lhe
arge of
Muuvy of thew
the
were
Were badly burned, aud one died on
wW.V.
A regiment of cavalry, lately stationed ut Fred

eri
of Yuolesvilie, Edwards's Ferry, Seneca, aud Rock-
ck. reachied Washington to-day, coming by way
vi! vg the Potomac,
Le country between Frederick and Poolesville is
and ietuibed, and the farwers ure engaged iu Larvest-
ing p. ‘There is uo
Reet! forces iu the vicinity, with the exception of
u.
bountiful grain cro truce of
v und then a deserter. Three brigades of Rebels
rosd
L
pusead through Seneca on Monday, taking the
toward Middicburg., Mavy of the people about
Jiockvlle Lad left for Washington, as they were ex-
scting the Rebels w ford the Potomac at that place
J)
vl
7
ir return from Pennsylvania,
Leudiuy Secessionists publicly rej orted that this
wil route of the Rebel leaders on the return
o {wir wy to Virginia, Eleven barges, belong.
ir g 0the Government, destroyed by the Rebels on
bo wey, ell remain where they were left partial;
bu: met, 10 the caugl.
T MWe worsded from the battle of yesterday near
Cer wburg w Il be taken to Harrishurg, Ba ti
and y "wrk. The Washington hospitals are ulso in
rend in. we 40 receive wonuded,
ore,
There Was great panic in Georgetown und
throush ©e conatry toward Rockville this morning.
Crowds 01" people, with loads of merchandise, can
flocking e ward the fortifications of Washington, re-
New-Nork
aribmne,
NEW-YORK, FRIDAY, JULY 3,
1863.
PRICE THREE CENTS.
ver XXIIL....N° 6.941.
Gettysburg. Gen. Paul comwanded the Third
Brigade of the First Army Corps.
Col. Stone and Col. Wistar were both wounded
and taken prisoners, Col. Wistar commanded the
Bucktuils—a Pennsylvania regiment. Col. Stoue
lalso commanded a Pennsylvania regiment in the
Second Brigade of the First Army Corps, and was
acting Brigadier-General of the Second Brigade.
Gen. Newton took command of the First Army
Corps on the fall of Major Gen. Reynolds,
la‘er.~-We learn from the officers of Major-Gen.
Reynolds's sift that our forces passed through Get
tysburg at 10 o'clock yesterday morning, and when
a quarter of mile west of the town encountered
Gens, Longstreet und Hill, wio attacked the Corps of
Gen. Reynolds, which was in the advance, Thiseorp
stood the force of the attack until it was relieved by
the Third Corps, and a commanding position secure 1.
ihe Rebels made w strong attempt io flank the posi-
bat were repulsed in the at-
tion we bad gained,
tempt. Gen. keynolds and Gen. Paul fell under
volley from the Rebel infantry. Both officers were
mounted, and at the bead of their troops. In the
course of the conflict we fell back betore gnperior
numbers to a stronger position, and the fight ceased
o'clock. At the close of the even
Ary of the Potomne bad reachicd the
for the day at
ng the W Lole
field, and Major-Gen, Mesde had all the Corps stot g-
ly posted for a ren wal of the battie this morning.
"The loss of the cueiny Was congidesed fully (ual to
Cure,
The army of the Potomac is in five condition and
very enthusiastic. Our logs of officers 18 severe,
Cols. Wistar aud Stone were wounded when they
tell into the hands of the Rel ele, Our army 1s re.
garded us better concentrated than that of the Reb:
ca lor thie events of to-day.
The Battle of Gettysburg— 06,000 Prisoncrs
Captured,
Eavtivone, Thursday, July 2-11 p. m
I shall send you soon an account from the battle
"field near Ge tiyeburg of yes orday’s battle, which 1s
very favoral.c.
Meunwhile the
mude of the capture of large nu
cment has ben
er of prisoners,
cheering annonn
others ure on
t u
g have ar:ived here and
Th w stared at 6,000, bu
Way an exaggeration. Gen, Scl
aunounced at the Eutaw House that 2,400 of them
some of wh
the way. e number Ie
y nek has just
have arnived,

From the Front,
Lattisons, Fiday, July 3-la m
The American learus Irom parties who left
Gettysburg at noon today that everything wis
progressing mvorsbly for the ultimate success
Up to that time they assert that 6,000
oar Lri i ni
prisovers bad been captured und sent to the rallrowd
terminus at Union Brndge for transportation to
Balti ore Ihe Tih Regiment have just gone to
Bolton depot to take ebarge of 800, already arrived,
(Gen. Schenck bus just apnounced from tre
Fataw House that Le then bad in Baltinore und ut
the lelay Houge 2,400 in Lis possession,
We
re
learn that pearly
rec on Wednes
1 yt
i
1,000 of these prisoners
w sy bythe Eleventh Army
y Bb)
4] LL
wien
rg m Lovgstreet’s Corps
st slightly faltered, Lu
to them to Remember
v ure said to have
(en. H ward cried
ville.” they rushed into the fight Like in-
vy, and the whole line of the eneny
(hat
gnva way before them.

During the ently part of to-day up to noon, when
0 formant left, there bad been no general battle
thongh Leavy skirmishing bad been going on all
the Ing, resulting in a heavy logs to the enemy
the capturing of over 5,000 more prisoners, In
A en skirmishes, which were couducted under
th noof Gen, Meade, our armas were entirely
Cova but the enemy siud ously avoided nny
general engngement, und it wus thought there
would be none ore to-asy, when it was said to
be the intention of Gen, Meude to press the enemy
alony the whole hoe,
y dence wud skill displayed by Gen, Meade
ent of Li
in coping with Lee had already won
He s« urmy, and the strategy
evinced by) hii
the confidence of his troops, und bis presence drev
sliongest de wonstratione of attachment.
weed the
Lud been strongly lmpreesed by the
lori Lue
I'he uriny es determination to win st uli
Lazurds, aud
ollicers Wid Lue
eadiul consequences that woulda
if
in the coming conflict,
ensue to them snd the country disuster should
OCCUTr 10 Our uring
The enemy was rupidly concentrating troops yee
gud Gen, Mende's whole army bud reached
terday,
the field
(ie
of battle,
on
Cumberland Valley on the eacmy.
11 o'clock po m.— Eight hundred and thirty Rebel
prisoners bhuve just puseod down Balawmore street
under vnard, Among the number are Geu. Archer
hh was expected to press down through
wud 70 other officers,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053570/1863-07-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.647,0.868,0.277,0.3,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>EXTRA
TWELVE O'CLOCK.
THE SITUATION.
Tho Information received at hcadtuartrrs
this mojnlng Is cheering, and no doubt la en
teralncd thnt the rebel Invasion will result In
the total defeat of Lee's army In Its laot dw
pcratc strnTglo.
It would not be proper to lay before onr
readers tho plana of onr Generals, aud the
fact" Mhlch render It morally certain that
the concentrateJ forces of tho enemy will
be overthrown; Mil If tho public knew all,
they would participate lu the feeling of confi
dence that animates the Government to-day.
The right wing of Oen, Meade's army, after
having performed marches that ore almost with
out parallel, withstood on Wednesday thcahoek
of Leo's best and freshest troops, superior In
numbers to oun and entirely defeated their
attempt to turn our right) and to-day we occupy
tho position from which they tried to drive us.
A decisive battlo may ho going on at this
moment, although It la tho opinion of mauy
In military circles that Leo will not dare to
rick nil ii von a battl Immediately.
Heavy skirmishing waa going on jesterday,
m hlch led to ttio report that a general light was
going 011, and to which wcgavecrodcnce. We
expect additional news from tho scat of war
heforo our ucxt edition Is prlutcd.
THE BEBEL INVASION
BATTLE OP GETTYSBURG.
MaJ. (Jen. Itejuolds.and Drlg, Cfu
Paul Killed.
We copy the following frem the Baltimore
American of this morning t
Major llumgartcn and another officer of the
htntTof MaJ, Ocn, Rcyuolds, arrived here yes
terday from Octtysburg, bringing with them
tho body of den. Reynolds who fell mortally
wounded In the hattlo on Wednesday, west ot
netlsburg, and died soon after being carried
irom tne ueiu.
From Major Bumcartcn we learn some In
teresting particulars of the battle, and are hajt-
py to no u mo 10 isny uiai u rinseu lor tnn u;.
with the army of (leu. Meade hi a most advan
taccous DOsltlon. either for attack or defence.
Nearly all the remaining divisions of our army
readied the fleldshortly after the firing ccacd
for tho dav. v
It appears that at V o'clock on Wcdnesdav
morning tbe 1st and 11th corpa ofthe Army of
tne roiomac reacueu tiettysnurg, entering irom
tin cist side of the town, and mnrchlng directly
through to the we6t side, the cavalry frcuof
mc cni'my 111 uie town railing nntk an we ad
vanced. On pjsslugoutof the west end ofthe
town, the enemy wns observed advancing rap
idly irom tho Chamlierthurg turnpike In line
01 name mwnras uiu town, evinenuy endeavor
ing to hold nn udvantageoiH position com
mandlnir the town.
Thu 1st mrpi", under din. Reynolds was in
thu ndvanee, aud pushed forward at double
quick to secnrelhewlvautageou position. Thu
enemy unrttY I.onL'Ptrect and J fill advanced
tttcadlly, and In u lew minutes n heavy tire nf
nuin ariniery nun muketry waa opmui niong
the whole FedirnI aud rebel lines. 1 lie 11th
army corns, under den. Howard, was also soon
In piisltlou, aud for a time tiUu 11 heavy buttle
lagid. bcural chargea were mado by the env
oi) to diiiloilgo our lorn, nil of vvhkh were
uiixucccaxful.
At it o'clock lhe enemy masked his entire
fonts, and endeavored to turu our right wlu.
(intral Jtejnold adv.ined to meet ttiem and
a hi iv v Inlantrv Huht tuMied. in which both
pirtles BUlftred severely, volhy after volley of
musketry oeiug poured imo tuo opjiosing coi
minis with dcidty itfect. In this charge Mujor
tiener u iu')U(uu leu mortally wounded, una
diid soon after hi lug comevi'd to Ilittvsbuig.
lie wa, as uua't leading h s corps aud lu the
thickest ol tiiotiuiit. (ituirui raui, command
lug thu M brigade nf tho First Army Corps,
vvum also kU'ed on the Held, aud Colomla Win
tar aud Stone ft 11 st-vcrely wounded, and weru
taken pi Isnners hv Uiu enutny. lue iiuiu lm
Itweeiithu conteimluit armies was strewn with
the dead mid wounded, and It is said (hit thu
inemv uttered fnlly us heavily as wo did,
though It Is not known what wua Ihelr loss In
1 ollleers.
I 'llntelfort to Hank Our rlirht wlmr cnllrelv
I fitlud, mid we held th prominent and coin-
iiiniidiui; piisitmti lurwmcu inu struggle wns
iii.ide at tlm 1 loci ot thu light, which ctunud fur
thu d 13 about 4 o'tlctk In thu afternoon. At
this time two more corps of (let) oral Meade's
unii) run lied tint liild, uud during tliu night
tlm tu tin body of our army wns lu portion to
uu U any demonstrations that thu ineiny might
make lu tiie morning, or 10 auvaueu on him,
as thu commanding central mlirht dechle.
The First armycorpn nobly malutalued Its
ponlilon agalntttheellorttoiliuk its rlglit, aud
srarceiy luiitreu mr a mniuenc wneu its gal
lant commandir Ml under the murderous Urn
ofthe enemy. A great uud decisive battle was
cnutldcnd Imminent, and tiotwltlistaudlngour
itevvre loss Iu ollleers. the advantages ol tliu
day were regarded a decidedly with mir lorceii.
Iho army was In flue condition, full of en tliu-
slusiu for thu ruining buttle, and toulldent of
sum, turn rui .vtcaue had uuo, 11 was
thought, (otuenlrnted his forces to 11 greatir
exti ut than thu cm in), a Urge portion o whoou
arm) wa miii scatunu up tnrouu tlm Liuu
berland VilUv.
Col. WUlar commundLd lhe Pitiiis)1vanU
Burktalls and Col. Htouo aluo rominuinled a
rcniifi)lviinU regiment, and both were lu tin
Hcioml brlgado ol tin- tlr-t urmv euro-, f'ol
elom, it lhe time of ru elvlug his wouud, wan
utliug ns Urlgudler Uuural ol thu sicouil brig
ade, (leu. Newton took lominauilof the lirntarmj
cori on tho fatt of Ikn. Reviuddi.
(,eii. I'juI commimUd the third brigade nf
tlio lirrti ami) torps, aiid wjs u moht ulultut
Ollieer.
Auollier Act omit.
Homo ccutlcimn coiuiutid wllh Die Mehi
whourrived here Uatevtnlug from (,ett)lmrg,
navuig icii oeioru uajngin in tne morniug
represent ihocondillou ot utrdra at lliuiloxu m
thu light on Wudneadn) eviuiug to have Imi
still moiufavorubloaud pruuiUliuot usutiess
ful Issue thau thu previous liiforiiiut'oii we hid
recelvetl, lliey statu that thu rebtls had held
(letl)sbuig lor home thnu prevloua to the ap
projc h of our arm) and had not oul) ih i uplud
but had commenced fortifying the hills west of
tne town, where tney propoeed to cnecic onr
savancc toward cnamoersnurgana me raontn
ofthe Cumberland Valley.
The movement of flcn. Reynolds, and the ra
pidity with which he advanced after entering
the east end of the town, took them somewhat
by surprise, and he soon obtalnod tho proml
ncnt position which the rebels were fortifying.
Tho fighting through the balance of the day
was In a futile attempt on their part to retrain
this Important position, from which they were
frequently repulsed,
Karl v In the afternoon both Lonestreet
and IIUl combined their forces for a grand cirbrt
to tnrn our right flank, when flen. Howard's
Eleventh Corps, which broke and ran at Chan
cellorsvlllo, dashed In to regain their lost lau
rels, and roost nobly did they repulse these two
veteran corps of the rebel army. Tbe repulse
was so complete that no further attempt was
made by thu enemy during the balance of the
day, and night closed In with our holding the
position chosen by the enemy to give us battle
trom.
Tbo Third and Twelfth army corps also came
on the field after thn list repulse of tho enemy,
but owing to the fall of den. Reynolds, and the
lateness of the hour, as well as tho exhaustion
of tho men, and the desire to take car of the
wounded, It was determined not to pui.li the
enemy foj; a renewal ofthe conflict.
v nen our imormam ion tne ueia yesterua)
morning Gen. Meade had arrived, and the main
body f our army was In position, ready to rush
thu enemy so soon as da) should dawn.
ucuytuurg is jusi twcniy-nve miies easi 01
vuaiiuriiiruii uiu u uur iuiiiuj vuuutl J lUOBt
of the way, which will doubtless be the scene
of tho great battles of the rebel Invasion.
Unfavorable Accounts.
From one of the officers who came down In
charge oflhn prisoners who arrived last night,
and who left Gettysburg on Wednesday after
noon, we have ncconnts not ao favorable as
those given by other parties. Ho describes the
ugiit on inni nay as ramcr uniavoranio to our
anus, and itatcs that the enemy held the Held
at the close of thu day, our force having fallen
oacK alter 1110 mil 01 ucn. itcynoidit nun ine
attack of the enemy was so sudden and unex
pected that both tbe corps of Hill and Long
street were for a time enguged with (Jen. Rey
nolds' corps cod that thu Llevcnlh corps took
but little part In tbo battle. Wn will doubtless
have reliable Intelligence to-day.
Arrival ofthe Dodrof Uen.IteynoljB.
The body ofMnJor General John F. Reynolds
killed In the battle near (Juttysburg, arrived
here yesterday, and, after being embalmed
by Mr. Weaver, was taken to the residence of
bis brother-in-law, Mr. (lilderaleeve.
TIIE FIGHTING YESTERDAY.
Large Number of Prisoners Captured
Our Arms Still Successful
We learn, from parties who left (lett)sburg
at noon yctvrday, that everything was pro
urcfslug fuvr rably for the ultimate snecess ot
our arms. Up to that time they assert that
over six thousand prisoners had been captured
and sent to Union Bridge for transportation to
Baltimore. At U o'clock last night a train w Uh
eight hundred prisoners, the first instalment of
those captured, arrived ut the Baltimore depot,
and shortly after Gedcral Schcnck announced,
from his headquarters at the Eutaw House,
that thoso then In Iki'llmoiu and at the Rcla)
House, which would soon bo fa his possession,
atnouuted to twenty-time hundred.
We learn that nuarl) one thousand of these
ftrlsoncrs were captured on Wednesday cubi
ng by the Eleventh corps In their gallant
charge on Longstrcet's corps. They are sjld
to have at Drat slightly faltered, but their olll
eers cried to them to remember Chancellors
vllle, when they rushed luto thn light with a
fury that was Irresistible, and the w hole line of
the enemy gave way before them.
During thu early part of the day yesterday
up to noon, at which hour our luform-iut left,
there had beeu no general luttle, though heavy
sklrmltblug had been going on all the morn
ing, resulting In heavy loss to thu enemy aud
thu capture of nearly live thousand prisoners.
Iu all these skirmishes which vv ere conducted
under the direction of Gen. Meade, our onus
weru entirely successful, but tho memy studi
ously avoided a general engagement, und It
w as thought theru w ould be uouu before to day,
when It was said to be the lutentlon of Gen.
Meadu to press the cm my along tbe wholulltie.
Thu 1 r u delicti aud skill dlspla)ed by Gen.
Meadu In thu management of his army, und the
it rat eg) evluud by him In coping with l.ei,
had already won tliu confidence of his troops,
and his presence along the lines drew forth the
strongest demonstrations of attachment. The
arm) evince 1 a determination to win at all
hazards, and had been strongly Impressed t.j
tlidr ollleers with the dreadlut (Oitseuuc4
that would euue to them and the country If a
disaster should oicurto our arms lu thu coin
ing conflht.
lhe eneui) was rapidly comtnlrutlni; hi
troops jeiiUrday, from thu Cumberland Vallev
towards Cluuihirsburg, an 1 Gin. MuiduV
whole arm) had rescind the Hi Id of battle. II
Gin, Com h presses nu him down the vallt)
wllh his troops from Hurrlshurg, which U c in
tldcntl) expected, wn miy took for a glorious
result.
Artlial i t ltelicl Irlouera
Shortly future. IU o'clock last night, 3S rebel
1 risotiers, Imludingbi) or TO oUUcrs, reached
lljltluioievlt the Western Man I ind railroad,
uu lir cuort of it military guard, coiup istd 01
a detachment of thu Nth rcgularlufeuiry, uuder
Lieut, tivduev W. Cooper. 'Iluv were a t.or-
tlou ot lhe rebel captured In tho engagement
on Weduesda), near (Htt)suurg, renns)lvuiiiHt
und lormed what Is kuowti ut (leu. Archer'
biliradu. In annearauce llnv weru similar to
other prisoners that have paed through this
(It), being dressed romjhl), aud some of them
iieiLgwiiiiouisiioes. iney wiruinurciied from
lioltun Depot alouir Howard aud Baltimore
streets out to Fort Murshal, wheie thy wilt be
quartered suit 1 arriucmcutarii made for the r
transportation South to be exchanged. Gut.
Areiier iiimsuii wus umong tue prisoners, it
Is slated that hu is ji uatlv 11 ot this Mat 1. but
has resided lu the Ninth lor a number of )eurs.
Altirtlulr capture liny were man lied from
(lett)sburg to Vesiiiiliiiir. and hroui;httotlii
ill) lu tlm rulhvn) tars, lhe Saw York o'uu
regiment, Col, Bugli), uUtul lu cseoiiiug
llntu tlirmigh this ell). Hit re will be aunt lur
part) ui about 1,'JUtl prisoners re idling the id)
this moruing, making over 2,000 ol tluvc ap
fund by nur tot tin uear Gettjsburg.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83035143/1863-07-06/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.034,0.419,0.383,0.415,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>FROM THE REBEL INVASION.
WHAT LEE PROPOSES TO DO,
VICTORY OR DESTRUCTION.
The Battle Near Gettysburg.
The Fiercest Fighting of the
The Fiercest Fighting of the War.
Fighting on the 2d and 3d.
NEWS FROM NEW ORLEANS.
NEWS FROM NEW ORLEANS. Brashear City Captured by Rebels.
Large Number of Guns Lost.
LATER FROM THE BATTLEFIELD.
The President Issues an Address
The President Issues an Address of Congratulation.
Great Victory Undoubtedly Won.
6,000 PRISONERS TAKEN.
LONGSTREET REPORTED KILLED.
GEN. SIGEL ORDERED TO BALTIMORE.
THE REBEL INVASION.
HARRISBURG, July 3.
A prominent citizeu of Gettysburg who
left there yesterday on a pass issued by
General Ewell to go to Hide.burg, met
Stuart, Fitz Hugh Lee and Wade Hampton,
with what he estimaei to be 10,000 cav
alry, who were moving ia the direction of
Gettysburg. .Their officer tojd them that
Lee had no intention of leaving Pennsyl
vania, but was going to remain here until
his army was victorious or destroyed.
He arrived here this evening, the enemy
making ne effort to detain him.
A dispatch from Loudon, this morning
statea that yesterday the rebels left Cham
bersburg, taking U.a road in the direction
of Gettysburg, lielore they left they burn
ed '.he depot and workshops belonging to
the railroad. i
Loudon is fourteen miles west of Cham
bersburg.
The enemy also evacuated Shippansburg
in the same direction.
i.
PHILADELPHIA, July 3d.
A special dispatch to Forney's Press, dat
ted Hanover, 1 P. M., via Washington 3J,
says this morning our forces opened on
5000 rebels who advanced on the field at
daybreak for the purpose of pillaging our
dead. The rebels hastily retreated.
The fight thus far has been the most ter
rific of the war. Loss On both sides heavy.
A desperate battle rages.
A Special to the Times, datd battle field,
near Gettysburg, 3 A. M July 31. At the
close of oiy lt dispatch at 4:30 P. M
yesterday the enemy had opened heavy
attack by artillery on our left. A mass
ing of their main strength on -otr left
flank, which covered Frederick road, with
the determination to crush1 it. So' intent
was the enemy on this purpose that every
Other pivtof tlx. otm left alon.-
The fighting was most desperate on both
sides.
We had against this great onslaught of
the enemy the 2d, 3d and oih corns. The
3d and 5th corps joined hands and fought
heroically.' Thi 2d corps ably supported
them and at the eame time held its two
position. One division of the 1st corps
was also engaged.
The fighting was so furious that neither
party took many .prisoners. Wo captured
about 000 in one or two cnarges.
Losses, considering duration of tight,
were more than usually heavy en both
ides. Many oZ our gallant officers have
fallen. j i l
Later in the evening General Meade
called a council of Corps Commanders, and
it was resolved to continue the fight as
long as any one was left to fight.
WASHINGTON, July 4—2 A. M.
The latest off cial information recehed
from General Meade is up to 12:30 Friday
noon. All was quiet up to that hour. Con
siderable firing, both pf artillery and in
fantry had taken pUceon various parts of
our line up to that time, and several hun
dred prisoners had been taken eince morn,
ing.
PHILADELPHIA, July 3.
Tbe Washington Star has the following
Major Ueneral Sigel has oeen ordered
to report to Gen. Couch at HarriBburg for
duty.
From a private letter from J orfolk, dat
ed the 1st, we learn that some 1,200 or
1,500 rebels have made their appearance in
Princess Anne county, with the dcsirn it
is supposed of making a raid into Norfolk.
Considerable excitement is represented as
existing in orfolk ia caasequenoe. j
SHIPPENSBURG, July 3.
s are concentrating near
Gettysburg. 8tuarfs cavalry were on their
way there yesterday.
Longstreet a and lull s corps are J-'ud to
be nenung on tne rigntr or Jvwcu e- front.
0,000 prisoners have thus far beei sent to
the rear.
Lee's forces, except a' guard, have left
Green Castle. AH naiet at Carlisle. The
enemy are falling back.
Chamberebnrg is notbnrtied, only build
ings belonging to the,. railroad destroyed.
Tbe death of Longstreet, brought by
rebel prisoners yesterday, is confirmed by
prisoners token this morning.
NEW YORK, July 4th.
The following is the latest:
BALTIMORE, July 3—10 P. M.
Special to Herald A special messenger
from Gen. Meade to Gen. Echenck, brings
news from Getty abarg op to 1 o'clock th'S
P. M. Gen. Meade had then driven' the
rebels four miles north and west from their
position of yesterday and was still follow
ing.. We have taken 1500 prisoners; they
are on their way to tliis city. The victory
is undoubtedly ours.
HANOVER, July 3.
Special to Tribune The most terrifio
battle of the war has taken place. We have
Longstrreta prisoner sure.
WASHINGTON, July 4. 10:10 A. M.
The following has jost been received
HKADQUAKTEaS ASJIT OF JPOXOMAC,
.July b:'40. M.n
To Major General Hatlcck. be
The enemy opened at one in the aft ftp
noon from abottt lod tfuns concentrated
upon my left centre, continuing without
inteminiQi tot abot three hours, at the
expiraSon of which time he assaulted say
left and centre twice, being upon both oc
casions handeosaeiyTeputoed with severe
loss to him. tearing in our hands nearly
3,000 prisoners, among whom :s Brigadier
Ueneral Armistead and many Colonels and
officers o lesser rank.
The enemy left many dead upon the field
and a la-ge number or wounded in our
hands. The loss upon our side has
been considerable. Maj. Gen. Hancock
and Brig. Gen. Gibbon were wounded.
After the repelling of the assault, indi
cations leading to the belief that the enemy
might be withdrawing, caused an; armed
reconnotsance from the left and the enemy
found to be in force. At the- present
hour all is quiet. My cavalry have
been eneaved all dav on both flanks of
the enemy harrassing and vigoroasly at-
tackins him with reat ucce8S. tith-
tndiDg 4bey encountered superior num-
hers' both f eavalrr and infantry. The
bers: both -of cavalry and infantry
GEO. G. MEADE
j, Major General Commanding.
PROCLAMATION BY THE PRESIDENT.
Washington, July, 10 A.M. Tbe Presi
dent announces to the country that tie news
from the Army-of- the r Potomac, to 30 r.
of tbe 34 is each ss to cover tbe Army with
the highest honor, and vromtiei a great sue
cms to the cause of the Ucion. .lie claims the
condolence of all for the many gallant ones
who have (alien, and that for this h especi
ally desires on this day, that He whr.se. will,
not ours, should ever be dune, be everwhere
remembered and reverenced with piofoand-

est gratitude.
ABRAHAM LINCOLN.
FROM NEW ORLEANS.
NEW YORK, July 3.
?5ra?tea7 (?ity was captured by tie-rebels
en the 2ilch, with all the troops, artil
lery, c, there. Our loss 1,000 men, in
cluding a eamp of t00 convalescequi, and
18 cr 20 pieces of heavy calibre. j
Our outposts have fallen back to Butte
Station, 20 miles from New Orleans. A
party of workmen are repairing the rail
road bridge over the Manchas,. which was
captured by the rebels.
A correspondent says, as far as ew Or
leans is concerned, the city Is seonre. "The
guu3 ox the Beet command tne city, and
General Emery bas disposed of his com
mand so that he can effectually defend
every point.
t torn Port Hudson there is nothing im
portant. The bombardment continues,
and another assault was expected on the
7th.
FROM WASHINGTON.
WASHINGTON, July 4.
baitle at Gettysburg last niht wa-1 extremely
lien- auu frtuMxira. ilea y ana aetermiaea as
?ault wtro made by the rebels wl-eh w?re Eal
lantlv met hy otir troopH. Tins morning at day-
lit the contei-t waa ppinleaiy renewea, our
rnv drove tre em-mv who id torn drove ours.
litintf t-'in'' de-.-iM.r:ttelv pevere, and the
licnwat, pprbiUily, dnring tbe war.
Pripo.ier ri port Lonir-'tr.-e killed and this
seema to lie ronii rmed y lu-i jntelligeaee.
General Aook of Aw lork was among
the kil'ed. General Sickles was wounded
and hia right leg amputated on the field.
General Barksdale of the rebel armj was
killed, and his body is in our posset sion.
The latest intelligence received here was
up to eleven o'clock to-day.
home rebel mail matter was captured
and a letter found from Jeff. D-via to Lee,
aying that he could send him no more
v roups as Richmond was seriously threat
ened, j</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030213/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.753,0.757,0.253,0.274,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Gen. Meade's Congratulatory Address.
d.vatches fiom Gen. Mea
{AE GREAT VICTORY.
gar Whele Army in Motion.
New-Dork
gen, Meade’s IHleadquarters Near
Frederick,
Vor. XXIIL....N® 6.944.
NEW-YORK,
The Rebel Army still Struggling to
THE BATTLE-FIE
Escape,
dur Cavalry Reaping Harvests of
Stragglers.
WEY TE SER
Destruction of Bridges on the
Potomac,
pro
HOVEMENTS OF AUXILLIARY UNION FORCES.
Gen, Couch Marching on the Rebel Flank.
NESE EN
Gen. French Moving to Intercept Them.
a
STRONG HOPES FOR A WHOLESALE CAPTURE.
nism
Pp
Our Whole Army in Motion.
Wasminaron, Monday, July 6. 1863.
Our whole army is in motion, and the highest
Lopes are entertained thor but a smell portion of
Gen. Lee's army will be le to reach Virginia.
—_—
Mlonde's Ecadquariers Near Frederick.
Bavrivoxe, Monday, July 6, 1863
Brig.-Gen. H. Haupt, having the direction of the
communicating corps, resciied here at midnight las!
pight, and had an interview with Gen. Schenck.
Uy to 1 o'clock on Sunday, when Gen. Haupt lef:
the headquarters of Gen, Meade, the enemy was
fleeing. Meade's headquarters were at Creagers
town, Md., some 15 mdes north of Frederick, and
to-day he is, no doubt, at Frederick.
Gen. Halleck is in possession of several recent
and from ther tone
de ares that Lee has suffered a digastrons defeat,
‘1 le following has Leen posted at Headqnarters:
Advices from the army up to 2 p. m. on Sunday,
ptute that Gen. Meade's Headquarters were at Crea-
ger~iown last night, and wers to be at Fraderick to-
day.
Gen. Meade hee telegraphed that Lee's army is
pelreating.”
eat
Gon. Kilpatrick nt Work Destruction ef
a Potomac Eridge.
Frepexick, Md., July 8, 1863.
A courier from Gettysburg to-day reports that
Gon, Meade's army this morning advanced gix miles
beyond the battie-fleld, and wae advancing when
the courier left, The Rebels retired without giving
butile. To-day brigade of Rebel cavalry, upon a
ye connoissancs, advanced to Mechuniestown, 15 miles
frown Wrederick, Col. Kilpatrick's cavalry attacked
them vigorously, when they retired after a feeble re-
pistance, Mechauicstowa is to the left end rear of
Goo. Meade's army, and seven miles south of Ewe
mictteburg.
Major Cole's Independent Maryland Cavalry to-
day destroyed the trectle-work bridge over the Po
toiase, need by tue Rebels in crossivg their cavalry.
We party who wade the dash yesterday ia this v)-
vinty crossed there, One of the prisoners captured
a: “uliing Waters was a courier from Stuart to Lee,
ii tad on Lis persou dispatches for Lee. Not be-
fog sesrclied immediately ater his capture, be de-
ptioyed thems on his way here. He gays the ord-
riuce train destroved by Major Foley belonged tod
Melanue's Rebel division, and was sent buck because
tev had armnnition in abundance aud wore than
they could trameport.
tnm———— i
Later from Hurvisburg—Couch’s Troops
©pervating on the Fehels,
Haxissone, Mondsy, July 1293,
Gen. Couch has pushed forward all his cfiagtive
force to cogperate with and join the Army of the
Y otomac, and 18, by order of Gen. Meade, pushing
the regiments forward us r«pidiy as they are organ.
ised. The conutry muy reat nsal iu bis power.
wii the enemy, aud siding in the glorious result.
iis advance is already iu contact
lee, wo far us known, holds all the passes in the
Routh Moautain leading inw the Cumberlaud Valley
fiom Gettysourg. This is done for the purposs of
rew.oving Lis traing, now rapidly pushing for Vir.
ginia. es 1 Um
Tlie mwoantaio ie full of disorganized troops frou
lees army, aud they are arriving within our lines
every bour,
INNS
KAZERS)/(W
oF

s
ral times enabled the Commanding General to
rapidly concentrate his whole force at the point of
After the battle-field came into our possession, s
private soldier who had been wounded in the foo
was found lying in the grass, under a bush; he had
wiped his gun and taken off the lock to clean it.
When found, he was inthe act of putting it toe
gether again. To the question—what he was doing
there 1 he replied, I am getting ready for another
pop. Ihave two boxes of cartridges left.”
The citizens of Adams and York Counties are send
ing in large quantities of supplies for the sick and
wounded, and all the farm-houses and barns in the
neighborhood of the battle-field are used as bose
pitals. One of your correspondents has evinced
commendable zeal in the practice of bis profession
and at the same time serving the Government.
On Thursday Mr. Byington discovered that a telee
graph instrument and operator were at Hanover; be
procured a hand-car from the President of the rail
road and sent an expedition down the road to repair
the wire, This accomplished, a dispatch was send
through to Tux TrRiBUNE announcing the progress
of the battle in advance of all other lines.
President Lincoln was in the Washington office a8
the time and was told of the passage of the message
over the wires. It was then 10 o'clock Thursday
night, and no dispatch had yet been received ad
Washington.
The President instructed the operator to inquire
of the operator at Hanover who Byington is? Mr.
Byington replied by referring the President to meme
ber of his Cabinet, and also telegraphed to Mr. Lin-
coln that a railroad was in running order to within
six miles of the battle field, and recommended thad
trains be sent for the wounded. The President re
plied that a train would be sent next day.
It has been remarked that never in the history of
this army was there so little straggling as during tke
week of march and battle just closed. Gen. Mead's
order on discipline has had a good effect. J. R. 8,
On Friday night, after the battle had closed and
all was quiet, several general officers were standing
1 on Cemetery Hill, discussing the events of the daye
One of the officers remarked, that he did not like
the extreme silence of the enemy, it looked as if hg
was practicing some strategy. Well, replied Gen.
Howard, it is evident that Gen. Meade is in a cone
dition to detect and prepare for any new scheme
Lee may develop. A very eiguificant nodding off
heads told that this was degree of confidence in
the ability of the Commanding General not always
enjoyed by the Army of the Potomac. J RS

The Destruction of the Crorsing at Wile
liamsport— Defeat of Rebel Cavalry-
Occupation of a Gap in South Mountain
Gen. Meade Re-enforced by Gens. Fose
ter nud Peck, with 18,000 Men—Gen.
French Taking Positions in the Moune
tains--Troops Forwarded from Harriss
burg —Lee’s Escape Considered Impose
sible.
From Qur Special Correspondent.
Harnissure, Pa, July 1863.
Intelligence has reached this place that yesterday
Maj.-Gen. Freuch sent a force toward Williames
port, which was successful in capturing and destroy
ing the pontoon train of the Rebels. The guard,
consisting of a lieutenant and only 13 men, were
taken. Their cavalry attempted to capture one of
our traine, but inforwstion having been given to oue
forces, Gen, Kilpatrick, with Stahel’s Cavalry, ate
tacked und ronted thew, and also drove them from
pass in South Mountainwhich he (Gen.K.) now occu
ples. Gens. Foster and Peck are known to have are|
rived with 18,000 men, and effected Junctiuu Wiiky
Gen. Meade's forces. Gen. Freuch has fallen back,
and occupies the gaps in the mouutuins, and aiso
guaids the fords, The recent rains have caused the
river to rise considerubly. Gen. Lee has every many
in the field, even taking bis train guards. The are
rival of our reéoforcements struck terror to the
hearts of the Rebels, who are reported making their
way back. Troops from this place are being sent
forward, and everything looks favorable. The
Philadelpbia City Troop, Capt. Randall, who bave
been doing good service in the adjoining counties,
arrived hero yesterday.
Latest,—Trustworthy Intelligence has been ree
ceived here that Gen. Meade has captured 25,000
The above sketch of the battlefied at Gettysburg a8 topographical engineers, und ie, therefore, in ull very short lines in recuforcing the point of attack. uesiged and substantially maintained, The eleve- The Excitement in
The wood in The enemy was compelled to march his infantry in tion occupied by the Rebel artillery was much
the rear of bis artillery a distance of several miles in lower than that on which the National troops were
pussiug from one wing to the other. The positions posted. The position was well calculated for de-!
was made by ore of our correspondents, who care. €88€ntial points, absolutely correct,
fully examined the topography of the. country and
thoroughly understood the situation; it wae submit-
ted for correction to
a
several Fioersls experienced
front of the left wing is where Longstreet and Hill
formed, preparatory to charging on the left. Ewell's
troops occupied the woods on the left, By reference
to the mep it will be seen that Meade moved over
Jones's Brigade of cavalry, lefantry and artillery, fresh militia are elaughtering and capturing the
near Monterey on the Hagervtown and Gettysburg
road, He captured 300 prisoners, including 200
wounded officers. He also took 150 wagons, and
two guns. The wagous were destroyed,
The Rebels were completely surprised, and unable
to make any eerions resistance,
Firing was heard in the direction of the enemy's
retreating column yecterday afteraoon,
It was probably cxused by eur cavalry and flying
batteries pressing on the enemy's rear.
Haxoven, Pa., July 5, 1863,
Tliere was a cavalry fight to-day, four miles south
i ve troops ander Gen. Pierce, formerly Milroy's
co. wand, arrived yesterday wt Chambersburg, and
poshied oo wo Greencusile, where they captured Ju
prisoners, 2 wagons losded with plupder, und 3
The prisoners were stragglers
maxing their way to the Potomac, in compuny with
Wa.ou
A diepateh from Chambersburg this morning seys
is heard in the direction of Hazes
proces of artillery.
Lialus.
tha heavy Lr
town. Jtis believed that Geo. French has made wu
attack In that vicinity, on the traius moving toward
“r
Yirgin.a.
Gen. Caweron left this morning, in compony with
a nub
There is uc further vews from the Army of the
Potoiuae.
i
us, for Grettysburg,
rof Sig
er UL DUT LL
Advance of Gen, Coucl’s Forces Gov, Cure
tin wants Yiore Troops Forward Fle is
unzious te Pulverize the Fnemy.,
PuiLaprrrata, Monday, Juty 6, 1663,
The following telegram has becn received frou,
tbe Governor:
YHARRIEBURG, July 5, 186%
“Ud R Biwpen Rorants, Philade pha
“The RIY COMING ded by Gen, Couch is advance.
fog iu force, knd is hkely to render important eer.
Yice, We shonld push troops torward, and ther
should lua uo delay. Gen. Couch bis telegraphed
Gen, Dana to that effect,
“The State ir responding with go much genero:i-
ty thst we cannot afford further delay inthe city. 1
Sus eatinhied that the Hebel anny i870 our powers, i
We cau ket promptly and vigorously, Much may
de) end on the strength of Coneh's wry. The cros.-
ing of tae Potomac prepared by the enemy ir de.
stroyed, und be iw ghort of smmumtion. Send for
Ward cumpavies mustered nto eervice to-day wud
W-uerrow, We must make np 40,000 men. le
prompt, aud muke everything yield to the presence
of Licops Lere, A. G, Curtis,”
The Cavalyy Attacks on the Flying Kebels—
Cuapiure of a Train and a Lurge Nuni-
ber of Prisoners.
Cruavensrows, Md., Monday, July 6, 1063.
of Gettysburg, between our forces and the rear of
Lee's army, which is now supposed to be on the re-
(treat to Hagerstown,
Our cavalry continue to bring in large numbers of
Rebel prisoners.
i
Gen. Mende’s Address to his Army.

Ha vquanTens AuMy oy Fovsuac,
NEBAK URTTYABUKG, July 4, 1608.
GeseraLl Onpenrs, No. 03, General, in behalf of the country, thunks the Army
j of the Potomac for the glorioue result of the recent
operatone. Our enemy, superior in numbers, and
fished with the pride of successful invasion, ate
ten ted to overcome or destroy this army. Baflled
1nd defeated, he has now withdrawn from the con-
TLe privations und fatigues the army has en-
lured, and the heroic courage and gallantry it dis-
pleved, will be matters of history to be ever remen-
tot
Te
bered,
Oonrtask is not yet secomplished, and the Com-
-nanding General looks to the army for greater efforts
to drive from our soil every vestige of the presence
of the invader,
It ie right and proper that we should, on guitable
occasions, return our grateful thanks tothe Almighty
Disposer of events, that in the goodness of His prov-
dence, He Las thought fit to give victory to the
cause of the just.
By command of Mujor-Gen. MEADE,
8. WILLIAMS, A. A. G.
vc
The Perfect Rout of Lee.
Larvimonr, Monday, July 6—Noon,
If wy news last night was glorious I do not know
what to cali it now. Prisoners are coming in here
by the thousands. Over 8,000 have already arrived
here, und Ge. Schenck lias orders to prepare to re-
ceive 20,000 more already captured,
The road alovg the line of the Rebels’ retreat ir
strewn with wagons, cannon, small arms, and camp
cquipage, abandoned by the enemy. The Rebels
auhitch the Lorses and males from their loads of
It is reported Liere by officers that on Saturday [cannon and stores, and, swounting them, push for
Mernoon our cavalry under Kilpatrick intercepted [the river.
retreatiog usin of Rebel wagons, guarded by
Couch bag formed a junction with Meade, apd the
graybacks by regiments and brigades. Not one-
tenth of Lee's army can possibly get back to Dixie
Ly the route they came, IT 18 NOT A DEFEAT FOR
LEE, BUT IT 18 A TOTAL ROUT,
The following is the bulletin just issued at head-
quarters:
During Friday night the enemy commenced to
retreat rapidly toward Greencastle and Hagers.
town, Gen, Meade following rapidly in pureuit, and
baving the entire cavalry force operating in the
enemy's rear,
Up to 12 o'clock on Saturdey many thousands of
prieciers hud been captured and sent to the rear,
with a large number of cannon and wagons. The
rout of the encmy is most complete and disastrous.
Gen. French will intercept his flying eolumue ut
Hagerstown, and Maryland, as well as Pennsyl-
vania, will soon be rid of the invaders.
the Encmy—The
Bridges Destroyed.
Near Gerryssuna, July 5, 1063,
The Rebels have retreated toward the Potomac,
Their gkirmishiers were driven in last night, and a
small cavalry force, probably their rear guard,
pateed through Emmetwburg this moruing abou.
daylight.
Our troope have been engaged all day in burying
the dead, relieving the wounded, aud collecting
siall-armeg, many thousands of wlrich belonged to
the Rebels.
The Rebel pontoon bridge at dam No. 4 has been
destroyed by our cavalry, almost unopposed, and
our cavalry, at the last advices, had gone up to
Williamsport to destroy the two bridges there.
Ouher preparatiovs are in progress to intercept
Gen. Lee's passage of the Potomac, and our army is
already in motion,
So much time, however, has elapsed since Gen.
Lee commenced to withdraw Lis forces from our
frout that his advance may bave reached Williams.
port in time to croes before we can prevent it.
Gen. Lec yesterday paroled whout 2,000 Union
prisoners, They were received by Gen. Couch,
It is not true, as stated, that Gen. Longstreet was
captured and died within our lines.
Gen. Hunt, Chief of Artillery, was not wounded.
Both of these last reports were apparently well
authenticated, and fully believed.
Frrorniek, July 5p. mm.
A report prevails to-day that the Rebel wrmy is
retreating, in a disorganized condition, down the
Boonsboro Valley, trying to reach the Potomac.
Prisoners are brought in by our scouts barefooted,
suffering from want of food.
Retreat of Pontoon
of the troops were changed us the exigencies re-
quired. The location ou she map is the oue at first
fense, and forced the enemy to fight at great diead-
vantage.
prisoners and 118 guus. It is believed that Lee's
retreat is impossible.
neu i prem—
Philadciphia—The Ene
listment of Defenders—The People Fully
arroused nt Last—The uppearance of
HMarrisburg—' Tho Attack om Carlisle—
Gen. Stahel’s Cavalry.
Hauxissono, Friday, July 2, 1863,
S——— {or this place, one began to have some idea of the
Passing through Phuadelphia, yesterday, en route

going toward the river, and many taking refuge inl bears on his person six wounds from musket balls, oxcitement caused by the invasion of Pennsylvania,
he mountains, The heavy rains of yesterday ren-
der the river too high to croes at the fords,
Yesterday forty Rebels, of the 12th Virginia Cav-
nlry, dashed down the Harper's Ferry road, driving
in our pickets to the outskirts of Frederick. A party
of cavalry and infantry pursued and captured four
of the Rebel party, but the others escaped,
Major Foley, of the Fourteenth Penneylvania
Cavalry, with a small detachment, yesterday de.
word the Rebel pontoon bridge of boats over the
Potomac at Falling Waters, four wiles from Wil-
lintusport; the bridge was fastened to the Virginia
#ide and swung down the river to prevent the cor-
rent carrying it away. A guard of three handred
Rebels, who were encamped on the Marylund side,
wan attacked by Mujor Foley, routed, and sixteen
prisoners, four horses, two mules, and two sutlers’
wagons captured and brought here lust night.
Major Foley destroyed five wagon-loads of am-
munition by running it into the river, Lieut. Shoop,
of the 14th Pennsylvanian Cavalry, swam the river
under fire from the Rebels on the Virginia side, got
u boat, brought it to this side, and the party then
crossed on the boar, set fire to the pontoon bridge
and completely destroyed it. Major Foley did not
lode man, An important capture was made at
Greencastle, on Thursday, by Capt. Dablgren of
Pleasanton’s Cavalry. (Phila. Iuquirer, 6th,
wd
Kilpatrick After Staart.
Barrimons, July 5, 1863,
In consequence of information that Stuart wes
aboot to make u raid upon our rear this afternoon,
Kilpatrick was sent out on our right. Some cannon
ading was heard, but up to 9 o'clock he had not re-
turned to camp. Should the enemy be found here
in the morning, the 4th of July will reccive additional
cause for commemoration,

Tho Losses.
HEADQUARTERS ARMY OF THE Pocus,
July 5, 1663.
The Rebel General Pender is wounded. Gen.'s
Kemper and Johnson, Rebels, are killed. The Rebel
losses are estimated at 20,000. Our troops are in
the highest spirits. Gen. Butterfield’s wound is
nore severe than was expected, but is not at all
serions. The Rebels abandoned their killed and
wounded. T. B,
lp
Hucidents on the Battle-field near Gettys-
barg—Gallant Conduct of Troeps—Ad-
vantage of Position—Heavy N.osses—
Tribune Enterprise—No Ntraggling.
From Our Special Correspond
GeTTYsBUKG, Pa. Saturday, July 4, 1063,
After the Brigade from the llth Corps, com
manded by Col. Noble of the 17th Connecticut, bad
expelled the enemy's skirmishers and eharpshoot.
ers from Gettysburg, the several regiments marched
through the streets with colors flying and the baud
playing the National Aire.
The prisougre yepors the roads filled witk Lelgle
Qus tioops foupd Gew. Darlow in the town; Le
one in the groin is very severe. It is believed be The streets were thronged with people eagerly dise
will recover. Mie. Barlow is here ministering 10 cugsing the ‘latest news” and auxiously awaiting
her husband. the urrival of “Still Later” intelligence. Following
jen. Schimmeifenig escaped capture by reeorting drummers of all sizes vigoronely beating drums of
to a dodge whorthy of the sharpest Yankee, When diffrent and questionable sound, were the new ree
he found his retreat cut off, Le seized the coat of a crults who had come aud were still coming forward
private and buttoned it olosely over bis uniform; he “for the (mmergency,” as one of the plackards hag
was knocked down and rum over by a gang of it.” It is needless to say that the recraite were raw
Rebels who were after plunder. He then stumbled doug With mung Loweeats J‘ vie SVidant tab
away ioto a celiar, and lay there concealed and or us Ci wig Ininly 3 en
without food for two days, but when he heard the
boys playing Yankee Doodle” in the streets, he
thought it eate to come out, Xe is now in command
of his brigade and ready for work.
The 11th Corps lost in killed, wounded and migs-
ing, 4,060 men, The Ist Corps loss foots up nearly
5,000, The 12th Corps lost in killed and wounded,
973, missing 242, 17 officers killed and 43 wounded.
One regiment, the ¥nd Mass., in Slocum’s Corps,
lost 11 officers in a charge, yet when this division
was repulsed the regiment fell buck in perfect order
and each soldier in his place.
Sharpshooting has become a serious service in bat-
tle. 300 men from our brigade were shot in the
rifle-pits on Friday, by a balt a dozen of the enemy's
shurpshooters concealed in a brick house in the
suburbs of Gettysburg. The house might have been
destroyed, but in doing this many others in the
town would have been damaged; it is a question
however, whether the whole town is worth the
lives it cost to save it.
The 2ud Brigade of she 3d Division, 2nd Corps
numbering 2.500 men, lost half its numbers in battle,
and the 20d Brigade, 2ud Division of the same Corps
in the lust charge of the enemy on Friday evening,
captured from the enemy double their own number
in prisoucrs, including Gen. Armistead and five bat-
tle-flugs, all within thirty-five paces of the 20d
Corps butteries.
The Rebel cavalry was in constant trouble; if it
appearcd Leyond tke protection of the infantry lines
on either flank, it wus charged into by the National
cavalry, und gent pell-mell back to its biding-place;
aud if too far within its own lines, the horses were
demorulized by the explosion of shells, The com-
mand wes of no service to the enemy, but tho men
soon became a reproach in the eyes of their com-
rades.
Perhaps one of the most important features of the
line of battle was the facilities it afforded to euch
portion to re-cuforce any point of attack. The
enemy was cotupelled to march from seven to nine
miles in going from ove wing to the other, whereas
three miles ov the diameter of a circle was the dis-
tauco between Mende's extreme infantry flanks.
This circumstsnce quve greus advantage, aud seve-
that they regarded the matter as a pleasant epicode
in life and considered playing soldier a fine thing,
At the rooms of the Union lLesgue, on Cheetuus
street, something of real earnestness and work was
manifest, Eighty men from one factory were there
asgembled, who had come forward to offer thelr sere
vices, and lives if need be, to aid fn driving the ine
vaders trom the Keystone State. ‘They were ade
dressed Ly the Hon. Wm. D. Kelly, who iv a few
ver Som¥fiimentory yeuarLs introduced Alujor-Gews
Staliel, a guest of the League, to the comjany. The
(General was heartily reccived by all, but, ae Judge
Kelly remarked, being a fighting and not a waiking
man,” was excused from making a speech. The
afternoon train brought Gov, Curtin from Harries
burg, and a large concourse of people assembled 1a
front of the Continental to pay their respects to theig
(Governor, who addressed the assemblage iu a stire
ring speech. ‘I'he businessof recruiting goes rapidly
forward, with what success may be inferred from
the statement that the regimens started by the Union
League bas already increased to the dimensions of
brigade, The oity was alive with rumors of every
possible description, many of which of the moss
exaggerated and impossible sort, were readily be.
lieved by the credulous.
The firet object in Harrisburg which greeted my
eyes us I looked from the car window io the dim
gray of morning, was a man in citizens’ clothes, with
cross-belt, cartridge-box, aud musket, doing gusrd
duty, My mind instantly reverted to the days
'76,und I drew a picture of sel(-sacrifibing putriotisng
and devotion of which the honest person before me
was the immediate subject, 1 have since learned
from citizens themselves that while numbers come
forward to aid in the defense of the city, there is
lacking that strong determination to do or die which
alone gives form and weight to such an wprising.
Agu we find the “playing soldier’ predominant.
Tue efforts being made to hg and disciplice
the recruits meet with but little co-operation.
wish to do justice to all. There are of course nume
bers of true men who are guided by the right princie
ples, and who strive by their zeal to overcome the
wasterly inactivity of others. Dut thud terrible
earnestness of purpose which should be seen unmisge
takubly on every ince, and which alone will end
this war, is sadly lacking, Many of the citizens fled
their homes at the cry of danger. Others, aa a pre
cautionary measure, moved their goods, but ree
muined themselves, Most of the stores are closed,
and the principal ocenpation of the many to
be to listen to every item of news and repeat it with
embellishments of their own. The scenes at the
bridge, over which no civilian, not even de
ents, are allowed to cross to the other side, are very
seo Bighih Page.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038443/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.133,0.764,0.203,0.22,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>UNION VICTORY!
The Gettysburg Battles.
J A
j encountered the Rebels, io Urge foroe, I
B)dcr Lingstreei and Hill, nwr Gettys
burg, Adams Co., Pa. Reynolds wis
killed, by a eharp-shootsr, but his loss
was not made known to his men, who
stood ibeir ground. Gen. Howard of tbe
1 1 lb Corps soon en-Wed and assumed
commaud, but the Corps were forced to
take s'jpport on a hill tomb of the town,
hare the, rested. Roth Corps fought
bravely. Geo. Paul was killed, and many
j good R.gllnBnul gffiaerii
,h. k. n.h.. A.m.
""6 -61
(except tbe Sixth) under God. Meade,
came op from the South.
ti i o.i n. T i 1
l (5
West, made a fisree attack upon tbe Un
ion line with all bis strength, but was re
pulsed at every point, tbe Union forces
gaining grouud. Oar Gen. Zook was
killed; Sickles had a leg shot off, and
Harlow, Graham and Warren were woun
ded. The Rebel Gen. Rarkadale's dead
body wsa left io onr hands he was the
Congressman from Mississippi who aided
Keitt ia his attack npon Grow, and whose
scalp" (wig) was taken by I'oUer ia the

Friday, 3d mat., the battlo wis I

I with decided advantage to the Uni
renewed,
antage to the Union arms,
and d re ad fa 1 tUughter of Rebels. Long-
street is repotted dead by some, and a
prisoner by others.
Saturday, 4tb inat., it is stated the Reb
els began a retrograde movement. It is
expected that Couch and tha Militia will
press them from the North. If (as repor
ted) tbe Potomac has risen considerably
by late rains, Lee's Army may be out off
and captnrcd, or dispersed.
These battles were tbe most sanguin
ary shock of arm a our continent ever saw,
or perhaps tbe world since Wsterloo.
The Armies must have numbered near
100,000 each of ihe best, most long
trained men, meeting an fair ground, well
supplied, full of hops, and desperate with
high resolve.
Our own little county of Union we sup
pose was represented by Companies of
Evans (Erst Merrill's,) Oongal (first Crot
lar's,) M'Call's (first T.Cbambcrlin's,) and
thoee first commanded by Roush, Church,
aud Tale six Companies, and individuals
in others. Iougal and Evans were in lit
Corps,which suffered most. Thoe who In
this crisis full, were in tbe noblest cause,
en a field that may decide the Gigantic
Struggle of the Age between Liberty and
Despotism.
fcaTMij. John D. Mosser wrote, Thurs
day, that he had escaped with his hone
killed and a scratch .on one leg, but he
feared Maj. Jiiomas Cuamberlin was
among tbe many slain on Wednesday.
His name does not appear in the list yet
published. Rut if he is taken, no more
beloved, patrioticaccomplished youth has
laid down his life on his country's altar.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024738/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.091,0.888,0.296,0.321,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>I AT IST FROM THE NORTH.
THE tI UK AT BATTLE ATOETTYH
BUBO.
tbe Pish* el Ttioritliii—Tl:e Ilncili* Hriiewed
fhsee anlter lieiierala Killci ami Four
Weaadrd M,l> Csafodsaam Prlaeit
irsTakam fbS •ulndera ea llol.i fr.»tiy»
-IU, k
We bavft rtieived from Hai. Hubert ttald,
(Vamissi'itier of l.xcbange,New Vorkpapere
al tb* M, 'td and -ttb inula. '1 be new aof the
r title ol OettyeburK diiUin courideTably from
ir.e lirst Yankee ecconnte. When tbey were
r.rai Mashed they wire tome dietauce leynnd
tixityalmig, but were driven out, uud are now
lh!* eJe of the town. Tiie following die
psrobes in Uie New York World give an se*
count of the prsgTBBS of the fighting, 'ihe
t; *i contains 'met* from the sdfoielrspest
of ti*u Memle, srbisb wes all the War Oe
partmssd would allow to be telegraphed from
Wellington to tbe Northern papers i
Wathungton. .Inly lid—An "fficiat dispatch
Mac leeetvad ibis afiernoou frcm Majwr-Qsm
arul Maade, dated liea'lcjnarti'rH, army of the
Potemas, 11 o'clock P. duly 'nd, which
saj
i',i» enemy attacked me about I P. M. ibis
tlby, au.!, hfier oil© of the ncverest i-nnteata of
tbs WHr, wui reput'ped al ail points. VVe have
tf-'-'l ..:"!-li-r,.:■ ly iv killed Btui Wounded.
Aiu.ng the former are lirigudhr Generals
Paul i.i.i Z ick, an.l among the woouiled Oen
ttali ure S: liles, Harlow, tlrnliam, and War
.in, aUghtiy. We have taken a large number
i risoaeta."
|ißi u-in nrrarc m
iVaahiugten, .luly 3.—A Inter dicpatch hae
i, P .ri ineiveil from Majos (l*ueral Meade,
dated B clock this morning, which ertys i
"The ucticiu corouient'ed ugain at early day
light up v varions parte oi th* line. The we
my. ti-'is far, have ma.le no iuipreeaion upon
■y poaMea. AH acconnts agree in placing
their -v i. iiiii.v here Piisoueis report that
I niifHireet's and A P. Hill's forces were
macli m.Hire.l yesterday, aud ba.l many vene-s
rai aabmss kille.l (leu. llarksdale, of Miss
ie de-i-\ His tanly is witbtti cm hues We
tiv i'.uH far about I t.ihi priKonsis, and a
mmH i ....I.i.i yet to i.c suirted
sssrsTeaei oasot thi nomine.
lletrrtoborg,AnXy d—A. p omiii-iut ci.izsu
al Hettyebuig, who left the.eynfterilay moru
iii? Un s pa*s issued by Oen. Kwell la go to
lleidlebiirg, met Smart, Kitzhugh h?e, and
•Tada llamotou, wßb what be estimated at
10,000 ivhli v, who were moving iv the direc
Uou ef Gettysburg. Tbeir officers t»ld him
lual Lee bad uo intention of leaving l'euasvl
t.ti.m. but was going to remain here uuul ins
aimy wks destroyed or victotious. The gen
i i-.iimi arrived here this eveuiug, tbe enemy
asking uo effort to retain itim.
Two milii.-.iimen from Snnjnebanna county
were killed Ibis evening at t?amp Curtiu by
I
A dispute li from Leadna tiiie morniug stales
fiitl yeeterdav the reliele left Cliambersburg,
tho road iv tbe .lirectiou of Gettysburg.
Betete leaving tbey bnrued tbe depot and
worktops belonging to tbe railroad. Londou
is fowtsea miles wet! of Cliambersburg.
ThesßSSßf also evacuated SblppeusburgyeH
imi'tv. mnvirig iv the same direction.
hveryitiiug «oes to show that c baa bis
whole hi my cciiiceutrated between Cash town
sill QsUjsßaig.
The train that left Carlisle at geveu o clock
tiiis evening brought down twenty-fenr rebel
.lei-eiicm who had come iv from the moun
lafoa They knew nothing about tbe result of
lbs Lttitle, I ut state that both urmies are tight
liiv tn h h -n-Hi desperation
Kiriirg whs heard from daylight up to three
a cluck this afternoon, at different points dowu
tu* river.
H*i ii i Kirn H BiaaOiTTYsaoaa, f
Thursday, t Thi pM.
Lite .i.it has beeu mamt up to the preseut
ui.'iueui Ihe euemy are now massing v heavy
lone oh our ieft, ami have just begau the at
t« t wuh attillery. Tbe probability is tbat a
levere battle will be Knight before dark.
Tin- it iel sharpshooters have beeu annoy
tug ii,i l.Hiieina at.l men all day from tbe
tUstiWsuf the 11.nit-lies in Gettysburg.
We hold the En metis burg aud Bultlmore
Midi
Wwic-HTivii it, Ps., July
1 o'clock, midnight tj
"ur forces are known to havegaiued upon
tti* euoury i-.mii l o'clock this afternoon.
Bmes 5 o clock the tiring bos beeu much
heavier aud more rapid, indicating a general
atiKKgsment between the entire armies. The
tehel lores ia concentrated ou South Mountain,
I-ward ('ariis)f, six mtlee uorth of Getty*
lur« i, jU Sedgwick a corps passed Vcrk iv
tiie iliieiiion of Hover, at I o'clock this after
u.'oii It is iv the rear of tbe enemy. The "J
at my cups moved up from lluuover at 8
B ilink thin morning.
ruumdetagaa, Joly -l A ppscial dispatch
li lbs ButoMtn, from Harrisburg, aaya
N -'.0 uk* ir yet known as U tesulls, tint ibe
laprecaiou prevails that the great decisive
Nils of the campaign baa been t 'Ught iv ibe
hMßl'borhond of Caautown, between Getty*
knrgand Chambersburg.
It U believed that as have tvj/,red heavy
lout in ojf.reit and mtii, hot Lse la 80 irlp
'e-o'l ac to be placed ou ibe defensive
Yesterday Gen Meade assumed tbe ctt-u
••ve. Tbe day before Lee had attacked Meade,
*v ess lepuleed with heavy los 3.
1-ee holds a gap iv South Mountain, near
J '.aabersburp through which he hopB to
•Maps if defeated. A guard stationed at
r »iigo Eighty four on tbe NortLurn Central
l-»ilroad, heard tiring iv that direction, like
jfotof fymg isSjßsryi whence il ie believed
i'leuiianion is again ni work with bis dashing
cavalry, lighting for the BiBBBBBMof tbe gap.
t'.t, Jnly Capt. Roberta, of
I'biladelßhia, who was captured near Gettya
tm'K r nd paroled, haa arrived hei*.
it* raports that yesterday, beyond t'oik, a
courier irom Geu. Meade to Gan. Ouch
awpped v boose to have hia horse fed. Tue
*"inei, iv ib* house became alarmed and blew
k born to jllect the neighbors, when the eou
fearing that the uoiae would reach the
'«t*la, threatened tbem it tbey did not desial.
«i itda momsat tbo owner n ihe boase a-*
•ivsd and, taking tbe courier for a rebel, drew
k l«i*tol and killed bim. Tbo courier's dU-
Ykttuoa w*re sabeeijueuUy eeul le Bakfaaore,
*»»y tu'.liatiiy. toatead of to Harriabnrg.
'apt Porter cay* that uumber* of people iv
USB wid Adams counties cliered srsry ppssl
aialamaas to the rebels,peiatlßf out lo item
i-i* property of Union oitissaa and of the Gov
•''■n-sni, and showing tbem tbe nude
Heavy and coutiunous artillery bring wee
jtMmtimj sfteiaoou, aad last aisht, ia
DAILY DOJe-A'TCHT"
a r
VOL. XXV.
JL -■■■■■gggWBMBBgggH
the direction of Mover, eight mBBB oorthweet
of Tork.
ins vtsr UTrsr veoa raa nmtmn.
The 'following diepalcbee ere fiabttehed by
tbe World a* "ibe very latest
Ph,loJ*lpha, July II -A special dispatch to
Pwraey's Ptett, dated Hanover. 1 P. M via
Waabiogton, Jaly 3, bbjb At li thi* morning
oar forces opened on about Mul libels, who
advsaeed on tbe field at daybraah for tbe par
poeefof pilaging onr deal Tbs rebels haatily
retrabtod. The fight tbaa far baa beea tbe
most terrille of tbe war. Tba loss est both
sidee waa heavy. Gen. Bkhlae wae wonaded
.eaerely. HU right leg wss BTMamtid, and
b* ib doing well. A desperate battle rages.
Wa hme tin, dn\y :s.—The information re
oeiveii here i* that the battle of Gettyebarg
last night waa extremely tierce aad stubborn
Heavy au 1 determined aaaaalts were made by
the rebate, which were gallantly awt by our
troopa.
This morning at daylight tba neatest was
spiritedly renewed. Oar army drove tbe eu
emy, who tn turn drove oure, MM fighting be
ing derperately severe, and the fiercest, proba
bly, of the war.
Prim ners report that Longstrget wae hilled,
and this seems to be confirmed by later intel
ligence.
Colonel Cross, of New Hampshire, and
General Zjok, of Yew Torb, art esaong ths
hilled. G«u. Metis* it le wIA, ufu wounded,
ami bed his leg amputated oo the field.
Gen lUrkudale, uf the rebel army, Is hilled,
and bis body ia in our posseaaion.
The lauat inteHipnce received here waa no
to II o clock io-day- [Thia "latest intel i
pence Ihe kaokae War Department did not
allow lo be made public—Ki>
a ntc-imri.AtijN or nil ha hi ur winau
war.
The torrofpoudsntof tua New York Watlmn
writing on the Jl inst., thue recapitulates the
battle of Wednesday
The engagement yesterday was cjuiti se v* ra,
though confined to our advauc*. the First and
Elovsuth corps, the art) in burn fouvht main
ly by tie First corps, aider General Heyuolds,
wbo wes killed by a Bt«arpahooter early in the
fight. We brat attacked the enemy a advance
inst beyciud Gettysburg and repulsed it, when
the whole corps became engaged, aud eulse
,'iently ibe Kleventh corps, which came up to
support by tire Kaaaetet'irg road. Theoppos
ing forces were the -eiel corps of 11.11 aud
I'! well. Our men gallantly sustained tbe fight,
holding tbeirowu until! o'clock, when tuej
re'ireil to a fttrong pcajliiou just to the east
ward in 1 Boatbward ai (Jityshurg. This was
maintained until ibe urnv.il of reiiiforcemeule
at uigtit, aud our lines aie now well formed.
No general en.tiigeirn.ut has yet taken place,
but the probability is that a great battle wiil
be fought this afteruot-u in tomorrow. The
enemy Is in great force. IMB troops are vow
all up i.ud weii in hauti.
Tbe bail!" yesterday wan sanguinary iv the
extreme. Wadswortlr*e division sustained tbe
early port'ouof it with grbat valor, charging
tbe enemy aud taking v whole regimeat of
prisoners with Hrigadiei -General Archer. We
have taken folly one tj ousand prisoners and
loft many, most of therm being wonaded and
in Gettysburg, tbe l renter portion of which
the nemv now hold.
The rt Mlb c.i ropy Pennsylvania College as
an Imapiial. jHooiueon's division and oue
brigade of Donbleday's supported Wade worth
witn great gnl!autry. The llth corps, most ot
it foagbt weM, and redeemed the difgrace of
Cli.iinelloinviile. Among *«lie general officers
we L.rii, besides Major Qeneral Keynolde,
Geneiui Pail killed, ami ltru«ral Harlow
wouuddd. lien. Scbimmelteuuig is a prisoner.
Au entiui.-it i ot yeeterday'e trus-ialties caunot
tin w be male.
OdltyebniK wae injure.! by shells to a OOO>
eiderabl j eiteut. Most ol the inhabitants re
main iv the burgb, mnuy got away yesterday.
kirtu beaatiful ilm-e, surrounded by a beau
tiful open and rolling country.
There has been mote or leifi akirmiabiog all
the niorniog, but uo engagement of dimeu
■ieaa lioth partiea are preparing tor the
great coutest b6fore tbem. Oar troops are iv
splendid cuudii.ton.and Oght l.k- veiertuie.
Amoug the casualties m yeet««.lay's eugnge
mt-ut ware tbe following
UeuieiiH.nl Bayard Vvilkisou, commaadiag
Battery il, Kouub regular artillery, sou of
Samuel Wilbison, Washington i irrespomleitt
of ibe 'lime*, right leg shot cfi below the
kuee, while gallantly lighting bia battery
Hgaiiut uu eightgau battery of tbe enemy,
eublaaiug hie position, believed to be a pris
oner
il. Stone, l I.i.it Pennsylvania, command
iug brigade, bally wounded.
Col. Boot, '.'lib New Ydik, wouuded and
prisoner.
Col Tildeo, .tb Maiue, takeu prlsouw.
Capts Hovey and Thomas, of Gen. Hobin
eon s at a tt', wounded.
Col Mahler, Wlb Peuusylvauia.dangerouE
lv wounded.
Col. LsekßßHh 11Mb New York, wounded.
Ai'j t Dodge, li'iii New York, woimded
uud captired.
1/eut. Col. Afiowßuiitb, ISTtb New York,
killed.
The following id a list of Usees of officere
in Geu. Sol. Meredith's brigade, W ads worm h
division, list army corps, lv yesterday's tight i
Oen. Meredith, bruised cm top of the head
by a fragment of shell. His horee was shot
nuder him aud fell upon him, bruisiug and in
jariug him internally.
Lieut. Col. G VV Woodward, Aid de-Camp
to Meredith, wouuded iv right arm.
The New York papers have uot a eingle ex
ul aut paragraph ov«r the light, wbicii is very
sigmtioaut. Tbe World, of the i-b, says:
At lust a gleam of intelligible relieves
tbe murky chaos of official tel«grams, iuwbioh,
for line daya past, tbe battl* fields of Ptiin-
Bylvauia have beeueiisbiouded. In a dispatch
which would have better sutitti -.1 the general
expcctaiious. aud gone farther to appease the
geuerul anxiety, bad tiie War Ddparlmenl
thought tit to nubiifli it iv lull, but which,
even iv the mutilated I i tn iv which Mr. Stau
ton present* it, commauls at'.eutiou aud in
spirea coutiJeuce by it* modest and tnauiy
tone, General Meade aiiuouucea tbat a great
battle really on Thursday eveuiug, aud
was renewed yeslerday moruiug, botweeu bid
own army and the whole force of the enemy.
He clutms for bia troops the credit of a stem
aud aolid res s-auce to au attack of which be
dose uot conceal tbe tierce and formidable
character, aud at S o'clock on Friday mormug
be asseits the continued success of that i-esisi
emee.
Since 8 o'clock ou Pri lay moruiug, bow
ever, uoihiug seeuis to have been bear.l from
tiie eceue from this supreme OOafoot, uud fur
titer lidiuge must therefore be looked for wiiii
an eageruess pceitively pnut.it iv ilsintsusity.
These tidiogs uii*y-— iuddo-1, if the Govern
ment will bit do iii* July, tbey must—reneb us
it any moment. Lit va hope that tbey may
come to throw a sudden glory of victory and
af hope over the solemn hour .it tbe great au
niveis-iry which the nation thisdiy celebrates.
ths cat ii ai cr BiiMßßßCttl i.a —a etan
son aoic'.ii' BT Sit fff Basma ma* r aaa
tint L«jiT</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82015209/1863-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.597,0.201,0.285,0.309,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>(ileal Hatlle in Pennsylvania.
e e
.1 A' A' V U AC C 0 UN TS.
e

VJvi J JADE W0UHJMSD. V
t'ot ii v.
PKr.U.bkNKUALK ILL. ISO.
Ihe Yntikces claira a drawn Battle.
Naii r.. Juiy I, via Mom duly 6th The crop
at il-l..i mi l liuiMiti ihjt couatiy h r uDturputcd.
in lV:..'i.ir:; v .1 a 10-. '.Ki.it. pasted u; this a.
u. 1 .1.. pi i 11.1 i.e.), ami wonine od,t
r...

uiu wii.'vl.
f .V. P.iwtil coin ii ii.iii,.r this puV, is cleauin-
v .t m x ri-rf.v.i x
Aauut.4 01 d.ra.eia.
'j be Coaiml-a y ol tins Trans M iiniutlppia Depart-
meu:,i.i t ij.-.jiii und I'oi. Hud oj a e well 0.0-

o'l 1 11 of Tuxa, y f -us. fc-m.h ai Magiu
ili: lo at .".1 v.iiicntias their siiires.
ten.Taytoi- b9s cantu.i.l many yatkee planti-M
an.; oveistieia, i-ud boltis tlieui as lioit.ina, for the ie-
1u.11 ..f a huudteu meu.c mlii.ed by llu!.. fo? a'uoot-1
ia Mi Ltiuit. Ue bo5d all bouUitrueia who base
'akc-t t:eUJtli at 1 iison-rtr war
.akc.i 1..C0JU. a-ti iisod rt or war.
l. i-a:i and Powers a'ai .n theFcJera? by the hold-
ueh, ol ibvir dalles.
inch 1: viai:, ju.y a, via arir.vTo.x. ia script u tiim, tor iiucianuy s aaj'te wur enaer du wo.uioa
:roni Mur!ii;..h:iric were tohl by Moby 's inen.thit Kt altP this eruaton oildood. -Th ptiaooera were ae
.1. An. cortliDEly cndoci9d to. te. (iaidn.-. who havrsf ihe
art bid torn up the track ou the na.'Juior and Ohio ot wMm hi west. Immedl-
Ilail liuid at the KcJay ilocae. U is reported ths
la e is niaieipns toward Uillirrij.e, Maryland. Th
ttutit h tv i'.i iappua:oJ Irjia the Ileit'tta.
iLAiiNoroM.Julv5th.wTbe enemv issdvaacins on

(he i!u.iuKPa aud Weluou roi d. Ihey were at
KuiiiMivil e U.-t uiKbt, -reo mi e.i Irsia the Eai'.road
-fi'-,un b.iiit'ied cava.iy
The w:rca were
cut at
hall prsl j'ei.it h.
V 1 L i o j o.s J u!y 5. Toe euemy tvok Warsaw sa
'.he WYiii'tiKlu.-i Suti Weliliiu l:a ICoad, a; tbia
'11 .i:n-.'. Ic i rep..il;d ihst taey huroed the coinpa
uy wan hnuso nud twrn'v thousand poiiu Is ol hacon.
ii.hQ(:iuir Ij the tJotornineiit. Th'y left about lour
this fveninj;, in the dlrecik.s ot Keeaaavllie, where
1 ho n.a.u oody ol itie1.-lot -ea badatjpped. arory e
iii.ia'e put.t tbtir foit e .l J 000 tj 4,001 cavalry and
u.laMry. Il in icpoited that half oi them are kite,
aiid ball uerofH,
Pit iiuond, July 4lh.
'l i e Now Votk UeiulU ol 1'ie yih uit. says
Leo's whoio army is undoubtedly ia Penn
sylvania Last ii'l.t the 1 chela uoio wiihiu threo miles
of lli..iaburg. A heavy fire baa been going
on all day between the out posts. The utmost
conslct nation prevails linoughout Pcnn.ylva-
ma, and iugilivi- keep pouring into Matria
bur;r, Lancaster and other cilicd, and iutooth
or MU t. in complete terror, bringing their cat
tic, inercUti'dixe, aud 1 ousohold goods.
(ion. Kcll Uaned ait order to the troop at
Chambcrebuig, tiiging tLo Bocossity U vigi
l.mco ui d tlisciplpie.
Cicuxuxi), July Tbu yaukce ruaaaudera are stUl
rtipoi.t'd'iM lo.te in lianovei No dcliaite in for ma
ti.tu of Mi ir iu iv.'mjn bat been received aiuce Fti
day nub., 'lhe Ui Ina I ir Ual' tons Ciossing sad
suniiu. did liot leave -tbia moinlog, as telrgisphic
cjim oulcation wiih Hanover Jonctloa was Interrupt
cd. the cause of which ia not yet ascertained.
Jtia reptirud that t a are wad a ejbt laat aiiht at
Sou.ia'Auua Liiuge.
H c:i jto.Mt, July 4th. Theru haa beeu a baU! at
Ce,.y.-i.ui-;, he tween LooKtU'-iH.'t aud II ill s Corpa, aad
nearly the whole ol Mead's uroiy. The Federal Oea
Ps w. 1.111 ma the kil e i. The reoebt at Carlois have
all fallou hack in tbe dhtciiuii of tbs mala body cf
Lie's samy. Ths L'uioa troop have icocenled ths
.own." Toe yaikdB ai-ui-wn: repr ot tbs battl at
Ce't'Hhurjr, iuJecinivd. iiotb aides auflenog aevere
ly. Ar.'.tUcr K"-al battle wa cxpcct.d bear the asms
luuit.
I'kTcsar 'mi, Ja!y i.X trala Jus', from City Polo
sxys a ter.-mlj tl h-. took plica near Uettyabur-r ou
Wtdutady i.nd Thursday. Toe Laltlm-ir Clipper
aaya A rvlw-.-'a eutir brigade w-1 cut off aad were
ma pi iiert tstt only ei.rht bnodrrd of tbtu bad
atr.ved at liahiinore. M.ijor Ucneisl Iteyuoidi Wa
.1 n the Urt Cre.
n-1 i-. -T'ie Clipper lai n luiUiy on blantoa far
-el.i' r.-.ii n'. 1, NuyiiJ' the li 'Ut ia indtt ivc abd tbe
IfeU; am i i "iaK hcivily.
1,'i 'iiu iNU, July o. Tii: 111-1:000: ot the Baum-oie
Anirr fin njii!1 o'eiork on NVedoaaday aays the first
aod eleventh corps of the army of tbe Potanaacea
crci iV tysbarg, tb cavalry ef the sstemy failing
back, tii pa-nug over the wait sad of tbs ttiwa, la
epeoiy, uader l.oujiblp-et and II ill. sdvaaced steadily
lor a tw luiouuca unjt.r a hevy lire of arUlieiy aad
muHki-P-y atlnnx; the whole cf the Federal and Itehel
Poet- St vera! untni jee 'sfil chirgsa were txad by
tbe enemy. A', three o clock th enemy msased the.
entire lot 'es ssd endeavored to tor our right wing
A b in II sht enKueJ'both khlea auJarlug sovSrely
Toe He M bet ween ths ouotendiDg ar sales waa strewn
with tb tkad and wounded. X te enemy MtTeisd folly
as heavily, r w did. Tbe cRart t flank oar right
win, ctiiirely failed. Ths ad rsntagev ot th day are
rcr.11 Jed as detids y with oor forces. OfilMrs who
arrived last night la charge ef prisoners d nibs the
achtt t We lneaJayri rather sinfav rsbb) to or art
tad state that tbe eetay held the ft eld at tb etas ef
ibe day. Osrfoiee's having fallea back after th fall
of Gen. Iteynolds oa Tbsrstlay, there waa ksavy
aklrmiahiog hot no general eega-resaeot. Tb enemy
wsa rapidly ooDcenCtetiajT uoops 00 yesiterdsy
Meads's whole army reached ths Bald cf battle. Oea.
Wada worth tras ssTtrtly wouitded. Oor kaai wa t
BJcTsertirraTryi elitaetoJ Cacairl
st Snth amaa I rtktt mA wetejeaalsei;
W )uv ao aAfUoals lAkaw. tr. loss WM snuL
Belwctn lwt aatl tana rJita a at Va.
M
wviuiviii uuiiiuifi, ueiarvjcv fmm "if ay
tbstoaek. No teWfTilahle eoomoliBeaUaa irae the'
Tie yeekiieeea to Uaf traoi host whieh arrived
at CUj Polot kt alrkt ssj that Oea. llsade was
severely wgosdad at tbs Wattle of UtUrttarf, aai
THE llKMTllht (jr Federal Oenends wtta kld. They alw
say n was a draws barns.
Uit af K.llUxl, Mitdw m.m MlaaSa t tba
jibi TomttMt H;lnirit r J Blrl
dlc.la, it Aetlea aur Havava Oar.
-aht Jant Jt,l8Ci3.
Corn pan r D KUWd Priva's Wsi. J. Barry,
rjotnpsav E.-Vroaaes, i Oora. J. J. Bobioaoa as-
vsrely, priva' Louis 04 sllshUy.
tmnpaay F Prtvats wa Teaar sevtrsty weoBdN.
CoBpaav GSe-rEseat Taeaus Carter atvoelv
wounded. T
Company C--Pri vsts ft. C. Kerrif sDxkUv sroeod-
led, prlva J. Tomtdla taNala;.
L- islcDaSLL,
A4J"I Uth Teaa. Bajteeat. J
Test sKrlIkey Wa as lavyt Wk are
thecnwltfl. sjowkATTbt loti Mx. whi stids with
labroadrt ssstiiiat taa -ewes-Hta t ta, sattsini
in aa aafcno a.i Acae jfwrrta t a wjsUMisi laspertx
Who are t bey lbs BtianiKtit tssassir sf repautlos.
woo Mrs la lba py-taiMa of sisry wua eaffirfs'
iosoes, shstptiBsA by iaveaiiua aa esveeomed ef
malice, to disw tSs blood of tnaooeace, aad bysoa
like bsnqrtl em the dead T Wee are tsey Tftsyare
a roakiiode nu auta can aanber,n black-tottled fa
milltij of the twaWltloa ef aUoler, searchlnr for
victioit la every ciiy, wa and vPUxa, wherever the
heart of bum inity Urob$ or tat ashes of morality
I UUU J. V
Inrul ru. udi cowara, eowara, word staiks-a
i ia t..i...a .t.. i...a... .0... k.
ii su hio 't w 1 ifaaA e hiih uvvis eivut wmw
b'gbwy wlih flashlax weapons thit out the aaabeam
as well the sSsde lvs aas tas --as wa osfaria
tb W:'t a nh:ein ot b te.rib! tnd. sad
nhowa tbe plaok which yoor d ad feet moat t ead
but aavs me i.-oca Uie tney vers or society, whose
rnivti am hlldeo ia a velvet abeath. wbxs bridge of
ieath a wcvnn letlowera. and who rprted w'th invia-
ille j.oi n, iren ths spotless waken ef the w iod
ic, j- khctt.
As iFCiDExr or the 8110s or Post IltTMoa. Th
Naxbea Courier ef ths 2ilh nit. pabUsbes the follow-
tag
At the late charge cf aur mea 0.1 the SVIeral ccU m
brta-twftrrv when they too, fee rat aad apiked tha
enemy e gast-ai W said H.tMv Coalsderatss weie
takeu priao1era. The rnr-d took litem before Otta.
lianks, who said Tssy s.e e to Brave to be my
nriaoners conduct testa to Geo. Oarlssr, and say lo
I ali ly ordered their release, sMosrsd theoa tr iaapeet
I the whole of his loNlflcattona, aad lhu dtreted them
W ue cnnuuctT-a nj oa nan u m iif r vucim i.bv, w iw
thl ialunctto Ts I tiea. Basks that yoa bavs ta-
apeciea an o wwawi, ji</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86053570/1863-07-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.353,0.114,0.987,1.07,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>FROM GEtTtSBURG.
The Battle Field Two Days After tae
Battle.
Correspondence-of the New York Times.)
rwrttiari Details of tbe Great stattles of
Friday.
GimtBrxo, Pi., Joly 5, :9oS Ai tb do
Ul, tha Incident and tba general history of
th gnat victory are brought to light, It Is
dearly defined as the moat hotly contested and
destructive engagement of the great rebellion
Tba peculiar feature of thsbatUe Is the ferocity
and desperation with which It was fongnt by
both armies, and tbo glorlom tsan place tbe
lostre of the national arms and the valor of the
Army of the Potomac In tha Iiuperiahablo an
sa! of brUrWnt aJetory. j
jnanauu oocnpiea tnrca days,' uir hours
flghtlnr ott Wedoeadav. four hours an Thurs
day, and, lncluding tbe artillery flringon Tri
aay, toinecD nonra mat aay, making a total 01
twenty-threat hours, daring which the battle
ragoa wun extreme larr.
lite momentonr Snd decisive part of the bat
tle waa mat on rjiaay. 11 oegan reauy at aay
llcbt and continued until 10 o'clock, thettrtn-
clpnl part of Ua musketry fighting being on
the. right, with fcloeum'a corpa. A lull of three
bonra followe4dorUK which the enemy massed
his artillery on oor contra, held by llancock
with tt Second, ami Newtoo. with tbo First
Corp. At 1 o'clock one hundred and twenty
guna opened on that poaltlon, sod rained shot
and shell la a perfect deluge for one hour and
forty mlnntes. A graph le description of this
awfnl period ha already been furnished to tbe
Tutu by an abler pen than mine, for that wri
ter and one of the Titiut' messenger had the
ezctung leiicuy 01 enaartog mat storm of iron
during the whole time. Mr. Wllkeaon is lo-dar
engaged In tbe mournful duty of obtaining the
remain and effect of his eldest son, the gal
lant )ouog Bayard, who was mortally wonoded
on vteunesaay, ten on tne neia, ana ayiog
finally, after ten hours Buffeting, without a
frlciia or a word to soothe the dying agonic
of his soul. Lieut. UUkeson was but nine
teen years old, yet had command of Battery 0,
Fourth regular artillery. Ills death adds an.
other noble son! to the holocaust of this terri
ble war.
I rode this morning over the entire length of
the battle-field, and It 1 not too much to Bay,
for I have seen nearly every other battle-field
In Maryland and Vlrgtula. that the slaughter
was perfectly unparalleled. Oar detail were
busily engaged In collecting and burying the
dead, and the ghastly, terrible sights were
enongh to shock a heart of adamant.
The vast number of dead lying In front of,
mocum' line, on tne right, ana or Hancock's
and Newton's on tbe ceutre, attracted much
comment. Tbey had been literally mown down
bv whole ranka at a single discharge. Blocuin
accomplished a bloody repnls of Swell's corps
on Friday morning, sustaining but small loss
himself, hla poaltlon being very formidable,
against which the enemy Insanely charged
Bat the field full of the greatest Incidents,
ana tne scene or tne most aesperate ngnting.
waa on the centre. In front of llancock ana
Newton, against wnom Longsirect'e corps was
precipitated. The enemy's front was tbat of
one ditlslon In line of battle, there were two
such lines, aud a very heavy line of skirmish
ers, almost equal to another line of battle Out
of their concealment In the woods tbey camo
across the open field and up the gentle crest,
on the top of which wot our line-! weak line
of men behind a line of defence hastily thrown
up and composed partly of stone walls, partly
or ine-pits, ana partly or natural projections
of soil and rock. Tbo first charge was repulsed!
tbe lino broke and Ml back before It bad reached
a point two thirds of tbe way over. A second
lino was formed, the officers came to tbe front,
aud with tbo onset of fierce and brutal hearta
they rushed. Our men looked with astonish
ment, while ugutiug wun great Tigort their
lino was dangerously weak, tbe defences were
not formidable, a lew men temporarily gave
wayt our advance, In some Instances, slightly
faltered.
The artillery engaged was small In force,
having been seriously weakened during the
early part of the light. The rebels came on so
close that their expressions of tierce rage were
plainly distinguished, some of them actually
gained tbe Inside of the first wall but they
never returned Our immortal men, nerved to
a degree of desperation never before equaled,
poured forth. such a devastating fire, and the
artillery joining with Its terrible canister, that
the two long lines of the foe literally sank Into
the earth. Of the divisions of Pickett, and Heth,
who made that charge, composed of eight
brigades, poelthely not two brigade returned
uninjured across the field. Tht color Uartrt
uf thirty-fit rrM rtgiuunti, who were In that
charge, were shot down, the colors fell on the
field, and were gathered by the victorious vet- j
eran of the Second Corps. Being repulsed,
large numbers of tbe enemy started back on
tbe retreat, buL our fire was bo diBtructlvo that
the fell fiat on their faces, or again rushed
about and Implored mercy at our hands, as
prisoner of war.
Beven colonels of rebel regiments were hurled
on that field this morning) eight mora were
captured, besides those who were wounded and
crawled or were taken off. Among tbe rebel
officers killed and captured on that front were
Barks da to on Thursday, Garnett killed and
Armiatead wounded on 1 rlday'heso general
olBcorij Col Magruder, brother of Ocn. Magru
der, killed) Col. Lee, of the 4Sth Irglnln, is a
prisoner) Col. Alien, of tbo 4bth Georgia, Is
klUed; Col. .Miller, of Ihu 4d Mississippi, la a
prlsoqer and wounded; Col, Frye, oftliolSth
Alabama, and Col. Aaborn, of Vlrglnlu, are
both prlsouirs. All the-e captnrvd or de
stroyed by tho brigade of Ocn Welli.a most
Intrepid ofllecr, who won, with many other,
the highest plaudits for his conduct.
A poculUr fact concerning our poslttuu Is
contained In the expression of surprise which
tho rebel officers uttered when tbey crossed our
line as prisoners of ar. Ono of the colon)
Sdid.as be looked at our thlulloo, Where are
tbe nieu who fought ua?" "Here," said a
captain. "My Godl' exclaimed tbe colonel,
if we only had another tine we could hare
whipped you;" and then, still gating about
htm with aatonlsbment. ho exclaimed, with
great emphitsls, liy 0-dt tea tould hat whipptd
you aa it teatt" This is a positive fact, and
Illustrates how the noble Army of tho Potomac
eau yet figbt, after all the imputations of de
moralization and lu t (Helen cy which have been
heaped upon it
Tbo bucoad division of the Second corps loses
42 oiucera killed and wonnded, and l,7ot) en
listed men killed and wouuded.
The b Uncut pruUo is awarded to Ocus. llan
cock and Newton for tholr dlitlngulabed con
duct on this portion of the field. Hancock
was secreiy wounueu m me tmgu, out re
mained la jl tig on hla back on the field, and
giving the orders, tlen. Newton was csjxj.
elall) actlto In supporting the line on the right
Hiih reinforcement.
History will nuvur chronicle a'tcnth part of
the gullaut deeds performed during these bloody
dajs) but the sails f-ct loo of having uobly per
formed bis duty shall be the sweet recompense
of every patriot's heart.
Tho enemy, by a purtlally secret and Igno
minious retreat, baa awarded to this gallant
army tbe acknowledgment of victory. Ills
forces are now on their way back lo Virginia,
beaten, weakened and demoralized by a terri
ble defeat) lie is hotly pursued, a victorious
army on his reur, a strong local force on his
flank, and a swollen river lu hi front, are tbe
obstacles to his successful relreat.
I regret to say that my esteemed friend, tl t,
James J, GrltUtbs, of Uen. Howard's staff, was
severely wonnded In the hip to-da while re
eonnolterlug tbo enemy's rear line In corap my
with the General. The weund I not datigeri ns.
L. L. t holts B 1
moat TItK ARITTOr TUB POTOMAC.
ICorwpoaience'cff Ike fcalUmora Imeaeaii j
Fbidbiicx, Wednesday, noon, July 8
The position of the rebels, and their condi
tion, has, bee n definitely aertelBd. Their
infantry line It drawa across fromFankatown,
Md to Fslllog Wat en,, and behind this Hoe
they are" using almost luperhuman exertion
10 get tneir 1 rains tsocn aa tnev nave saved;,
artillery snd ammunition across tho river. The
beat military authority hero doubts, I might
almost Say Is convinced, that they have no
pontoon train, beyond that destroyed atFaTTlng
Waters, and that with such canal boats as they
had not previously burnt, and timber felled In
the vlclnltv and at Martlnabunr. they ara en-
Jeavorlug to supply tha deficiencies of tbetf
engineer ccrpi; r If Is known Hat two days ago
they bad troops felling timber.
They also attempted to cross some wgous
on flat-boats, but the Impelaooj current tx the
rewerw tne 'attempt rutua. -rney are now
crossing their horses on the boats, and leaving
the wagon this side, probably Intending to take
them to place and. tan transport them cm tbe
canal boats r tt
I have hard the opinion expressed In a very
htrh mimarv fanarter that the rebels' will' Lro-
bably sectireUaatkoatdsfetielblellrielii frontof
T BSASBBAAB-ararvi.f- AHHVUVU .assaillllH S I aBSJU'l
dearor to hold our army at bay whilst they
WlliJamportf Intrench ,tAMuacves. and -en
enre toe means 01 crossing.
Tha position of the rebels U much mora d
perst than I had allowed myself to think h-jrv.
tofore. Of course they may get .away, but it
looks much leal probably now than It dldtwen-ty-fonr
hour backV h 4
Lee If aavdaxuartera, a
Le' beadquarter Is deflnllely ascertaiatd
lo be at IXagerttown to-day, and his troops are
mainly on the road between there and Mil-Uanipprt,-whlob
la only- six miles distant.
Apontotf.CGeti.Xarleys rtbel command Is
lo day reported as cut off In the mountains.
near Green castle, by our cavalry. This Is of
course at present only a rumor, but It la cred
ited to aome extent In view or a knowledge of
too purpose 01 ueo. rieasantoni ana uen,
ScdgSclck's freent movements.
Our Cavalry Operatlona.
The cavaUf'of tJen. Plcasanion tiave1)een
operating with magnlllceul success during tho
last three days. It Is a positive fact, that
wnust tno reoeis were retreauag we naa car-
airy in, toeir front ana rear, ana on both Hanks.
Its presence and bold dashes greatly aided In
increasing tne Demoralization or tne roimi. and
the discipline the have heretofore shown was
greatly relaxed.
It la the opinion at headquarter that our
cavalry have not taken less than 0,000 prison
ers, Including wounded, who hare been picked
up everywhere along the road, where they were
abandoned by ibelr friends, aud In the farm
houses. Amoeg tbe capture ts Brig. Oen
Robinson, lie had lorn off hla Inelguta of rank
aauu wn, utuoavu iu vitittui vii'kiiiuia uui (lata
recognized. Brig. Gen. Trimble, of 10th of
April ana rnuaaripnis rauroaa rame, is also a
prisoner. He waa found In the farm houae of
Mr. David Wblsler, near Gettysburg. His left
foot was blown off by a shell.
Tbe damage done to the rebel train by the
dashes of our cavalry ts almost Incredible.
Everywhere alone: tho retreat thev were can.
lured, cut off, and burnt. General KUpatrUik
dashed Into tbe middle of Gen. EweU's ttalu
aud burnt between two aud three hundred
wagons, and run off the horses. Tcnlay he
captured sixty morowagont and300horsesand
mules.
Our cavalry X think K 11 Patrick's division
had a fight yesterday at Ilagerstown with a
rebel Infantry divlsluu. Their position was nt
one time dangerous, but they got out finally
without serious loss, to far as the particulars
are now known.
On the Advauce
Our army U moving steadily. Of Its direcv
tlon and disposition I shall aay little, though
the former may be readily gnossed at from what
Is said of the position of tho enemy. If Lee
remains on this side of the river, the Drobablll-
tie of another battle within the next forty
eight hours are, to use a newspaper phrase,
Imminent.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84025980/1863-07-10/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.095,0.524,0.617,0.669,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Great Battle near Gettysburg, Fa-
Defeat of the Federal Army.
Over Twelve Thousand Prisoners Taken
Four Federal Generals Killed The Yankee
Commander Wounded.
Petersburg, July 5.—-A train just from Ci
ty Point reports a terrible battle near Gettys
burg,. Pa., on Wednesday and Thursday.
The Northern papers say that Archer's en
tire brigade, (Confederate) was cut off and ta
ken prisoners—but only eight hundred had
arrived in Baltimore.
Maj. Gen. Reynolds, (Federal,) was killed
the first fire. Tbe latest is that Meade was
calling on Stanton lustily for reinforcements
—stating at same time that the fight was in
decisive and the rebels pressing him heavily.
SECOND DISPATCH.
Richmoiid, July s.—The battle at Gettys
burg was between Longstreet's and Hill's
corps, and nearly the whole of Meade's army.
The Federal Gen. Paul is among the killed.
The rebels at Carlisle have all fallen back
towards the main body of Lee's army. We
would reoccupy the place.
The Yankee accounts represent the battle
as indecisive, both sides suffering severely.
Another great battle was expected near the
same point.

Later from the Battle of Gettys
burg.
Federals Admit an Enormous Loss.
Richmond, July 5.—-Accounts from the
Baltimore American state that on Wednes
day morning, at 9 o'clock, the First and Ele
venth corps of the Army of the Potomac en
tered Gettysburg, the cavalry of the enemy
falling back.
On passing out tbe west end of the town the
Confederates under Longstreet and Hill ad
vanced steadily, and in a few minutes there
was a heavy firing of artillery and musketry
along the whole of the Federal and Confede
rate lines, and several successful charges were
made by the Confederates.
At three •'clock the Confederates massed
their entire forces and endeavored to turn our
right wing, when a heavy fight ensued, both
sides suffering severely.
The field between the contending armies
was strewn with the dead and wounded.
It is said that the Confederates suffered ful
ly as heavily as we did.
The effort to flank our right wing entirely
failed.
The advantages of the day are regarded as
decidedly with our forces.
Officers who arrived last night, in charge
ef prisoners, describe the fight as rather unfa
vorable to our arms. They state that "the ene
my held the field at the cbse of the day, our
forces having fallen back after the fall of Ge
neral Reynolds.
On Thursday there wa6 heavy skirmishing,
but no general
The epemy were rapidly concentrating
their troops yesterday.
Meade's whole army bad reached the field
of battle.
Gen. Wadsworth was severely wounded.
Our loss was enormous and heavy, and es
pecially among the field and line officers.
4
Latest from the l¥Orth.
Meade's Report of the Battle at Gettysburg.
Gen. Longstreet Reported Killed.
Petersburg, July 6.—The Philadelphia In
quirer of the 14th has been received.
Gen. Meade's official dispatch to Washing
ton, dated July 2, II o'clock, p. m., says "the
enemy attacked me at 4 o'clock this afternoon,
and after one of the severest contests of the
war, he was repulsed at all points. We have
suffered considerably in killed and wounded.
Among our killed are Brig. Gen. Paul and
Gork. Among the wounded are Gens. Sick
les, Barton, Graham and Warren. General
Sickles' lfig was amputated on the. field.—
We have taken a large number of prisoners."
A s«cond dispatch from Gen. Meade, dated
8 o'clock Friday morning, says the "action
commenced again at early daylight upon va
rious parts of the field. The enemy thus far
have made no impression upon our position.
All accounts agree in placing the entire rebel
army in position in Our front. Prisoners we
have taken report that Longstreet's and Hill's
forces were much injured yesterday, and ma
ny General officers killod. The dead body of
Gen. Barksdale is within our lines. We have'
thus far about sixteen hundred prisoners and
a small number is yet to be sterted."
The correspondent of-the Inquirer says
that it is reported that Gen. Longstreet is
among the rebel killed.
The rebels still held Gettysburg at 1 p. m.,
July 3d.
Our loss is very heavy. That of the rebels
cannot be far from 20,000, and the fight was
still progressing on Friday,
The rebels so far have bean repulsed in
every attack. The fight is still raging.
Gen. Lee sent in a flag of truce, asking for
a cessation of hostilities, for burying tbe
dead, which Meade refused.
The Inquirer breathes freely after reading
Meade's dispatches.
Vicksburg is not yet taken.
The Brashear City intelligence is confirm
ed in the Northern journals.
Highly Interesting Intelligence.
General Stuart's Operations near Bal
timore.
Lee master of the Situation—Eis whole
Army *n Splendid Condition—Over Twelve
Thousand Prisoners Taken.
M_aiiNSßcao, July 4, via Staunton July
Oth.—The Baltimore Sun of tbe Ist gives ac
counts of Stuart's movements upon West-1
minster and Pikesville, seven miles from the
city. On Monday last he captured in Mont
gomery county, 1200 mules, 400 prisoners,
_o. At Westminster he captured and dis
persed the Delaware cavalry.
The wildest alarm prevailed in Baltimore.
The militia were ordered out, the streets bar
ricaded, and the Secessionists threatened.
Gen. Lee has assessed a tax of $350,000
upon York, Pehn., giving twenty days to
raise if. Forty thousand dollars had been
collected by the citizens.
Banks has arrived at New Orleans with on
ly 5,000 men.
Prisoners who arrived here to-day from
1
Pennsylvania, say that on the Ist and 2d, Lee
and Meade had a general engagement, and
that Lee had defeated the Yankee army, witb
heavy loss on both sides, but no details are
given.
Meade was falling back on Baltimore, and
Lee following.
The Yankee cavalry injured the. pontoon
bridges at Falling Water, seven miles from
this place to-day, and captured three wagons.
They immediately left.
In the battle at Gettysburg on the Ist and
2d Gen. Reynolds was killed; Gen Sickles lost
a leg, and one other Federal General was
slain.
[second dispatch.]
Martinsburg, July s.—At 6 p. m., on Sa
turday, Gen Lee had changed his front, and
now occupies the ground from which he drove
the enemy on tbe Ist and 2d.
His whole army is in splendid spirits, and
he is master of the situation.
We have captured twelve thousand of the
enemy.
Gens. Heth, Pender and Pickett are among
our wounded. Col. Avery, of North Carolina,
is killed. Bennett and Parker are wounded.
General Ewell's wagons have been recap
tured.
[third dispatch.]
Martinsburg, July 6.— Reports to day say
that there was a heavy fight yesterday, in
which we defeated the enemy and drove him
three miles.
A vast number of prisoners reported taken
by Lee.
Prisoners taken refuse to be paroled, and
they are now on the way to Richmond by this
place.
This has been the bloodiest battle of the
War. Our lobs very great. The enemy's is
immense.

Attack on the Guard at South Anna
Bridge.
THE ENEMY REPULSED.
Ashland Burnt by the Enemy Gen. Meade
Wounded at Gettysburg Four Federal Gen
erals Killed.
RicH-OND, July s.—The Yankees attacked
the guard at South anna Bridge, last evening,
and were repulsed. No particulars have been
received, but it is known that our loss was
small.
Between two and three o'clock, this morn
ing' a party of Yankees, one hundred strong,
went to Ashland, and burnt the railroad build
ings, destroyed the water tank, and tore up
the railroad track. No telegraphic commu
nication since the- raid.
The Yankees, on a flag of truce boat at City
Point last night, say General Meade was se
verely wounded in the battle at Gettysburg,
and that four Federal Generals were killed.
They also say that it was a drawn battle.
Further from tbe Great Battle.
Meade Retreating on Baltimore and Lee Pur
suing—Confederate Generals Killed.
Richmond, July 6.—A1l unofficial tele
grams from Martinsburg", dated the sth, states
that Lee has defeated the enemy.
Meade was retiring on Baltimore and Lee
pursuing.
We lost 4,000 prisoners and captured 12,
--000,
Generals Barksdale, Garnett and Kemper
were killed. Gen. Hood was wounded.
Special Dispatches to the Chronicle.
Great Excitement in Philadelphia!
Destruction of Railroad Bridges, c.
Confederates near Washington
City.
Petersburg, July 3.—The New, York He
rald says the enemy have not advanced on
Harrisburg.
Latest accounts state skirmishing going on
at various points South of the Susquehanna.
Yesterday, at Oysterville and Maysville, es
pecially the latter, all our forces were within
their defences.
At sunset, yesterday, rebels had torn up
the railroad track for 31 miles, between Ma
riettasville and Sykesville. Damage at latter
place slight.
The rebel General, Early, has levied on the
inhabitants ot York for one hundred and fifty
thousand dollars in "green. backs," forty
thousand pounds fresh beef, twenty thousand
barrels of flour, thirty thousand bushels of
corn, ten thousand pairs each of shoes, socks,
coats and hats; and fifty bags of coffee, large
quantities of sugar and groceries.
Gen. Early says we will occupy the place
permanently. Its defenders entrenched them
selves and prepared for attack to-day. The
enemy repulsed; they crossed the river at
Bain bridge on pontoons with intention of cut
ting the Pennsylvania Central Railroad.
The greatest alarm prevails at Philadel
phia. The Mayor and Gen. Dana have issued
stirri*ng proclamations, appealing to the citi
zens to be prepared to defend their homes.—
There was great panic in stocks, yesterday.
held a meeting and resolved to
close their collieries until the crisis had pass
ed and this to enable them to volunteer. The
merchants resolved to raise .a million of dol
lars for defences. The Board of Brokers rais
ed twenty-live thousand dollars to be divided
among five hundred men who may enlist for
the emergency.
A line of entrenchments will be commenc
ed around Philadelphia to-morrow. t
The splendid bridge over the Susquehanna
at Columbia, valued at one hundrsd and fifty
seven thousand dollars, was burned on tbe
28th of June to keep the rebels out of the
town.
The rebel cavalry are committing great de
predations upon cattle and horses around
Washington City, at Drftinesville and Long
Bridge. They also made their appearance at
various points in Montgomery Co., and in
sundry places yesterday, seizing all of the
finest horses in place of their jaded animals.
Some few showed themselves near Washing
ton at Silver Springs five miles from the City,
they stoppod the stages which connect with
tbe Rail Roads.
s*—« i
From Mississippi.
Jackson, July I.—Captain Keer sunk two
steamers in the Mississippi a few days since.
Forty negro soldiers, captured by Gen. Ly
on near Port Hudson, arrived here this even
ing. They say they were forced to take up
arms.
Later from Getty soar?.
The Federal Army Reported Routed and 40,
--000 Prisoners Captured.
Martinsburg, July 6th.
On Satarday night our centre fell back
drawing the enemy from their works.
Ewell and Longstreet then flanked the ene-
Imy and gained the Heights.
A general fight ensued yesterday, in which
the Yankees were routed.
Lee captured FORTY THOUSAND PRIS
ONERS, according to all accounts.
Gen. Kemper was'killei.
There was fighting at Wilhamsport be
tween Imboden's Cavalry, with several regi
ments of infantry, and a DtvisiOn of Yankee
Cavalry under Pleasanton.
*m
Additional from tike Battles la
Peansylvaaia.
Later from Vicksburg—Meade's Loss •Report
J ed 60,000.
1 Richmond, 7.
The Tribune of the 4th contains many de
tails of the battle on Wednesday.
Brigadier Gen. Barksdale" is mentioned a;
twice wounded and a priseaer.
Brigadier Gen. Schemmelfing is a prisoner.
A telegram received says the fight was
most terrific; the loss on both sides tremen
dous.
We have Longstreet a prisoner sure.
If Couch arrived to-night the victory is
bound to change.
Philadelphia, 3d P. J_.—Stirring times in
town.
There is a current report "that Longstreet is
killed.
The siege of Vicksburg is said to be pro*
greasing satisfactorily, but the Rebels are re
garded as very obstinate.
New Orleans dates of the 27th report
nothing new at Port Hudson.
The Rebels overrun the country.
PETERSBURG, 7th.
The truce boat reached City Point this
morning. No papers were allowed to come.
Captain Milford states that Sickles is dead.
Passengers overheard one Federal say at
Fortress Monroe that the loss of Meade could
net be less than sixty tbeusand in killed,
wounded and missing.
r*
Tbe Jackson'Mississippian learns from a
reliable source that Gen. Price occupies He
lena, which is in Philips county, Arkansas
on the West bank of tbe Mississippi.
•r</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85025181/1863-07-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=lee+battle+fighting+gettysburg+pennsylvania+union+yankee+rebel+confederate&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.153,0.29,0.438,0.474,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Tho fighting at Gettysburg, on Wodncs-
J"""",
fri I... I rJi.l... .....1.
wnsonoouuo most uospcratc etiaracter,
aml l" losses on bot 811103 ,0!U1U1" 1,10
rcsults mny 1,0 ll,u9 8umlnci1 UP-
On Wednesday the enemy attacked the
advanco of our army, under command of
Generals Roynolds aud Howard, driving
lllom from Cashtown through and to tho
sol,lh of tl,c town of Gettysburg.
'nS Wednesday night and Thursday

'iaultsoou aftordaylight, and after noarly
twelve hours'esporato fighting was driven
(from Gctt'-iburg, leaving his killed and
wounded 'ii the fiold.tho who'c of which.at
the endJf tbo engagement, was iu the pos
Bcssio'ol'tbo Federal tronps.
0! Saturday it became apparont that
1.-.1 I.--- 1.. 1
mauc mem luvmcioio 10 every assault.
1 ho slaughter was terrible. The killed
(and wounded on both sides will nrobablv
rcaec jornj lliousana. J lie enemy cap-
turcd :bout thirtv-Gvc hundred prisoners,
mostly in the battle of Wednesday. Tho
Federal have taken about fivo thousaud
prisoners.
j Tho rebel? lost heavily iu their general
and fwld offioers. General Archer aud
Armistcad arc prifoners. General Garnet
is reported mortally wounded, and General
Barksdalo killed. Tho latter was buried
by our troops,
Genoral Hancock, Sickles, Zook. Gib-
bona and Warren wcro wounded. Gcn-
oral Reynolds, Paul aud Weed wcro kill.
,ed.
Gecoral Sickels was comfortably for-
waruee bv rai road to B.i timm-n
night.
i Tho report respecting tho death of Gen.
Longstreot aud (he capturo of Gen, Hill,
I of iho rebel armyarc not confirmed.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
