<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-standard-oil-monopoly</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85035524/1908-02-07/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1904&amp;index=14&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Fraud+Oil+Standard&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+fraud&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ROOSEVELT IN SCORCIII1 WORDS
ATTACKS THE LAW-DEPYING RICH
The President in a Special Message Compares Crimes
of Standard Oil to Murder, Fraud and
PUTS GAMBLERS IN STOCKS IN CLASS WITH CARO SHARKS
Asserts That Unscrupulous Men of Wealth Have Banded Together to*Attack
Ilis Administration and Bring About a Reaction.
Washington, D. C.—Never before, perhaps, in the history
of the country has a President of the United States defended his
policy in such impassioned language or made such a bitter attack
on his enemies and predatory wealth in general as President
Roosevelt does in a special message which he sent to both houses
of Congress.
His message was ostensibly for the purpose of recommend
ing legislation for the protection of the interests of the working
man, but he makes it the instrument by which he flays the
Standard Oil Corporation and the big railroad and financial in
terests of the country who are opposing him because of his poli
cies ; places the blame for the recent financial distress on a few
men of great wealth, and plainly intimates that there is a con
spiracy against him by the reactionaries of the country.
He does not recede one jot from his determination to curb
trust abuses and renews his recommendations for the enactment
of legislation that will give the Federal Government supervision
of the financial and physical operation of railroads and control
of law-defying wealth.
The President refers with very
strong feeling to the attacks that he
says are being made on him through
newspapers and public speakers con
trolled by the Standard Oil Trust and
other combinations and says the key
note of these attacks upon his efforts
to secure honesty in business and
politics is that they are unnatural
and unwarranted, and business panic
is the penalty.
Uke Plea of Gambler.
The morality of such a plea, he
says, is precisely as great as if made
on behalf of the men caught in a
gambling establishment raided by the
police and means that no effort should
be made to prevent a repetition of the
insurance, banking and railroad scan
dals in New York, the Chicago and
Alton deal, the successful effort by
the Standard Oil people to crush out
every competitor and to establish a
monopoly which treats the public
with a contempt it deserves so long
as it permits men of such principles
to avow and act on them with im
punity.
The “business” which is hurt by
the movement for honesty, the Pres
ident says, is the kind which in the
long run it pays the country to have
hurt; the kind which has tended to
make the name “high finance” a
term of scandal to which all honest
American men of business should join
in putting an end.
The opponents of the measures he
champions, Mr. Roosevelt says, single
out now one and now another for
special attack, as if the movement he
is engaged in was purely economic.
This is not so, he says, for it is funda
mentally an ethical movement and
one which must be persevered in until
the spirit which lies behind it sinks
deep into the heart and conscience of
the whole people. His purpose, he
declares, is to secure national honesty
in business and politics and equality
of opportunity for all, and he will not
hp swnvarl frnm it hv ftttank« on him.
Lairs Will Be Enforced.
The laws, the President insists,
must in future be administered as
they are at present, justice being
meted out with an even hand to great
and small, rich and poor, weak and
strong. And he adds that there
should be no delay in supplementing
the laws now on the statute books
with others he recommends.
Referring to the financial situation,
the President says there is a natural
tendency to feel gloomy and fright
ened at the outlook, but he declares
there is no justification for such a
feeling, as there is no nation so ab
solutely sure of success as ours, and
we must certainly succeed.
Not Responsible, He Says.
The President then disclaims any
responsibility for the business dis
tress, saying he does not believe for
a moment that any actions of the
Administration brought it on. It was
due, he says, to the speculative folly
and flagrant dishonesty of a few men
of great wealth, who seek to shield
themselves from the effect of then
own wrongdoing by ascribing its re
sults to the actions of those who have
tried to put a stop to the wrongdoing.
“But,” says the President, “if it
were true that to cut out rottenness
from the body politic meant a mo
mentary check to an unhealthy seem
ing prosperity, I should not for a mo
ment hesitate to put the knife to the
corruption.”
He advocates the immediate re-en
actment of the employers’ liability
law, limiting its scope to interstate
employment to conform to the ruling
of the Supreme Court; urges legisla
tion providing for compensation by
the Government and employers gen
erally to all employes for Injuries,
calls attention to the need of some
action in connection with the abuse of
injunctions in labor cases by the
courts and warns men of property
that they cannot afford to trust to
anything but the spirit of justice and
fair play.
Mr. Roosevelt assails stock gam
bling and the “cornering” of the mar
ket. He says there is no moral dif
ference between gambling at cards,
in lotteries, at the race tracks and
gambling in the stock market. It is
just as pernicious and in degree the
evil worked i3 far greater.
President’s New Platform.
Roosevelt’s platform, as he states
it in this second message, is as fol
lows: “We seek to control law-defy
ing wealth; in the first place to pre
vent its doing dire evil to the Repub
lic, and in the next place to avoid the
vindictive and dreadful radicalism
which, if left uncontrolled, it is cer
tain in the end to arouse.
“Sweeping attacks upon all prop
erty, upon all men of means, without
regard to whether they do well or ill,
would sound the death knell of the
Republic; and such attacks become
inevitable if decent citizens permit
those rich men whose lives are cor
rupt and evil to domineer in swollen
pride, unchecked and unhindered,
over the destinies of this country.
“We act in no vindictive spirit and
we are no respecter of persons. If
a labor union does wrong we oppose
it as firmly as we oppose a corpora
tion which does wrrong; and we stand
equally stoutly for the rights of the
man of wealth and for the rights of
the wage worker.
“We seek to protect the property
of every man who acts honestly, of
every corporation that represents.
wealth honestly accumulated and
honestly used. We seek to stop
wrongdoing , and we desire to punish
the wrongdoers only as far as it la
necessary to achieve this end.”
The Administration’s aim, the
President asserts, is to control law
defying wealth, and he asserts that
corporations and men of great wealth
have banded together to bring about
a reaction from this policy, hiring
writers to attempt to overthrow and
discredit all who honestly administer
the law.
Flays Standard Oil.
The Standard Oil Company and the
Santa Fe Railroad he specifically de
nounces. With regard to the former
he says:
“The methods by which the Stand
ard Oil people and those engaged in
the other combinations of which I
have spoken above have achieved
great fortunes can only be justified
by the advocacy of a system of moral
ity which would also justify every
form of criminality on the part of a
labor union, and every form of vio
lence, corruption and fraud, from
murder to bribery and ballot-box
stuffing in politics.”
In advocating laws better to secure
control over great business concerns,
especially great common carriers, Mr.
Roosevelt says the Interstate Com
merce Commission should be empow
ered to pass upon any rate or practice
on its own initiative, even to prohibit
an advance in rate pending examina
tion.
He says the Federal Government
should exercise supervision over the
financial operations of interstate rail
roads, and must also assume a cer
tain measure of control over their
physical operations. He favors traffic
associations.
After quoting from Lincoln, “with
malice toward none, with charity for
all; with firmness iu the right as God
gives us to see the right, let us strive
on to finish the work we are in,” the
President says: “In the work we of
this generation are in, there is,
thanks be to the Almighty, no danger
of bloodshed and no use for the
sword,” a3 “wo strive to bring nearer
the day when greed and trickery and
cunning shall be trampled under foot
by .those who fight for righteousness
that exalteth a nation.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90052331/1907-09-26/ed-1/seq-8/#date1=1904&amp;index=7&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+Trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>When I was a boy, there used to be, in one
of the “Advanced Readers,” a story which
made an indelible impression on my youthful
memory.
Under the heading of “Alexander and the
Robber,” was given a spirited conversation
which was alleged to have taken place be
tween the Macedonian Conqueror and a rob
ber-chief, whom he had captured.
In this conversation, Alexander the Great
upbraids the robber-chief for his crimes, and
the robber-chief defends himself by comparing
his own methods to those of Alexander him
self. My recollection is that the Macedonian
King started out promisingly in the discussion,
but that he steadily lost ground. At the close
of the conversation, the robber-chief had every
thing his own way. To speak in up-to-date
phraseology, the King had got himself “balled
up.”
In brief, the argument of the robber-chief
was about this: “I do just as you do; but I
don’t do as much of it.”
It is a pity that our “Readers” no longer
carry this story of “Alexander and the Rob
ber.” It would apply mighty well to latter
day conditions.
The world acclaims Alexander the Great
because he burnt the whole city instead of one
house, murdered a thousand instead of one
man, and robbed provinces instead of individu
als.
But after all, he was a mere robber. Fan
ciful theorists may prattle about the Helleniz
ing of Asia, but that is mere academic talk.
The world gained nothing, and lost much, by
the raid which Alexander made into Asia.
Hardy, enterprising Greece did not Hellenize
Persia and Assyria; on the contrary, the
effeminacy of the East flowed back to Greece,
along the lines of Alexander’s march, and
Greece lost her hardiness and enterprise. Per
sia, in the end, conquered Greece; as effeminate
Greece, in turn, conquered her conqueror,
Rome.
“Alexander and the Robber,” —the story
in the old time Reader came back to me when
the papers announced that the Chiefs of the
Standard Oil Trust were to hold a conference
at Fairhaven, Mass. That’s where H. H. Rog
ers lives. And H. H. Rogers is the Standard
Oil Chief who is being sued for $50,000,000
by a man who alleges that Rogers cheated,
him out of that amount of pocket change, in a
transaction concerning an improved process for
refining oil. And the Plaintiff must have had
the Defendant in a tight place, for Rogers’ son,
and Doctor, and Preacher went into court and
swore loudly that Rogers was too sick to come
to court. And the Judge continued the case
indefinitely, stating that it would be “cruel and
inhuman” to force such a sick man as Rogers
was to come to court. And immediately after
the case had “gone over,” I saw, in the Wash
ington Post, that Rogers, the sick man, had
taken Mark Twain out for an automobile ride,
and that Rogers, the sick man, had acted as
chauffeur.
Whether the Judge who continued the lit
tle fifty million dollar case has gone out and
hung himself, I do not know; but I guess that
Young Rogers, and Old Rogers, and Rogers’
Doctor and Rogers’ Preacher, laugh a good
deal among themselves at the neat manner in
which they tricked the Judge.
What I meant to say was this: When those
chiefs of the Standard Oil Trust meet at Fair
haverf, there will be, bunched together, the
most ravenous and remorseless band of robbers
this world has ever seen.
Long before Ida Tarbell had published her
magazine articles, Henry Demorest Lloyd had
given, in his “Wealth and Commonwealth,” a
complete history of the criminal methods of
this robber band. From Courthouse records
and other official documents, Mr. Lloyd proved
that the Standard Oil Company, with John D.
Rockefeller in active control, had violated al
most every penal statute of the Code.
These banded criminals had made use of the
vilest men and the vilest methods to stifle
competition and to kill off rivalry. The com
mon thief, the brazen perjurer, the house
wrecker, the murderer were useful instru
ments, used by this gigantic‘monopoly. Above
and beyond this lower level of criminal meth
od, came the corrupt influencing of elections,
the bribery of men in office, the subsidizing of
the Press, the corrupt control of the State
Legislatures and of Congress. In municipal
politics, in state politics, in national politics,
these rascals, who were gaining $125,000,000
every year, from one Trust alone, have exerted
their baleful influence—corruptly and crimi
nally.
Touch dozens of the Pet National Banks,
in whose behalf nearly $200,000,000 of the
nation’s wealth is annually laid aside—to be
used by them, free of interest, and you touch
the Standard Oil band.
Touch the monster railroad corporations,
which are taxing commerce to compel divi
dends on about seven billion dollars of fraud
ulent stocks and bonds —and you again touch
the Standard Oil band.
Touch the Cotton Seed Oil Trust, the Lum
ber Trust, the Copper Trust, the Steel Trust,
the Harvester Trust—and again you touch the
Standard Oil band.
For, these Alexanders of modern commer
cialism have not yet had to weep for more
worlds to conquer; their tired troops have not
mutinied at the Hyphasis, refusing to march
farther! No; these omniverous, insatiable,
irresistible men of the Oil Trust have continu
ed to add province to province, until in scope
of territory and richness of loot, their empire
is greater than that which fell before the
onset of the Macedonian King.
Not only the New World, but the Old bows
to the Rockefeller band. Not only the general
Government of the United States, but every
state in the Union, and every city in every
state, knuckles to the Standard Oil band.
The direct revenues of the Oil Trust is theirs
—5490,000,000 net profits in seven years. Then,
the profits of their banks, their railroads, their
copper mines; their holdings in the Steel Trust,
Lumber Trust, Harvester Trust, and many oth
er commercial enterprises, are theirs.
Think of what the Grand Total must be!
Compared to it, the National Treasury
shrinks into comparative insignificance.
The average increase of wealth in this coun
try is not more than five per cent.
When Express Companies pocket net earn
ings of 200 per cent; and the Standard Oil
Trust 1,000 per cent; and we have a dozen
other Trusts increasing their wealth in the
same proportion, there is bound to be some
class, or some classes, which are increasing
their wealth at a smaller rate than the average
five per cent, OR NOT INCREASING AT
ALL. Where some exceed the average, some
must fall below it. When the Steel Trust
gets so much more than the average; when
Express Companies, Railroads, Banks, Oil
Trusts, Whiskey Trusts and Sugar Trusts
get so much more than the average—there
must be many a million of men in America at
whose expense these Trusts get more than
their share.
When a band of robbers meets in their cave,
and gloats over the loot which fills it, one nat
urally thinks of the folks who were robbed.
Somebody had to lose what these robbers
stored away in the cave.
When the Standard Oil band meets at Fair
haven, the robbers will gloat over the vastest
accumulation of loot disclosed in the records
of the human race.
They have had a free rein for a full genera
tion. They debauched Public Opinion by
gifts to churches and schools; by the purchase
of public men, and by the employment of
Press Agents. They have enjoyed immunity
from punishment by hiring the best lawyers,
intimidating the witnesses who could not be
bought, and bribing the Judge where they
could not hire the Judge’s son or son-in-law,
or nephew to act as their “Attorney.”
From whom did the robbers take the loot—
THE ONE THOUSAND PER CENT NET,
PROFIT?
And how did they ever manage to steal so
much? /
The American people are the victims; and
the two old political parties supplied the ma
chinery by means of which the robbers filled
the cave.
The Standard Oil band have been enabled
to steal $490,000,000 from the American people
in seven years because the American voter
is so fond of the Democratic and Republican
parties that he would rather be robbed by
those Twins than to be protected by any new
political organization.
In other words, the fools are Wedded to the
Knaves AND NEITHER WILL SUE FOR
A DIVORCE.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1905-03-03/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1904&amp;index=17&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+trust+Trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE FIGHT against the Standard Oil Trust by
the people of Kansas is attracting world-wide
attention and people in all sections of the country
are showing their sympathy for Kansas. On Feb'
ruary 21, tho Illinois legislature adopted a reso
lution offering to lend tho state of Kansas tho sum
of $100,000 without interest, for a period of six
years to aid in establishing a stato oil refinery.
This resolution refered to the Standard Oil trust
as "that merciless octopu3 whoso tentacles now en
circle every state in tho union." Another resolu
tion provided for tho appointment of a joint com
mission to confer with the stato officials of Kansas
and to agree on steps to bo taken for pipe lines to
aid common carriers. Indiana oil producers havo
organized to fight the oil trust and they will urge
the erection of a stato refinery. Tho bill ha3 been
introduced in tho Texas legislature, making tho
pipe lines of that stato available to independent
producers and it is proposed by somo that tho
state erect a refinery. Oklahoma Is likowiso con
sidering tho erection of a stato refinery, together
with the proposition to make oil producers preserve
a uniform price throughout the stato.
AN INTERESTING DESCRIPTION of the trou
bles between Kansas and the oil trust is
given by Frank P. Gallagher, the staff correspon
dent for the Omaha World-Herald, in a dispatch to
that newspaper, under date of Topeka, Feb. 21. Mr.
Gallagher says: "It was a bitter experience with
the sinister influences of Standard Oil that led the
people of Kansas, but as late a3 two years ago tho
oil industry amounted to little. Twelve years ago
Standard Oil wriggled into Kansas under the de
ceptive title of the Forest Oil company. Depart
ing from its historic policy, the Standard Oil man
agement determined to develop the fields without
waiting for the people to catch the oil fever. Near
Neodesha, in Wilson county, many wells were
sunk, but the oil refused to gush-and the borings
were abandoned. Standard Oil relinquished its
leases to hundreds of acres and surrendered the
task of development to the prospectors and pro-
moters."
THE FIRST IMPORTANT STRIKE was made
by Charles Knapp, six years ago, at Chanute,
near one of the abandoned properties of tho For
est Oil company. A little later it was found that
Peru, Kan., was located on a vast oil deposit. Soon
nearly every town lot had its oil well, and the For
est Oil company returned to the field with renewed
vigor. As the business developed the Forest Oil
company underwent several changes. Its small
capitalization disappeared, and on January 7, 1901,
it took the name of the Prairie OH and Gas com
pany and increased it3 capital stock to $2,500,000.
Tho company then built pipe lines to Neodesha
from Chanute and at the latter point a refinery
was established. In 1902 the supply of oil was
still unsatisfactory to the Standard Oil folk, and
in order to create a boom it suddenly raised the
price of crude oil from 90 cents to $1.10 a barel.
The effect" was magical. In twelve months the out
put grew from 322,000 barels with a value of $289,
000 to 1,018,000 with a value of $1,120,018. A
greater part of the output was taken by the
S'tandard Oil company, but each day E. J. Web3ter,
who has built an independent refinery at Humboldt,
Kan., took 200 barrels.
IN THE MEANTIME, Standard Oil, according to
Mr. Gallagher, had been whetting its cimitar
with the intention of striking down tho entire Inde
pendent oil industry of Kansas. The capacity of
its plant at Neodesha was added to until it had
reached 300,000 barels of crude oil a day. The
pipe lines wore extended until tho main conduit
ran from Tulsa in the Osage nation south of the
Kansas 3tato line through Kansas to Kansas City,
Mo. At Caney, Neodesha, Altoona and Humboldt,
the Prairie Oil and Gas company built giant tanks,
and began to store oil. By January 1, 1905, it had
a total stock on hand of 5,448,034 barrels. Until
last August, when the Standard finished its sys
tem of pipe lines through the 3tate, oil had been
bringing prices ranging from $1.20 to $1.40 a bar
rel, according to its specific gravity. It was at
this juncture that Standard Oil sprung its trap,
in which the oil producers and consumers of Kan
sas and tho single independent oil refiner, E. J.
Webster, are still squirming, but with a show of
life that astonishes the captor. The price of crude
oil began to fall. In four reductions tho prices
wore cut to 72 cents for a barrol of tho best oil.
Another smash of 2 cents was mado on January
31, 1904. To what a low lovol prices for cnido oil
had sunk is illustrated In tho following compara
tive table: Wcstorn crude oil prlqes -32 dogroo
and above, 70c; 31 to 32, C5c; 31 to 31, GOc;
30 to 31, 55c; 30 to 30, 50c; 29 1-2 to 30, 45c;
29 to 291-2, 40c; 281-2 to 29, 35c; 28 to 281-2,
30c; 22 to 28 heavy, 29c per barrel. Bartlesvillo,
I. T., 82c per barrol. Eastern crude oil prices:
Pennsylvania, $1.40; Tlona, $1.55; Corning, $1.07;
Now Castle, $1.32; North Lima, 93c; South Ioina,
88c por barrel. Indiana, 88c; Somerset, 81c; Rag
land, 53c; Petrolla, Ont., $1.33 per barrol.
THE PRAIRIE OIL AND GAS COMPANY then
mado such rules relative to teats that tho
owner of a high quality of oil received no more
than one whoso output was of an inferior quality;
moreover, tho Standard Oil's inspectors did all
tho grading. In somo Instances they graded tho
oil high and when tho time camo to buy thoy re
graded the same oil in a lower classification. There
wore other injustices that aroused intense Indigna
tion among tho producers, but tho worst blow
was yet to fall. As soon as the Standard had com
pleted Its conduits it could transport Its oil with
out shipping by rail. This the Independent dealer
could not do. It was then that tho railways ad
vanced tho rates from 10 cents to 17 cents por
100 pounds. In addition to this, tho railways arbi
trarily ruled that a gallon jshould be hold to 7
instead of 4 pounds. Tho effect was to raise the
cost of shipping a car of oil to Kansas City and
other river markets from $$45 to $98. The further
effect was to prevent tho producers from shipping
their oil and thoy were compelled to accept Stand
ard Oil price3 at tho wells. Tho most remarkable
fact in this connection is that tho four railways
Involved, tho Santa Fo, the Missouri Pacific, tho
'Frisco and tho Missouri, Kansas and Texas, abso
lutely went out of the lucrative business of trans
porting oil and they did this simply because the
Standard had so commanded.
SPEAKING to this correspondent, J. M. Parker,
secretary of the State Oil Producers' asso
ciation, said: "If tho railways would give us tho
original rate of 10 cents per 100 pounds, or $45 a
car, we could ship all of our oil to Kansas City and
other points and it would give U3 $1 per barrel at
tho well. It would give the railways 100 carloads
of freight every day. But the Standard Oil com
pany tells the railroads to desist from hauling
any oil whatever, and by an exorbitant rate forc
ing us to sell to the Standard, the only market
in the fields, at a price of 47 cents a barrel, which,
under the compulsory rates demanded from tho
railways by the trust, nets the producer 7 cents
more than if he had used tho railways."
MR. GALLAGHER adds: "While the men who
are attacking Standard Oil realize the great
power of this corporation they express confidence
that Kansas will yet be able to gain the mastery.
I regretted that I could not bring to them better
cheer from Nebraska, the sister state. When I told
them that Nebraska, far from trying to cast off
the yoke of the octopus, was about to put it on by
erecting a Rockefeller memorial, I saw in their
eyes not a little consternation and a steely glint of
scorn and resentment. They have a habit of being
in deadly earnest down here. The people are a
unit against Standard Oil. Consequently it is dif
ficult for them to realize that any stato in the
union, least of all Nebraska, should regard Rocke
feller bondage with anything but aversion and hor
ror. Secretary Parker of tho Kansas Oil Pro
ducers' association gave expression to this idea
when he said: "The legislature of Nebraska is in
session. It has a duty to perform. It should take
such action as will render the acceptance of a de
grading gift front Rockefeller Impossible. Natur
ally it is inconceivable to us hero in Kansas that
such a plan 3hould ever have been entertained.
It would be dreadful if Nebraska should bo content
to wear such a badge of senility."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/46032385/1909-03-19/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1904&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard+trust&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil+Trust&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Three Important Judicial Decisions
-' The decision of the Missouri state supremo
court barring the Standard Oil trust from Mis
souri, the decision of Federal Judge McPherson
rdeclaring the Missouri two-cent passenger fare
rand maximum freight rate laws to be confisca
tory and, therefore, non-enforceable, and the
decision of Federal Judge Anderson at Chicago
'acquitting the Standard Oil trust, occurred,
f practically, during the same week.
It will not be surprising, therefore, if the
American people are inclined to view these three
: judicial results together.
Is it significant that the only relief from cor
porate imposition, so far as concerns legislative
action, has been given through the legislative
machinery ' of the states?
Is it significant that the one judicial opinion
seeking to apply the law to a powerful corpora
tion that has seemed so inclusive, so complete
as to bring the powerful lawbreaker to a posi
tion where it is actually willing to beg for terms
was rendered by the supreme court of a state?
Is it significant that on this occasion, as on
other occasions, the decisions upon which those
great corporations depend for escape from pun
ishment are rendered by federal courts?
No more important decisions have been ren
dered than the three herein referred to.
To be sure the decision barring the Standard
Oil trust from doing business in Missouri will
be appealed to the United States supreme court;
but it will not go to that high tribunal in any
deceptive .form. T.he highest court in the land
will be required to bluntly meet the issue -whether
the people of a' great state the very power
that creates corporations have the right to
specify the terms upon which these creatures
of law shall do business within the borders of
the commonwealth.
While Federal Judge McPherson's decision re-
lated directly to Missouri', two-cent passenger
rate law it will, if sustained, affect all other
two-cent rate laws; for if confiscation may be
shown in the great state of ivfissouri certainly
it may be shown in other and perhaps smaller
states. Indeed there are already signs that rail
road officials are laying plans for an organized
effort looking to a restoration of the three-cent
rate .wherever the two-cent rate has been put in
force.
From a fine of $29,240,000 by Judge Landis to
a verdict of acquittal by .Judge Anderson is a
long leap even for the Standard Oil trust that
is quite accustomed to rapid passage above
yawning chasms.
Judge Anderson based his verdict of not
guilty upon reasoning as follows:
That the law in the case as announced by
the circuit court of appeals governs and con
trols in the trial of the case and is binding upon
both court and jury and that this decision indi
cated that the government lad practically failed
to prove its charge.
That the government failed to establish the
very foundation of the charge against the oil
company in failing to prove that there was any
established or fixed rate of 18 cents between
Whiting, Ind., and St. Louis, and Chapoll, Ind.,
and St. Louis, a deviation from which was neces
sary to a violation of the Elkins act.
That the government In relying to prove the
eightcon-cent rate upon an unfixed, shifting and
changeable classification, In which only maxi
mum rates were named, and which classification
was prepared and fixed by the state railroad
and warehouse commission, which is a body en
tirely Independent of the federal authorities
regulating Interstate commerce, was relying up
on incompetent evidence.
That aside from the law and the insufficiency
of the evidence, there was a variation between
the counts in the indictment and the proof, and
that while the government charged one thing in
the Indictment It offered proof about an entirely
different thing.
That the fixed rates, assuming that even the
unproved elghteen-cent rate was an established
rate, had not been properly posted and pub
lished in accordance with the Elklns law pro
visions. The . Associated Press quotes "an Important
law officer of the government" as saying; "A
four-horse rebate team can be driven through
the Elklns law n,s It now stands after the de
cision of the United States court of appeals and
that of Judge Anderson in the Standard Oil case
at .Chicago. An attorney who could not protect
a' client from a charge of rebating, If those de
cisions are sustained, would not be worthy of
his hire."
This law officer pointed out that Judge Landis,
who Imposed the $29,000,000 fine upon the
Standard Oil company, held that it was the duty
of the shipper to make reasonable inquiry as
to whether the rate he was using was lawful or
not. Judges Grosscup, Seman and Baker of the"
United States circuit court of appeals, reversed
that statement of the law and held, substan
tially, that the government had to prove that
the shipper knew he was getting an illegal rate.
In the opinion of government officers that rarely,
if ever, could be done.
In this view Judge Anderson has not only
released the Standard Oil trust from all punish-
TI1E CONGRESSIONAL RECORD
The New York Evening Sun makes a timely
protest In behalf of the most Important govern
ment publication when it says:
"Mr. Taft's suggestion at the Carnegie hall
meeting for negro uplift, that perhaps his hear
ers read the Congressional Record provoked the
risibles of the audience. Nevertheless, the com
pendium of legislative proceedings to which he
referred could be read with profit by many
men who rarely or never see it, but profess to
take an intelligent interest In public affairs.
The inveracities of the Record, such as the post
delivery embellishment of speeches and the
publication of undelivered speeches under the
leave to print, are negligible in comparison with
Its veracities. Taken as a' whole, it furnishes a
quantity of useful information Indispensable to
an adequate knowledge of the workings of our
government."
A Commoner reader recently suggested that
the Congressional Record be made available
to every citizen at a stated price per year. This
' Is certainly a good suggestion. Instead of pok
ing fun at the publication wherein is recorded
the doings of the world's greatest legislative
'assembly, men who hope to participate in the
ment In this particular case but his decision,
followed by other federal judges, will mako it
Impossible to convict any one on the charge of
rebating.
When Judge Landis assessed the fine of $29,
240,000 against the Standard Oil trust there
were many who questioned tho policy of such a
large fine. There woro some who intimated that
it was a bit of demagogy on tho part of tho
federal judge who was brave enough to call to
account tho most powerful trust in tho world.
But nowhere, outside of tho pleadings filed by
tho attorneys for the trust, has any one ever
seriously contendod that tho Standard Oil trust
was not guilty of tho offense chargod against it.
The proof scorned so complete that a judge
whose ability aa a lawyer and whose character
as a man Js unquestioned assessed tho enormous
fine of $29,24 0,000. It was so complete that
public opinion which was somewhat divided as
to tho policy of assessing such an enormous fine
was practically unanimous in believing that tho
trust was guilty as charged. Yet In the light of
the opinion rendered by the court of appeals,
speaking through Judge Grosscup, Judge Ander
son is not only ablo to wipe out tho fine of
$29,240,000 but he is ablo to give a verdict of
acquittal a verdict that washes tho Standard
Oil trust "pure as tho driven snow."
Does any Intelligent man or women bpUovp
that tho republican managers would have, per
mitted, prior to election day, decisions which
destroys tho two-cent fare rate law and dis
charges the Standard Oil trust from accounta
bility for its lawlessness?
Does any ono believe that in the light of tho
tendency, of this day clearly showing tho utlor
indlfforonco to public opinion on tho part of
representatives of special interests tho work of
reformers is at an end?
Does any one imagine that popular govern
ment can be preserved for a long period of time
If this disposition to give license to corporate
lawlessness Is to continue unchecked?
Should not the very audacity of the champions
of tho trust system, the very contempt they
show for the public rights, encourage democrats
everywhere to renew their devotion to the cause
of the people? It is truo the people are generally
patient in enduring great wrongs; they are often
thoughtless In the presence of opportunity to
cure those wrongs; but always they are powerful
enough to crush the system that oppresses them
and, in all reason, they are human enough to
retaliate when their eyes have been opened to
tho solemn truth.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059523/1904-05-22/ed-1/seq-31/#date1=1904&amp;index=6&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Oil+Standard&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1911&amp;proxtext=Standard+Oil&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ANEW force in the
trust conflict is afield.
Spurred into action
by repeated attacks in the public prints, the
Standard Oil Trust -at last has come out of
the shadows and invaded the field of litera
ture, evidently proposing to try the effect of a
little publicity all its own.
This, at least, is the conclusion which
must be drawn from the study of a new phe
nomenon in the publishing#world. About a
year ago a book by Gilbert Holland Mon
tague, bearing the title "The Rise and Pro
gress of the Standard Oil Company," made
an appearance. It was published by Harper
&amp; Brothers, and that house, with unique gene
rosity, has undertaken to give the little vol
ume a wide circulation.
LAST fall the libraries of the country—North,
South, East and West—began to receive free
copies. A slip Inserted in each volume an
nounced that it came "With the compliments of
Harper &amp; Brothers." Free distribution of the book
has recently taken a fresh spurt.
College professors and clergymen all over the
country are now receiving copies, also with the com
pliments of Harper &amp;%rothers. Why Messrs. Harper
&amp; Brothers have suddenly become so liberal is the
question no one seems able to give adequate answer.
AFTER reading the volume little doubt remains in the
mind of the gentlemen favored, however, that Har
per &amp; Brothers represent, ana, indeed, are acting
for, the Standard Oil Company in this literary propaganda.
The book, as one critic of note has aptly said, is simply a
brief for the Standard Oil Company. It might, indeed,
very well have been written by their eminent attorney, S.
C. T. Dodd. In fact, the information comes directly from
no less authority than John D. Rockefeller himself that
Dodd did have something to do with the book.
A few months ago Mr. Rockefeller was talking with
an old friend about-the articles on the Standard Oil Com
pany now appearing In one of the popular magazines.
"They are not true," Mr. Rockefeller said pathetically.
"If you want a true history of the Standard Oil Company
you should read Montague's. Dodd helped Montague."
Anybody who has read the many defenses of the
Standard Oil Company written by Mr. Dodd, and com
pared them with the little volume now being so com
pletely circulated, can easily believe that Dodd did help
Montague.
"DOOK THAT WENT BEFORE
° TOLD THE OTHER SIDE
The situation is rather amusing when the fact la
recalled that some fifteen years ago the Harpers brought
out that vivid and violent attack upon the Standard Oil
Company by Henry D. Lloyd, entitled "Wealth vs. Com
monwealth."
This book made a tremendous sensation In its time.
Intemperate and one-sided though it might be considered,
It was documented so thoroughly that the Standard Oil
Company was never able to refute or even to answer it
The magnates of the Standard Oil are said to have been
very indignant at the Harpers for publishing such a
book, and when four or five years ago the publishing
company failed, they were not a little rejoiced.
It will be remembered that after their failure the
Harpers fell into the hands of Colonel George Harvey
Now Colonel Harvey has always been, more or less asso
ciated with corporate interests. It could not be expected
that with his associations he would look with any sym
pathy on such work as that by Mr. Lloyd.
No doubt he was glad to make peace with Mr Rocke
feller by publishing Mr. Montagues "Brief for the Stand
ard Oil Company." It is reported that the book was
THE GREAT OIL TRUST MASTER IN THE ACT OF.
TELLING MINISTERS THE VIRTUES OF
\ HIS METHODS, WHILE THE *
\ OCTOPUS LISTENS
Bl in glee
THE St. PAUL GLOBE SLlNiiA\, MAY 2C 1901
Great Trust Master's Story Trips Its
~ Readers Into Mistaken Beliefs by the Great
Truths It Does Not Tell, Declares This Critic
[the nvriter, from years of intimate acquaintanceship ivith
the secret history of the Standard Oil and its business methods,
says he is able to substantiate e-very statement made beloav.
For personal reasons, hoiicvet, he requested the editor to
withhold his name.]
bought outright by Mr. Harvey. Then the free distribution
began.
It seems hardly likely that Mr. Harvey -would be
bo generous as to give all the libraries, clergymen and
college professors in the United States, 150,000 of them,
free copies of a dollar booK. All things considered, it
seems very fair to conclude that the real distributer of
the book is Mi-. Rockefeller, or the Standard Oil Com
pany, in whose interests it is so apparently written and
published
To any one at all familiar with the history of the
Standard Oil Company and the methods it pursues, the
book written by Mr. Montague offers interesting, though
perhaps somewhat irritating, reading. The argument of
the book is based upon the assumption that when Mr.
Rockefeller began to wipe up early refiners he was by far
the strongest refiner in the United States. This is an
inexcusable mistake.
HOW MR. ROCKEFELLER BECAME
THE BIGGEST AMERICAN REFINER
At least ten other operators in the United States pos
sessed refineries as large and as economical of operation
as Mr. Rockefeller when he started out. Mr. Rockefeller
obtained his whip hand in the oil business through a
scheme known as the South Improvement Company.
Mr. Montague slides over this scheme in a beautifully
general way, representing it as very similar to the rail
road pools then in progress. He says that when the South
Improvement Company attempted to gather control of
the oil business, it included among its members the
strongest group of refiners in the country, the combined
capacity of whose plants exceeded by far that of the un
organized refiners.
This is a fundamental mistake. The South Improve
ment Company, when its great scheme was sprung, con
trolled, according to the best statistics of trade at that
time, just 4500 barrels a day. At that time 45,000 barrels
were produced in the United States every day.
RAILROADS HAD TO BEAR
ALL THE HARSH CRITICISMS
Mt. Montague overlooks the fact entirely that Mr.
Rockefeller obtained his extraordinary lead in the oil
business by using the contracts of this secret company
to scare the early independent trade out of Cleveland.
Within three months Mr. Rockefeller literally bluffed
twenty refiners in that city to sell to him. Where before
the daily capacity of his refineries was 1500 barrels, he
raised it to 10,000. It was in this way that Mr. Rocke
feller became the biggest refiner in the country, not, as
Mr. Montague says, through the_ superior efficiency of
his methods.
According to Mr. Montague the rebates which Mr.
Rockefeller secured were the regular thing in the busi
ness. They were always, he asserts, awarded to the big
gest shippers. He overlooks the fact that from the be
ginning of Mr. Rockefeller's career the entire outside oil
industry was united against the rebate system. The
operators almost unanimously fought in Congress, in the
Legislatures, in the courts and in the press against it.
Never at any time after Mr. Rockefeller began the use of
the rebate system to unjustly gain power did the oil in
dustry consent to it. Not only did the individual operators
combine against the system, but the courts declared it
to be contrary to public policy. Nevertheless it was con-
One of the most outrageous features of the rebate
system as practiced by the Standard Oil Company was
obtaining drawbacks on other people's shipments. The
fact that the Standard Oil Company did such a thing is
established by documentary proof. And yet Mr. Montague,
from start to finish of his book, scarcely alludes to this
practice!
One would suppose from the book written by Mr.
Montague that everything the Standard Oil Company
has done was in accordance with accepted busi
ness practices, and that everybody else in the
oil trade did the same. As a matter of fact,
there was always an organized opposi
tion, supported by both press and
courts, against most of the things
*By an Expert
Mr. Rockefeller was doing.
All the way through the book, wherever allusion is
made to an unjust practice by the Standard, It is charged
to the railroads. This is an old dodge of the Standard.
Somebody else is always forcing it to do wicked things.
As an illustration of the way the terrible raids upon
other people's business by the Standard are treated, it is
interesting to note Mr. Montague's allusion to the union
of the Tidewater Pipe Line and the Standard Oil Com
pany in 1883. The decrease of rates in freight to the
Standard which followed the success of the first seaboard
pipe line is charged to the railroads. As a matter of
fact, the Standard Oil, in order to block competition,
forced the railroads into making contracts with it. When
the Tidewater by a series of business moves, only fair to
call piratical, was pressed into an alliance, Mr. Montague
mentions it in one line.
SECRET BESIEGING, DIRECT
ATTACKS AND UNDERSELLING
"Finally," he writes, "the Tidewater was forced to
cease its opposition"!
Many curious errors are" to be found In this book.
They are of such a nature as to gloss over the specific
criticisms generally filed against the Standard Oil Com
pany. Nobody denies that the company has conducted its
business with remarxable ability. Nobody denies, either,
that Mr. Rockefeller and many of the gentlemen com
bined with him were leaders in the oil business from the
start. But that they could have built up their present
great monopoly without the use of special privileges, or
without persistent attacks on everybody who has at
tempted to enter the oil business during the past thirty
years, nobody can believe.
It is clearly established that, by besieging the rail
roads secretly and insistently, they obtained special rates.
By direct attacks they forced the various pipe line sys
tems to sell out to them. By a system of criminal under
selling, practiced persistently all over the country, they
have driven refiners out of business, and maintained the
price of refined oil.
These are actual facts, which can be proved by docu
ments. But Mr. Montague glides over them without as
much as a glance, and represents the great combination
as the inevitable result of superior methods and the oper
ation of natural law.
Especially ingenious is Mr. Montague's closing para
graph. .
"The power of the Standard Oil Company," he writes,
"is tremendous, but it is only such power as naturally
accrues to so large an aggregation of capital. In the per
sistence with which competition against it has continued,
in the quickness with which that competition
increases when opportunity for profit under
existing prices appears, and in the ever-pres
ent possibility of competition lie the safe
guards against the abuse of this great
power."
A most casual investigation would con
vince any unprejudiced mind that the oppor
tunities for profits have, indeed, not been re
stricted for the Standard Oil Company.
Hundreds of millions of dollars realized by
their methods prove the fact to be a fact.
But that the safeguards against the great
power, mentioned by Mt. Montague, are not
operative is also proved by the long record
for lawlessness and destruction made by the
Standard Oil.
It seems a very clever trick upon the part
of Mr. Rockefeller to circulate such a con-
Eoling book. It serves a double purpose. It
is at once a balm to his injured feelings and
dust in the public eye.
It appears, however, still up to Mr.
Rockefeller to prove that a great variety
of untoward acts described in the public
prints are not true before he can
expect the public to
accept Mr. Mon
tague's book
eve</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88086023/1904-10-18/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Octopus+Standard+Oil+Control+Railroads+Rockefellers&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.042,0.804,0.443,0.48,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Standard Oil Company ii'lw Control
of Many ltallroails.
New York. Oct. 17. Wall street Is
watching while Standard Oil gradual
ly but suvely dominates the railroad
?vstems of the country. Changes in
directorates of various trunk lines
foreshadow complete ascendancy of
Standard Oil Interests in the most Im
portant railroad systems of the coun
try and the elimination of the tradi
tional power of the Vanderbllt-Mor-gan
party.
Within the last three years the
Rockefellers have gradually obtained
a foothold In the New York Central;
New York. New Haven Hartford,
Chicago Northwestern and other
lines usually known as Vanderbllt
Morgan railroads.
New methods of doing business will
be introduced in the New York Cen
tral railroad. One of the most Im
portant changes. It is said, will be the
retirement of Senator Depew, chair
man of he board of directors.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1905-02-20/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Kansas+Strikes+Standard+Oil+Opposes+Transfer+Big+Octopus+Frenzied+Revolt&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.398,0.471,0.484,0.525,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Opposes Transfers to
the Big Octopus
Legislature Passes Six Bills
as Result of Frenzied
Revolt

Topeka Kan., Feb. 20. The Oil Pro
ducers' Association has engaged Sena
tor Fitzpatriek and Representatives
Beekman to go to Washington to op
pose the transfer of the Foster leases
in Indian Territory to the Standard Oil
f "mmny. The Kansas delegation in
congress will be asked to oppose the
transfer.
A Topeka special says: The state of
Kansas, with $400,000 and a stiff
backed population, has set about the
task of fighting Standard Oil, with
$400,000,000,000, and tentacles spread
ing all over tho United States and for
eign countries. The battle between the
Sunflower state and the greatest of all
monopolies nnd its ultimate outeomo
will be worth watching.
Back of tho state of Kansas are
powerful influences which have not yot
appeared upon the canvas. The peo
ple of the state have appealed to Thos.
W. Lawson, of Boston, who has already
paid his sarcastic compliments to
Standard Oil, to take the generalship
of the fight, but it is doubtful if he
will accept. However, it is figurod he
may bo relied upon for any friomlly
counsel.
In six days the Kansas legislature
has passed the anti-trust legislatien:
Anti -discrimination bill Aimed at
.standard Oil.
Maximum freight rate bill To pre
vent railroads favoring Standard Oil.
linilroad commission bill To pro
vent Standard Oil dominating stato
railroads.
Stato refinory bill To compote with
Standard Oil.
Anti-gas pumping bill To prevent
use of artificial powor, thus keeping
Kansas gas within her borders.
Pipe lino common carrior act
Throws open oil conduits to all competition.
Delegations of hundreds of stalwart
ami determined men swarmod up to the
state capital today from the oil fields
and positively demanded that tho bill
pass. It is also true that not all of
theso min were oil producers. l"n their
ranks one could see many speculators
men who have invested in "wild
cat" oil schemes. Those men are anx
ious that the stock they purchased at
10 cents on the dollar should become
worth a trille more than the paper up
on whirh the certificates are written.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1905-02-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Congressman+Campbell+Standard+Oil+Fraud+Regulation&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.108,0.868,0.297,0.322,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Campbell Again Has Con.
ference With Iloosevelt.
Senate Wants Other Trusts In
cluded in Investigation.
Washington, Feb. 21. Senator Long
this morning received a telegram from
the president of the Kansas senate and
speaker of the Kansas house of repre
sentatives containing the text of the
concurrent resolution of the Kansas
legislature in regulation to what is
known as the Foster lease in the Osage
Indian reservation declaring against the
extension of the lease.
Senator Long at once called for the
president and secretary of interior and
they informed him that the matter had
been definitely settled and that their
decltion in the matter would not be
changed.
It was stated that an agreement had
been reached between the secretary of
a. '"-r"v V' i
,iZ J TiTT"--.-.-'
X 7
I' yy
Congressman P. P. Campbell of Kansas Who Has Become Famous for His
Fight on Standard Oil.
Interior and the oil men interested in
the extension of the lease which agree
ment had bean inserted as a provis
ion in the Indian appropriation bill re
ported yesterday to the senate.
The president and secretary of inter
ior were very positive in stating that
this agreement was satisfactory to
them and would be carried out.
The provision is to the effect that
any allottmerts on Osage reservations
in Oklahoma made under the Foster
blanket lease of March 16, 1X96, which
leases and sub-lea.e were executed pri
or December 31. 1904. or executed after
that date based on contracts made
prior thereto and approved by the sec
retary of interior, "To the extent of
680.0'XI acres in the aggregate," are ex
tended for a period of ten years from
March 16, 1906, and provision is also
made for increase on royalty on gas
from $50 to J100 per annum.
Representative P. P. Campbell re
ceived a similar telegram containing
the Fitzpatrick resolution. Mr. Camp
bell also visited the president and later
in the day consulted with Senator Long
in regard to the matter.
Senator Long presented to the senate
today a copy of the concurrent resolu
tion number 21 of the Kansas house of
representatives which he received today
from J. R. Burrow, secretary of state
and which provides that "Our represen
tative in congress be requested and our
senators directed to prepare, urge and
perfect such national legislation as will
control the Standard Oil company and
protect the oil industry in Kansas from
destruction by the greatest monopoly
the world has ever known."
Representative Campbell again visit-
ea tne president today and conferred I
with him further regarding the gov-1
ernmental investigation of standard nil
The president again took occasion to
assure Mr. Campbell and through the
senate of Kansas that investigation
would be most thorough.
The Kansas legislature has taken
another rap at the Standard Oil com
pany. Both houses have adopted a
resolution calling upon our congress
men to prevent the renewal of the
oil leases in the Indian Territory and
to work to annul the Standard's leases.
This is interesting, because it is sup
Posed that at least one member of
the Kansas congressional delegation is
very much concernea m the Indian
Territory oil leases.
The senate Monday afternoon adopt
ed the following resolution presented
by Senator Fitzpatrick:
"Whereas, The Standard Oil company
has a blanket lease for oil and gas of
the Osage Indian reservation, known
as the 'Foster lease,' which, if it con
tinues to hold, will make it able to de
stroy private producers and drive them
out of business; and
"Whereas, The secretary of interior
has declared in public prints that this
lease, which is commonly known as the
Foster lease,' passed into the control
and ownership of the said Standard Oil
company by fraud; and
"Whereas. The secretary of the inter
ior has consented under protest to re
new to the Standard Oil company, o"r
its agents and representatives, the lease
of nearly 700,000 acres of this land; and
"Whereas, The 700,000 acres he has
selected is in the heart and body of the
oil and pas portion of the reservation,
leaving for individual lessees or pur
chasers only pasture land; and
"Whereas, The said 700,000 acres is the
richest portion of the western oil field,
and its continued use and development
by the Standard Oil company would add
to the power of that,company to anni
hilate other production; and
"Whereas, The Standard Oil company
has been declared by public opinion to
be an outlaw, and by its tyrannival prac
tices and unfair competition the enemy
of honest commerce; therefore, be it
"Resolved, By the senate of the state
of Kansas, the house concurring there
in, that the president, the secretary of
interior, and the congress of the Uni
ted States be, and they are hereby re
quested to hold up and annul the said
'Foster lease," in whole, which the sec
retary of interior has declared in pub
lic statement was originally obtained
by fraud.
"Resolved, Further, that copies of
this memorial be telegTaphed by the
president of the state senate, and the
speaker of the house, to the president
of the United States, the secretary of
interior, the president of the senate, the
speaker of the house, the Hon. Chester
I. Long and the Hon. P. P. Campbell;
and that Senator Long and Representa
tive Campbell give it as wide publicity
as possible.
"Resolved, Further, especially ad
dressing the Kansas delegation in con
gress, that this is a contest of the hon
est industry of the land against insolent
greed and commercial out-lawry, and it
is the duty of all men who hold offi?e
by the suffrage of the people of Kansas
to help in a war which their state ha3
first declared by legislative action."
The vote on the resolution was as fol
lows: yeas Betts, Elaker, Brewer, Buschow.
Chapman. Sonnor. Dolley, Fitzpatrick,
Fulton. Getty, Gilbert, Griffin, Has
kell, Hodgts. Huffman, Hughes. Mar
tin of Bourbon, Martin of Woodson. Por
ter of Crawford. Quincy, Simons. Smith of
Edwards. Stillings, Tucker, Wilkerson,
Young 26.
Nays Benedict, Benson, Lower, Noftz
ger. Porter of Montgomery, Smith of
Franklin, Waggoner 7.
Absent Hamme. Harrison, Hayden.Mil
ler. Peck, Stewart 6.
Senators Benedict, Samuel Porter and
Noftzger opposed the. resolution on the
ground that the statements made could
not be substantiated. This brought Sena
tor Fitzpatrick to the defense of the res
olution and in a lengthy speech he gave
the history of the "Foster lease."
He told of the round about way in which
the Standard Oil secured the blanket
lease on the 700.000 acres of oil lands in the
Osage reservation.
"The senators here who have spoken
about this 'Foster lease' know whom I
speak of when I refer to "the gentleman
from Wisconsin,' and I get it from this
gentleman from Wisconsin that he had
made arrangements to enlist every promi
nent politician in the interests of the In
dian Territory Illuminating Oil company
to secure a rowan! of that lease," said
Senator Fitzpatrick In part. "Those who
have been in Washington have been there
in the intcreMs of this company.
"With a weapon, such as 700.000 acres of
blanket leased oil lands, the Standard Oil
will he able to supply th.s countrv and
the world with oil and it will be impos
sible for any independent refinery to sur
vive against those who own the refineries,
the pi;e lines, the cars and such a lease.
When the people of this country are ris
ing up in every town and village to ask
that this monster be crushed, then for the
government to step in and lease a reser
voir of 700.000 acres of oil. is something the
government will not knowinglv do."
Senator Smith, from Franklin, explain
ed his vote against the resolution by say
ing that the style of literature in the res
olution reminded him of a heated cam
paign speech, and he was opposed to the
language and not to the resolution.
The Fitzpatrick resolution concern
ing the Foster lease was sent imme
diately to the house and there it was
passed by a unanimous vote. The
memorial was telegraphed to Wash
ington, to the officials named in the
resolution, last night at a cost of $65.
Resolutions Offered in Lower
House of Legislature.
Backing Up Kansas in Her Fight
on the Standard.
WOULD LOAN US MONEY
Propose to Furnish 100,000
JVithout Interest.
For a Period of Six Years for
Refinery Project.
CALLS FOR COMMITTEE.
To Confer With Our Legislature
on Subject.
Expresses Accord With Effort
for Commercial Freedom.
Springfield, 111., Feb. 21. The house
today adopted two resolutions affect
ing the Standard Oil company. One
offered by Representative Allen offers
to loan the state of Kansas the sum
of J 100,000 without interest for a
period of six years to aid in establish
ing a state oil refinery and refers to
the Standard Oil company as that
"merciless octopus, whose tentacles
now encircle every state in the union."
The resolution was adopted by a close
viva voce vote amid considerable con
fusion and laughter.
A resolution by Representative Mc
Goorty of Chicago asks for an investi
gation of the laying of pipe lines
through Illinois by the Standard Oil
company and provides for the appoint
ment of a joint committee to confer
with the state officers of Kansas to
agree on steps to be taken toward de
claring such pipe lines common car
riers. This resolution was adopted
without a dissenting vote. Mr. Allen
is a Republican and Mr. McGoorty a
uemocrat.
The McGoorty resolution declares the
present house to be in hearty accord
with the fight of the Kansas legislature
for commercial freedom.
Representative McGoorty explained
when the resolution was introduced
that it was not intended to make any
investigation of the Standard Oil com
pany. "I merely want an investigation of
the pipe line which now extends to
Galesburg and Monmouth," he said.
"This, pipe line later extended to In
diana. If necessary the report of the
committee .appointed may be followed
by a bill to make the company a com
mon carrier and subject to the same
regulations and penalties."
The text of the resolution is as fol
lows: "Whereas, The state of Kansas,
through its legislature and chief execu
tive has taken steps and adopted meas
ures to provide against the aggression
of the Standard Oil company.
"Whereas, Kansas has become a great
oil producing state and under proper
enabling legislation purposes to supply
to the consumer oil and its bi-products
in defiance of threats of extermination
and ruin, reported to have been made
against said state by Standard Oil com
pany, and
"Whereas, In this regard the assertion
by Kansas of her rights and powers as
a sovereign state of this union, has
awakened the hope that this most me
nacing of all combinations is amenable
to the law of the land, and
"Whereas, It is reported that pipe lines
and conduits controlled by the Standard
Oil company, extending from the oil fields
of Kansas to certain cities of the state of
Illinois intend to supply oil to such cities
are rapidly apiroaching completion and
that such pipe lines are proposed to ex
tend across the state to its eastern boun
darv; and,
"Whereas, The people of this state have
the right to know and be fully advised as
to the purpose of the Standard Oil com
pany In this regard and under what rights
and terms it may claim as a common car
rier or in any other capacity; now, there
fore, be It
"Resolved. By he house of representa
tives of the general assembly of Illinois,
the senate concurring therein, that a joint
committee of this Joint assembly consist
ing of five members, be appointed forth
with, three of whicj shall be appointed by
this house and two of which members
shall be appointed by the senate, for the
purpose of conferring and communicating
with the Kansas legislature and its state
officers and determining and representing
to this general assembly and to both
branches thereof, the scope and extent of
said pipe lines and such other information
necessary to enable this general assem
bly to safeguard and protect the people of
this state and its commercial interests. Be
it further'
"Resolved. That the members of this
general assembly are in hearty accord
with the efforts of the Kansas legislature
and its chief executive in the great fight
for commercial freedom."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99063957/1905-08-25/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Kansas+Ida+Tarbell+Rockefeller+Standard+Oil&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.101,0.348,0.681,0.738,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>What lias Happened la Kansas.
Miss Ida M. barbell, in the Septem
ber McCluro's emashos Iho last refuge
of thoso apologists of John D. Rockc
fcllor and v his associates who, whon
tainted monoy discussion was rifo,
cried that if Standard Oil had been
an offender onco it had now reformed,
and put itsolf nbovo reproach..
"If ono wants a noat demonstra
tion," says Miss Tarboll, "complete to
tho Inst detail, that the Standard Oil
Company is today, as always, con
spiracy in restraint of trade,' ho should
go to Kansas. Tho 'oil war' in that
state, which in turn amused, bowil
dorcd and excited tho country during
tho earlier months of tho present year,
was tho direct result of a suddon real
ization by tho Knnenns that tho Standv
nrd had been playing in tholr torrltory
a gamo 30 years old, playing it under
their vory noses so quickly and doftly
that, koon as thoy prido thomsolves on
being, thoy had not realized its moan
lug until thoy began to fool tho pres
surol" Tho story of tho Standard's attempt
to gobblo .tho Kansas oil Hold is tho
history of ita earlier practical aggres
sions repeating itself, but with a dif
ferent onding. In Kansas it encoun
tered a now'brand of public spirit, and
wont into .tho contest with this onlight
onod and electric commonwealth, han
dicapped by its post sins; tut for a
whllo, until public sontimont was
Jnrousod, Standard Cdl had ovorythlng
its own way.
Miss Tarboll lolls In tho Soptombcr
number what Standard Oil did to Kan-
sas, how it enmo into tho ptato after
fortune had boon sunk in locating
tho oil, and by tho operations of its
old, wol-trlcd juggurnaut, tho railroad
rate, proceeded! to gobblo tho fruits of
tho pioneers' sowlbg. Miss Tarboll
shows in tho clearest and most inform
ing way just how tho railroad operat
ed as tho socrot allies of tho Stand
ard. Tho wholo railroad situation ap
pears In mtniaturo in this story of tho
Standard Oil's smothering of tho Kan
sas oil Industry. What happonod thoro
Is going on nil ovor tho- "United Statos,
but tho Kansnns nro tho only Ameri
cans who havo put tho sttHo abovo
'special privilege "You may bo in
vesting $15,000,000 for taking caro of
our oil," eald tho pooplo. "You may
do tho work moro promptly and per
fectly than nny othor concorn ovor
could, but justlco is moro important
than millions, and every man shall
havo a cbanco in Kansas. Wo aro go
ing to stop your gamo. You must play
fair with ui If you stay In Kansas.
This is not tho tono that stntos usu
ally adopt toward tholr' business rul
ers. Kansas is tho first to try It. What
has boon tho conscquonco to Kansas
of this determined attitudo, Miss Tar
boll xosorvos for tho Octobor numbor,
in which sho will tell "What Kansas
Did to Standard Oil."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1906-05-10/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Grafting+Exposed+Standard+Oil+Topeka+Wilhoit+Espionage+Cheated&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.234,0.374,0.209,0.227,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>MORE GRAFTING
IS EXPOSED
CHICAGO, May 10. —E. M. Wil
hoit of Topeka, former Standard
Oil agent, at the Interstate com
merce commission hearing today
testified that tho Standard Oil com
pany ordered him to pay for in
formation concerning competitors
and that the Standarl Oil main
tained an ospolnago system through
out the country. "Water White,"
"Perfection" and "Headlight" are
three grades of oil gold from the
same tank. Ho said:
"I know I cheated, hut so they
instructed me. The Standard Oil
company values a man only by the
dirty work he does. Self respect
compelled me to quit. I used
chocks to bribe railroal employes,
as I told the commission. The San
to Fe and other railroads reduced
tariffs as gifts to tho Standard Oil
company."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1907-10-31/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Standard+Oil+Trust+Kansas+Supreme+Court</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>OIL TRUST HEARD
Standard Files Its Replies in
Supreme Court.
Kansas Business Not Directed
From 26 Broadway.
86' Broadway. Here are a few of -the
questions ana answers:
Q From whom, if any person, does
the Standard Oil company of Kansas
purcnase crude our
A From the Prairie Oil 1 and Gas
company.
Q To whom and Jn what manner
does the Standard Oil company of
Kansas sell refined oil. gasoline, and
other oil Droducts?
The answer shows that the oil is all Found That It Ended Sooner
som to me eranaara uii companies or
DALTOyETURNS.
His Four Months Parole Ex
pires Today.
HOW IT
Indiana, Kentucky, New Tork, Ne
braska, and Ohio; to the Continental
OPERATES. I company and the Granby Mining
omeuinr company.
Q By whom and in what manner
are the prices fixed at which the
Than Expected.
HOCH CANT BE FOUND
Prairie Oil Company Merely a standard ou company of Kansas pur- Was Thought That He Would
cuncrcs truos on ana ai wnicn it sens
refined oil, gasoline and other oil pro
aucts
A The Standard Oil
Frcducing Concern.
Be Pardoned.
Enormous Sums Paid in DiTi-
dends on Kansas Holdings.
company of
ZSZmF.iX rud.? 0,1 a e "ket Says That He Has Been Treated
prices and sells oil products at prices!
This was Standard Oil day in the
Kansas supreme court. Amended an
swers in the Standard Oil ouster suits
were filed by the Standard Oil of Kan
sas, the Standard Oil of Indiana, and
the Prairie Oil and Gas company. The
two former filed with the court their
answers to all the interrogatories pro
pounded by the state.
In the amended answers and in the
replies to the interrogatories, the fact
Is freely admitted that the Standard Oil
companies of Kansas and of Indiana
are owned by the Standard Oil com
pany of New Jersey; that the Prairie
Oil and Gas company is owned by the
National Transit company, and that
the Standard Oil of New Jersey owns
the National Transit.
This in itself would constitute a
prima facie case against the Standard
for violation of the anti-trust laws, but
the answer sets forth the novel defense
that each of the companies does its own
line of work, and is in no sense a corn-
fixed by itself.
Tables are presented to show the
amount of the product of the Kansas
company and the total gallons of re
nnet! oils, napthas. gas oils, fuel oils,
lubricating oils, asphalt and acid oils
are as xonows:
1903
1904...
1S0S
Well In Topeka.
At 3:10 this afternoon, Emraett
Dalton, who for four months has been
out on parole from the state peniten-
19,573,992 tiary, took the Union Pacific train for
31.517,713 ILansing, to reenter tne state peniten
47,179.632 tiary, under a life sentence.
CLOSE UP TIIE 'ARCHWAYS.
No Vehicles "Will pass
State House.
Around the
isuo... 66. 088,005 I Rowmnr Tlnnh. Khn It lean thomht
Q Is it not true that the Standard I r..i.. n.,ni.
mr.r Tr l I c-.c.v. I""
w" .cSm.. K,. ,i un
reports of all Its business to the
Standard Oil conmanv of New Jersey? not returned to lopeka, and ail er-
A No
The answers of the Standard Oil
company of Indiana are very similar to
those of Kansas, being prepared by
Alfred L. Kday. the general attorney
and attested by William P. Cowan, vice
president of the Standard Oil of Indi
ana. In the list of stockholders of the
Standard Oil of Indiana appear
such well known names as John D.
Archbold, 1.801 shares, H. H. Rogers,
2.001 shares. W. H. Tilford's profits
on his shares have by his orders been
paid to the Standard Oil company of
New Jersey. There have never been
more than ten or a dozen shareholders.
peting company, and consequently no I Back in 1900, J. D. Rockefeller's name
appears as owning one share. Then in
1901, he dropped out, and William
Rockefeller appeared On the list for
one share. William Rockefeller stuck
until early in 1903, when his name
ceases to appear.
Bearing In mind that the capital
stock of the Standard Oil company of
Indiana was only 11,000,000, it is in
teresting to observe the size of the
dividends paid. They are listed as fol
lows:
June 7, 1900. 749.925
Sept. 12. 1900.
Dec. 20, 1900...
March 18. 1901.
May 29, 1901...
combination has been formed.
The answer alleges that the Prairie
Oil and Gas company is merely a pro
ducing company: that it confines its
attention to pumping oil out of the
earth and transporting it through its
pipe lines.
The Standard Oil of Kansas refines
oil and sells it at wholesale.
The Standard Oil company of Indiana
purchases the products of the Stand
ard Oil company of Kansas, and sells
these products in a wholesale and re-
tall way.
The Standard Oil of New Jersey, it
is solemnly asserted, has never done
uni. hfia1n nt Anv lrinri In 1tanftlll
Thnn th. whole scheme of Standard Sept. 11, 1901
fill munanment Is set forth and the bis: I Feb. 21, 1902..
Rockefeller trust !s out in the open, Sept. 16. 1902
flchtlne- for its life. Jan. 21. 1W3..
Each of the amended answers filed Feb. 27. 1903...
asserts that there are no agreements June 20, 1908
between the various members of the Dec. 10, 1903.
Standard Oil family: that each head March 8. 1904...
of the hvdra does its own thinking. May 17. 1904
and that No. 26 Broadway, N. T., does Oct. 18, 1904.
not control or direct any of the affairs. Dec. 7, 1904
But the answers to the interrogatories Feb. 21, 1905
show that the various subsidiary com- May 23, 1905....
panies are eacn contronea Dy ine oig Dec. 12, 1905.
guns of the Standard Oil of New Jer- Feb. 26, 1906
sey. and so it isn't really necessary Nov. 14. 1906
that the orders should come direct Jan. 2, 1907..
from 26 Broadway. I Feb. 21, 1907..
The. amended answers to the petl-1 March 21. -1907
lions oi me state aiso set lorin -the
anti-trust laws of Kansas are In
violation of the bill of rights, the con
stitution of the state and the constitu
tion of the united States.
The amended answers in the case are
signed by Alfred D. Eddy, W. S. Fitz-
Patrick, R. R. Vermillion, W. E. Stan
ley, and Earl W. Evans on behalf of
the Standard OH of Kansas and of In
diana, while for the Prairie Oil Gas
company the answers are signed by
J. B. F. Gates and J. D. McFarland.
April 10, 1907...
May 14. 1907...,.
May 31, 1907
July 30, 1907
Sept. 6, 1907
otal
LOOK OUT FOR POLICE.
One of the most astonishing things Special Officers Sworn In to Take Care
revealed by the Interrogatories is the
fact that the Standard OH company of
Kansas, with 11.000,000 capital, has paid
32,233,300 in dividends, while the Stand
ard Oil of Indiana, which is the big
clearing house for the retail profits,
with only $1,000,000 capital, has in less
than seven years paid over $50,000,000
In dividends.
The answers of the Standard Oil of
Kansas show that the 10,000 shares of
stock in that company are owned as
follows: H. M. Flagler, 6,000 shares;
James A. Moffett. 8993. shares; A. M.
Dunks, A. Swoboda, Thos. Black. W.
P. Cowan, W. M. Burton, G. W. Stahl,
J. C. McDonald, one share each. H. M.
Flager is vice president and director packed with
or tne stanaara on or isew jersey. I morning.
ana James A. Aioirett is a director or
the same. Cowan and Burton are
stockholders of the same company.
The following is a statement of the
amount of dividends which the Stan
dard Oil' company of Kansas has paid:
of Halloween Offenders.
For the purpose of circumventing Hal
loween depredators, a large number of
special policemen have been sworn in
for. tonight. They will lurk in the dark
places all over the city, unmarked by
brass buttons or shining star, and grab
crossing lifters, gate destroyers and
other disturbers, without warning. Ow
ing to the class of devilment attending
the date on former years, the police
court will not be over lenient with of
fenders caught by the officers tonight.
and the police expect to have the Jail
young
May 19, 1894 100
June 6, 1895 100
January 19. 1897 100
June 1, 1898 6.000
1, 1899 8.000
1, 1900 20.000
1. 1901 10.000
2. 1902 10,000
25. 1906 750.000
November 16, 1906 600.000
February 5. 1907 200.000
June 28, 1907 400.000
October 3, 1907 250.000
Croker's Horse Beats the King's.
Newmarket, Eng.. Oct. 81. Rich
ard Croker's Rhoder, ridden by W.
Bullock, won the Dunhurst plate to
day, beating King Edward's Perrier,
which was second.
DEATHS AND FUNERALS.
June
June
June
June
June
Total $2,233,300
The company denies that it has a
private telegraph wire leading from
16 Broadway, New Tork. to the man
aging office of the Standard Oil com
pany of Kansas, or that the policy of
the Kansas company is dictated from</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87056245/1911-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Supreme+Court+Dissolves+Trust+Sherman+Anti&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.178,0.083,1.004,1.088,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>5UPR,F,V3E COURT DISSOLVES THE STANDARD OIL TRUST
iXountv ifec order iJanlO
WEEK
REPUEL
CAN
i
J
V
Epoch Making Decision Marks the High
way of Industrial Progress InAmer
ica Prevents Combinations for the
Restraint of Trade.
(From Chicago Tribune)
petition11 to such an extent as tobe
a combination of conspiracy in re
straint of trade in violation of the
first section of the Sherman act and
also to be an attempt at a monopo
lization which became a perennial
violation of the second section.
"We see no cause to doubt the
correctness of these con elusions,"
said the chief justice, "considering
HAVE FRIENDSHIP DAY
English Roses Sent Prom the Grave
of Ann Hathaway by Mrs.
Young Alice Freeman
Palmer.
Washington, D. C, May. 15 The
Standard Oil company of New Jersey
and its nineteen subsidiary corpora
tions were declared today by the
Supreme Court of the United States
to be a conspiracy and combination
in restraint of trade.
It also was held to be monopoliz
ing interstate commerce in violation the bfat from every aspect'
nf tbfl Sherman anti-trust law. The
dissiolution of the combination was Ruthless Crushing of Rivals,
ordered to take place within six Ranging over a career of thirty
month?. (two years, the Standard Oil corn
Thus eilded the tremendous 6trug- paay is found by the court to have
gle on the part of the government had one continuous purpose the
to put down by authority of law a crushing out of rival. In subject
combination which it claimed was a ing to scrutiny the acts and doings
menace to the industrial and econ- of Standard Oil in the long distant
omi3 advancement of the entire past for the purpose of getting
ountrv. .assistance in discovering intent and
ipurpose, Justice White said:
limits to "unaue nestraini. ttWe tMnk no disinterested mind
At the same time the court inter- can survey the period in Question
.pretod the Sherman atti-trust law without being irresistibly driven to
so as to limit its application to the conclusion that the very genius
acts of "undue' restraint of trade for commercial development and
It was on this point that the only organization which it would seem
discordant nete was heard in theVas manifested from the berinn:ncr
ouri. soon b'ejrot an intent and purpose to
Justice Harlan dissented, claim- exclude others, which was frequently
in? that cases already decided by manifested bv .acts and dealinsrs
the court had determined onee for wholly inconsistent with the theory ters from those members who have
all that the word undue or that they were made with the removed from Plymouth,
"unreasonable," or similar words, sn?:e conception of advancing the! Mrs. Ada Corbin responded from
were not m me siaiut?. ne ue- development of business power bv
clared that the reasoning of the nsuai methods, but which, on the
court in arriving at its finding was contrary, necessarily involved the
in effect legislation which belonged intent to drive others from the field
in every instance to congress and anj to exclnde them from their
not to the courts. j right to trade and thus? accomplish
The opinion of the courtwas an-themasiery-whichwa5 the-- end- in
H rouneecr rhy Chief" Justic e White. yjew
Tn printed form it contained more
than 20,000 words. For nearly an Monopoly Intent Continuous,
hour the chief justice discussed the "And, considering the period fiom
t ease from the bench. goin: over most the date of the trust agreements of
-of the points in the printed opinion 1879 and 1882 up to the time of the
but not once referring to it in order expansion of the New Jersey cor
poration, the pradual extension of
the power over the commerce in oil
which ensued, the decision of the
v far the gT3ater portion of the
opinion of the chief justice was de
voted to the justification of th6
court in requiring that the "rule
of reason ".be applied to restmins
of trade bef ore they were held to be
violations of the Sherman antitrust
law.
The court found this justification
-in the common law of the fore
fathers and in the general law of
ihe country at the time the Sher
man antitrust law was passed.
In short, the court held that the
technical words of tt .statute were
to be riven the meaning which those
-words had in the common law and in
ihe ,vw of the country at the time
nf the enactment.
This meaning of the words accord
ins totheeourt called for the ex-
-erises of. reason in determining
what restraints on trade were pro-
fiiUtcd.
XZzzi Ccnpicta cf Trxits.
In the course of tee opinion,
Chief .Jnstiee White recalled that
-tha ltrwcr court the United States
Circuit Court of Eastern Ifirccrl
had foend that the effect of the
tcquHtbn by the Standard OilCom-
Ti-nv of New Jersey ox tne snares oi
other corporations in exchange for
Irs eertiScates, irate to the corpora-
iicn an enlarged and mere perfect,
sway and control over tha trade and
commcrca in petrol run and its pro
ducts,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1908-01-31/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=President+Roosevelt+Law+Defying+Rich+Attacked+Standard+Oil+Fraud&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.137,-0.064,1.274,1.274,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The President in a Special Message
Compares Crimes of Standard Oil
to Murder Fraud and Ballot
I Stuffing
ROOSEVELTS PLATFORM AS HE 1
STATES IT IN SECOND MESSAGE
We ixek to control lawdefying wealth in the first place to prevent its
doing dire evil to tho Republic and In tho next place to avoid tho vindictive
and dreadful radicalism which If lert uncontrolled It Is certain In tho end
to arouse
Sweeping attacks upon all property upon all men of means without re
gard to whether they do well or 111 would sound the death knell of the Re
public and such atucks became Inevitable If decent citizens permit those rich
men whose lives are corrupt and evil to domineer In swollen pride unchecked
and unhindered over the destinies of this country
We act in no vindictive spirit and we are no respecter of persons If a
labor union does wrong we oppose It as firmly as we oppose a corporation
which doc wrong and twe stand equally stoutly for the rights of the man of
wealth and for tho rlchts of the waco worker
We sock to protect the property of every man who nets honestly of every
corporation that represents wealth honestly accumulated and honestly used
We seek to stop wrongdoing and we desire to punish the wrongdoers only as
far as Is necessary to achieve this end
I Special to The Evening World
I WASHINGTON Jan 31President Roosevelt sent a special mes
sage to Congress today which is quite the hottest state document he
V ever penned
It is in effect a defense of his administration with respect to his cam
picn against corporations And there are some who will find in it an
ack upon the Supreme Court of the United States
I Never tcfore has he been so bitter in attacking malefactors of great
b wealth He jumps on the Standard Oil Company in vigorous fashion
takes a fall out of tricky corporation lawyers and compares men who bribe
J Matures and illegally manipulate corporations for their own profit to
the leeche who fatten upon blood money from dens of vice gambling
houses and saloons
It is plain to be seen That the Presidents message is an answer to
the broadside campaign of abuse that has been heaped upon him by ad
vertisement and pamphlet since he instigated corporation prosecutions
He stands pat on his record promises further action and eternally lam
tastes his enemies He practically accuses the Standard Oil Company
and certain railroad interests with instigating these attacks
The President disclaims any responsibility for
the panic of last fall and the resulting hard times
lIe blames it upon the speculative folly and flagrant
dishonesty of a few men of great wealth who seek to
shield themselves from the effects of their own
wrongdoing by ascribing its results to the actions of
those who have sought to put a stop to the wrong
doing
In his message the President repeats much that he has said in for
mer messages and in his public speeches but on no previous occasion
has he cut loose with such freedom and vigor It is a message that is
sure to arouse a storm of comment and every citizen who takes the
slightest interest in business or politics should read it carefully I
president Fires a Broadside I
at Men Who Oppose His Policies
i The excuse for the message IE betrayed In ho opening paragraph The
president says
The recent decision of tho Supreme Court In regard to the employers
liability act the experience ot the Interstate Commerce Commission nnd
of the Department of Justice In enforcing the Interstate commerce nud anti
trust lava and the gravely significant attitude toward the Jaw and its ad
ministration recently adopted by certain hells of great corporations render
It desirable that there should Ixi additional legislation as regards certain
II of the relations between labor and capital and between the great corpora
lions aud tho uubllc
Hho Supreme Court has decided the employers liability law to be un
constitutional because its terms apply to employees engaged wholly III intra
elats commerce as well ai to employees engaged In interstate commerco
By a substantial majority the Court holds that the Congress has power to
deal with the question in BO far us Interstate commerce is concerned
As regards the employers liability law I advocate Its imnicdlitto re
cnactmont limiting its scojio so that It shall apply only to the elites of
cases as to which the Court says it can constitutionally apply Jut slrclIlth
m</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-battleships/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
